<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html</id>
    <title>Ajour / Spitlo.com</title>
    <updated>2022-08-23T00:44:28.696Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 22 Aug 2022 Gmail will call the cops on you based on the content of your emails]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4040</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/22/allopathic-risk/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-22T14:47:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links falsely told the police that a father was a molesting his son: Filternets fail. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Google falsely told the police that a father was a molesting his son (permalink) Correction: An earlier draft of this story misstated a technical detail; Mark didn’t email his photo to his doctor; rather, he took the photo with his phone and the image was automatically synched to his Google Photos account, triggering a scan. Mark’s toddler had a painful, swollen penis. His wife contacted their doctor, whose nurse asked Mark to send him a picture of the toddler’s penis, because the pandemic was raging and the doctor wasn…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physics Safety Tip]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2662/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2662/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/physics_safety_tip.png" title="In general, avoid exposure to any temperatures, pressures, particle energies, or states of matter that physicists think are neat." alt="In general, avoid exposure to any temperatures, pressures, particle energies, or states of matter that physicists think are neat." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 21 Aug 2022 The Shitty Technology Adoption Curve Reaches Apogee]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4036</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/21/great-taylors-ghost/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-21T18:14:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Workplace surveillance is coming for you: Empricism-washing as a form of wage-theft. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Workplace surveillance is coming for you (permalink) If you want to do something terrible with technology, you can't just roll it out on people with money and social capital. They'll complain and your idea will tank. Successful shitty tech rollouts start with people you can abuse with impunity (prisoners, kids, migrants, etc) and then work their way up the privilege gradient. I call it the Shitty Technology Adoption Curve. The point of the Shitty Technology Adoption Curve is to normalize technological oppression, one gro…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 19 Aug 2022 Business Roundtable vs Humanity]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4030</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/19/handmaidens-to-extinction/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-19T18:26:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Business Roundtable's climate plan was killed by its arch-rival, the Business Roundtable: If only Apple, Pepsi, Walmart and Google knew someone at the lobbying shop they own. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Business Roundtable's climate plan was killed by its arch-rival, the Business Roundtable (permalink) Three years ago to the date, the Business Roundtable unveiled its "Statement on the Purpose of a Corporation" – a commitment by its 200 member-CEOs and companies to protect the environment. Then they spent three years and millions of dollars lobbying against that goal. https://www.businessroundtable.org/business-r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Age Milestone Privileges]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2661/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2661/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/age_milestone_privileges.png" title="If you reach 122, you get complete unrevertible editorial control over Jeanne Calment's Wikipedia article." alt="If you reach 122, you get complete unrevertible editorial control over Jeanne Calment's Wikipedia article." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You haven’t been hacked, these aren’t devices spying on you and these errors aren’t your fault]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7300</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/08/18/you-havent-been-hacked-these-arent-devices-spying-on-you-and-these-errors-arent-your-fault/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-18T08:46:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is possible to accidentally open the developer tools in browsers. Either by pressing F12, selecting the “Inspect” option of the context menu or hitting one of the many keyboard shortcuts that open different tools. These tools can look intimidating and as if someone is hacking your computer. Especially when you see the Console tool […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 Aug 2022: Chokepoint Capitalism Kickstarter is live]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4027</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/17/chokepoint-capitalism/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-17T15:36:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Kickstarting the "Chokepoint Capitalism" audiobook: We wrote a book that Amazon won't sell. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Kickstarting the "Chokepoint Capitalism" audiobook (permalink) My next book is Chokepoint Capitalism, co-written with the brilliant copyright expert Rebecca Giblin: it's an action-oriented investigation into how tech and entertainment monopolies have destroyed creators' livelihoods, with detailed, shovel-ready plans to unrig creative labor markets and get artists paid. http://www.beacon.org/Chokepoint-Capitalism-P1856.aspx Ironically, the very phenomenon this book describes – "chokepoint capitalism" – is en…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gen Z]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2660/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2660/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/gen_z.png" title="Curdled milk, of a peculiar kind, made after a Bulgarian recipe and called &quot;yaghurt,&quot; is now a Parisian fad and is believed to be a remedy against growing old. A correspondent who has tried it, says he would prefer to die young. (1905, The Elk Falls Journal)" alt="Curdled milk, of a peculiar kind, made after a Bulgarian recipe and called &quot;yaghurt,&quot; is now a Parisian fad and is believed to be a remedy against growing old. A correspondent who has tried it, says he would prefer to die young. (1905, The Elk Falls Journal)" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-August Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42774</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/08/16/mid-august-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-16T21:12:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events The next virtual meetup of the Seattle/Tacoma IF group will be on Sunday, August 21, from 2 – 4 PM PDT via Discord. (This month they’re playing Pytho’s Mask.) In early September, inkJam will be running to encourage new games written in Ink. The SF Bay IF Meetup will convene again on September 3. This … Continue reading "Mid-August Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4020</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/16/do-stuff-talk-about-it/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-16T15:46:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How Democrats could win more elections: Do stuff. Make it timely. Tell people about it. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How Democrats could win more elections (permalink) My fellow Americans…if I may call you that? I've only been a US citizen for five weeks, but I think I may have identified a key weakness in the Democrats' electioneering strategy, and I wanted to bring it to your attention because it would be great if the forced birth/martial law/mass incarceration party didn't win the next election. If Democrats want to win more elections, they should try: Enacting popular policies, preferably ones that materially i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why React Re-Renders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/why-react-re-renders/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/why-react-re-renders/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-16T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In React, we don't update the DOM directly, we tell React what we want the DOM to look like, and React tackles the rest. But how exactly does it do this? In this tutorial, we'll unpack exactly when and why React re-renders, and how we can use this information to optimize the performance of our React apps.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Steve Teixeira, Mozilla’s new Chief Product Officer]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69795</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/steve-teixeira-mozilla-new-chief-product-officer/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am pleased to share that Steve Teixeira has joined Mozilla as our Chief Product Officer. During our search for a Chief Product Officer, Steve stood out to us because of his extensive experience at tech and internet companies where he played instrumental roles in shaping products from research, design, security, development, and getting them […]
The post Announcing Steve Teixeira, Mozilla’s new Chief Product Officer appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mitchell Baker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 15 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4003</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/15/deere-in-headlights/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T15:37:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links This weekend, I watched a hacker jailbreak a John Deere tractor live on stage: Total pwnage, with a a side of copyfraud. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading This weekend, I watched a hacker jailbreak a John Deere tractor live on stage (permalink) Last Saturday, I sat in a crowded ballroom at Caesar's Forum in Las Vegas and watched Sickcodes jailbreak a John Deere tractor's control unit live, before an audience of cheering Defcon 30 attendees (and, possibly, a few undercover Deere execs, who often attend Sickcodes's talks). The presentation was significant because Deere – along with Apple – are the vanguard of the war on r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unreliable Connection]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2659/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2659/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/unreliable_connection.png" title="NEGATIVE REVIEWS MENTION: Unreliable internet. POSITIVE REVIEWS MENTION: Unreliable internet." alt="NEGATIVE REVIEWS MENTION: Unreliable internet. POSITIVE REVIEWS MENTION: Unreliable internet." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On ratings and meters]]></title>
        <id>https://lea.verou.me/?p=3502</id>
        <link href="https://lea.verou.me/2022/08/on-ratings-and-meters/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-12T22:29:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I always thought that the semantically appropriate way to represent a rating (e.g. a star rating) is a <meter> element. They essentially convey the same type of information, the star rating is just a different presentation. However, trying to style a <meter> element to look like a star rating is …tricky at best. Not to […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lea Verou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 12 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3994</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/12/regulatory-uncapture/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-12T15:37:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The FTC takes aim at commercial surveillance: Oh, the sheer poetry of "Commercial Surveillance and Data Security Rulemaking." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The FTC takes aim at commercial surveillance (permalink) The biggest fallacy in the online privacy is that there is a difference between "state surveillance" and "commercial surveillance." Bizarrely, it's a fallacy that is widely held by both government snoops and Big Tech snoops. Many's the time I've spoken to a DC audience about privacy, only to have an audience member say, "I'm OK with Uncle Sam spying on me – after all, I've already given up every sensitive scrap of info…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Cup Holes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2658/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2658/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/coffee_cup_holes.png" title="Theoretical physicist: At the Planck length, uncountably many." alt="Theoretical physicist: At the Planck length, uncountably many." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 11 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3986</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/11/rope-a-dope/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-11T13:46:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A dark money group is lying about Medicare cuts: Who the fuck are the "American Prosperity Alliance?" Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A dark money group is lying about Medicare cuts (permalink) The "American Prosperity Alliance" does not exist, except as an anonymously controlled bank account that has paid for the production and dissemination of a slick ad that spreads the falsehood that the Democrats have cut $300b from Medicare: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-xCep6NvbhE Let me repeat: this is a lie. What "American Prosperity Alliance" is talking about here is a provision in the bill that allows Medicare to negotiate drug pric…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I joined Mozilla’s Board of Directors]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69771</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/kristin-skogen-lund-mozilla-board-announcement/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-10T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I first started working with digitalization and the internet when I became CEO of Scandinavia Online in 1998. It was the leading online service in the Nordics and we were pioneers and idealists. I learnt a lot from that experience: the endless opportunities, the tricky business models and the extreme ups and downs in hypes […]
The post Why I joined Mozilla’s Board of Directors appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 10 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3978</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/10/be-reasonable/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-10T13:39:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A modest proposal to fix contracts: Rescuing contracts from sprawling garbage legalese novellas masquerading as "agreements." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A modest proposal to fix contracts (permalink) Every time I click through one of those garbage legalese novellas you're expected to say "I Agree" to before doing something totally normal and inconsequential, I'm reminded of the legendary Lenny Bruce bit "Eat, Sleep and Crap." http://cellar.org/showthread.php?t=24181 In this bit, all civilization begins with agreements: "Let's see. I tell you what we'll do. We'll have a vote. We'll sleep in Area A. Is that cool?" …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complex Vowels]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2657/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2657/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/complex_vowels.png" title="Pronouncing [ṡṡċċḣḣẇẇȧȧ] is easy; you just say it like the 'x' in 'fire'." alt="Pronouncing [ṡṡċċḣḣẇẇȧȧ] is easy; you just say it like the 'x' in 'fire'." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using browser developer tools as an image browser]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7295</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/08/09/using-browser-developer-tools-as-an-image-browser/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-09T18:16:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes you come across web sites that have a lot of images scattered all over the page and you don’t care much about the content, but only want the images. You can use the browser developer tools as a media browser. Load the page you want to get the images from (here is a demo […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3969</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/08/locus-of-individuation/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-08T14:21:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "So You’ve Decided to Unfollow Me": On the joys of writing to find your people, rather than pleasing a hypothetical audience. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "So You’ve Decided to Unfollow Me" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read "So You’ve Decided to Unfollow Me," my Medium describing the joys of writing to attract the audience of people who want to read what you want to write. https://doctorow.medium.com/so-youve-decided-to-unfollow-me-7452c96b4772 I've been blogging for more than 20 years, but I've been writing for publication for even longer than that, so I can remember the emergence of blog…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cheat codes for the web – Browser developer tools for non-developers]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7292</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/08/08/cheat-codes-for-the-web-browser-developer-tools-for-non-developers/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-08T08:22:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every browser these days comes with built-in developer tools that help people create, test and fix products for the web. You can right-click any website and select `Inspect` to get to them, press `F12` or `CMD + Shift + I on Mac` or `Ctrl + Shift + I` on Windows/Linux. These tools are for developers, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Field Prefixes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2656/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2656/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/scientific_field_prefixes.png" title="Massage: Theoretical (10), Quantum (6), High-energy (2), Computational (1), Marine (1), Astro- (None)" alt="Massage: Theoretical (10), Quantum (6), High-energy (2), Computational (1), Marine (1), Astro- (None)" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3955</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/07/inky-wretches/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-07T16:12:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Epson boobytrapped its printers: "For your protection." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Epson boobytrapped its printers (permalink) "Innovation" has become a curseword, thanks to…innovation. Some of the world's most imaginative, best-funded sociopaths have spent decades innovating ways to fuck you over. While the whole tech sector likes to get in on this game, no one "innovates" like inkjet printer companies. Printer companies are true fuckery pioneers: the tactical innovations they've developed in the war on their customers would make Otto von Bismarck blush. Selling printers with half-empty ink-cartridges: https://www.the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3949</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/05/a-lousy-taxi/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-05T14:09:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Uber's still not profitable: An effective wealth transfer of $2.8 billion from labor to capital in just three months. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Uber's still not profitable (permalink) Uber just released its Q2 numbers for 2022 and trumpeted that it had finally achieved cash-flow positivity – and it only took 13 years and $32 billion in losses! So has Uber finally turned a corner? Will the company finally attain profitability and repay those billions? Nope. The best analyst of Uber's financial disclosures – as always – is Hubert Horan, a transport analyst who has made a second career out of debullshitifying Uber's bala…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asking Scientists Questions]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2655/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2655/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/asking_scientists_questions.png" title="'Does the substance feel weird to the touch?' is equally likely to get the answers 'Don't be ridiculous, you would never put your hand near a sample. We have safety protocols.' and 'Yeah, and it tastes AWFUL.'" alt="'Does the substance feel weird to the touch?' is equally likely to get the answers 'Don't be ridiculous, you would never put your hand near a sample. We have safety protocols.' and 'Yeah, and it tastes AWFUL.'" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A back-to-school checklist for online safety]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69735</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/privacy-security/privacy-security-tips/back-to-school-checklist-for-online-safety/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-04T16:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first day of school is right around the corner. Whether that brings some relief, gives you jitters or both, we’re here to support families with one major thing: internet safety.   For parents, thinking about the dangers of the web can be scary. But it doesn’t have to be. While the internet isn’t perfect, it’s […]
The post A back-to-school checklist for online safety appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 04 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3943</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/04/its-a-trap/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-04T15:10:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A TRAP for workers: Oops, we re-invented indenture. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A TRAP for workers (permalink) One of the weirdest parts of conspiratorialism is the hunt for anagrams as secret expressions of guilt. Ken Cheng's recent BBC Comedy of the Week show, he has a great bit on this, pointing out how weird it is that someone figured out that "delta" and "omicron" are an anagram for "media control." https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p0ckq7pb As Cheng says, "do they think the coronavirus was invented by Tom Marvolo Riddle?" And yet, sometimes, villains really do use word-games to tip their hands. How else to ex…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemtrails]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2654/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2654/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/chemtrails.png" title="Ants have reverse chemtrails--regular citizens spraying chemicals everywhere they go to control the government." alt="Ants have reverse chemtrails--regular citizens spraying chemicals everywhere they go to control the government." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 02 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3927</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/02/oligarchs-r-us/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-02T15:26:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The high cost of "self-funded" Democrats: Rich dilletantes will not save us. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The high cost of "self-funded" Democrats (permalink) It costs a lot to win a US election – even if it's just a race for (formerly) low-stakes offices that have emerged as culture-war battlegrounds (like school and election boards). In the 12 years since Citizens United, the dark money firehose has turned many races into plute-on-plute economic warfare, where cash from the 1% matters far more than votes from the 99%. Republicans have a structural advantage when it comes to moneyball elections, because they are t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Aug 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3922</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/08/01/dumb-pipes/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-01T15:19:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "View A SKU": A plan to turn Amazon into a dumb pipe. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "View A SKU" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my recent Medium column, "View a SKU: Let’s Make Amazon Into a Dumb Pipe," about how interop can help us demonopolize Amazon and tame its market power: https://doctorow.medium.com/view-a-sku-32721d623aee To explain this proposal, I need to start with an axiom: there are lots of problems with Amazon (lots!) but the fact that Amazon is really convenient is not one of those problems. Your use of Amazon isn't a mark of your "laziness" anymore than your consump…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Omnitaur]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2653/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2653/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/omnitaur.png" title="&quot;My parents were both omnitaurs, which is how I got interested in recombination,&quot; said the normal human." alt="&quot;My parents were both omnitaurs, which is how I got interested in recombination,&quot; said the normal human." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of July Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42741</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/07/31/end-of-july-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-31T17:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events August 6 is the next meetup of the San Francisco Bay IF Meetup, and will be conducted online. The next virtual meetup of the Seattle/Tacoma IF group will be on Sunday, August 21, from 2 – 4 PM PDT via Discord. (This month they’re playing Pytho’s Mask.) In early September, inkJam will be running to … Continue reading "End of July Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 29 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3916</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/29/managed-retreat/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-29T18:59:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Spending $200b to relocated doomed communities will save $1T: The best time to start a 100-year project was a century ago, the second best time is now. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Spending $200b to relocated doomed communities will save $1T (permalink) One million US homes are built on floodplains. It would cost $200B to relocate the people who live in them. If we do that, we will save $1T. Those homes are doomed. When (not if) people leave them (either before or after floods come), they merely be arriving at a conclusion that is inevitable today. https://prospect.org/environment/how-to-de-develop-in-an-age-of-fire-and-flood/…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riot Games’ head of player community, known as ‘Aureylian’ to game streaming fans, on her favorite corners of the internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69485</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/interviews/riot-games-aureylian-game-streaming-interview/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-29T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Riot Games’ head of player community, known as ‘Aureylian’ to game streaming fans, on her favorite corners of the internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proxy Variable]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2652/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2652/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/proxy_variable.png" title="Our work has produced great answers. Now someone just needs to figure out which questions they go with." alt="Our work has produced great answers. Now someone just needs to figure out which questions they go with." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3912</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/28/descartes-was-an-optimist/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-28T17:40:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Your computer is tormented by a wicked god: Bootkits are why we can't have nice things. Peter Thiel's evil, but he's not an "evil genius": How to criticize self-mythologizing villains. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Your computer is tormented by a wicked god (permalink) Computer security is really, really important. It was important decades ago, when computers were merely how we ran our financial system, aviation, and the power grid. Today, as more and more of us have our bodies inside of computers (cars, houses, etc) and computers in our body (implants), computer security is urgent. Decades ago, security practitioners beg…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla celebrates groundbreaking creators in new docuseries “Firefox Presents”]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68743</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/new-mozilla-docuseries-firefox-presents-launch/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-28T17:31:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Different is dope. Firefox has always stood by this. It’s also the mantra of Abby Wren, the woman featured in the pilot episode of our new docuseries, “Firefox Presents.” Launching Friday, April 15, “Firefox Presents” is a documentary series featuring colorful and inspiring creators who each have a unique journey of finding themselves or their […]
The post Mozilla celebrates groundbreaking creators in new docuseries “Firefox Presents” appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Help design the State of CSS Survey 2022!]]></title>
        <id>https://lea.verou.me/?p=3493</id>
        <link href="https://lea.verou.me/2022/07/help-design-the-state-of-css-survey-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-28T10:42:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since 2019, the annual State of CSS survey has collected feedback from web developers from across the world to try and take the pulse of the CSS ecosystem, and it’s become a valuable resource not only for CSS developers, but also for browser vendors. This summer, one of my side projects is helping out with survey […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lea Verou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A toy remote login server]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/07/28/toy-remote-login-server/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/07/28/toy-remote-login-server/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-28T08:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! The other day we talked about what happened when you press a key in your terminal.
As a followup, I thought it might be fun to implement a program that’s like a
tiny ssh server, but without the security. You can find it on github here, and I’ll explain how it works in this blog post.
the goal: “ssh” to a remote computer
Our goal is to be able to login to a remote computer and run commands, like you
do with SSH or telnet.
The biggest difference between this program and SSH is that there’s literally
no security (not even a password) – anyone who can make a TCP connection to
the server can get a shell and run commands.
Obviously this is not a useful program in real life, but our goal is to learn a
little more about how terminals works, not to write a useful program.
(I will run a versi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parents want to keep their kids safe online. But are parental controls the answer?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69498</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/deep-dives/parental-controls-internet-safety-for-kids/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-27T17:37:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For our new series Parental Control, we’re digging into the challenges technology poses for parents and exploring all the ways that can empower them. So we looked into digital platforms and found ourselves, as many parents do, in the parental control settings.  These settings, along with services that promise to shield young people away from […]
The post Parents want to keep their kids safe online. But are parental controls the answer? appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3908</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/27/boricua/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-27T15:28:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links "War Against All Puerto Ricans": Required reading for the eve of a new independence referendum. Dashcam repo: Cruising the streets with a license plate camera to win debt-collector bounties. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading "War Against All Puerto Ricans" (permalink) Puerto Rico is back in the news. Sorta. That Other America breaches the US media consciousness every couple of years. The Bad President put it in the news by his horrific, racist failure to respond to Hurricane Maria: https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/it-totally-belittled-the-moment-many-look-back-in-anger-at-trumps-tossing-of-paper-towels-in-puerto-rico/2018/09/13/8a3647d2…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Air Gap]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2651/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2651/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/air_gap.png" title="You can still do powerline networking, but the bitrate does drop a little depending on the lightbulb warmup and cooldown delay." alt="You can still do powerline networking, but the bitrate does drop a little depending on the lightbulb warmup and cooldown delay." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 26 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3900</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/26/aislands/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-26T13:07:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links "A Half-Built Garden": Ruthanna Emrys's stunning First Contact novel. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading "A Half-Built Garden" (permalink) A Half-Built Garden (published today) is Ruthanna Emrys's new novel, a spectacular first-contact novel about complicated utopias and networked conflict – it's a wild ride, and a perfect example of one of the smartest structural analyses of science fiction I ever heard: https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250210982/ahalfbuiltgarden I got this analysis from my editor Patrick Nielsen Hayden, nearly 20 years ago, when he was giving me his editorial notes on my debut novel Down and Out in the Mag…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 25 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3893</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/25/can-you-hear-me-now/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-25T14:11:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Why none of my books are available on Audible: And why Amazon owes me $3,218.55. Sarah Gailey's "Just Like Home": A haunted house novel that made the hairs on the back of my neck stand up. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Why none of my books are available on Audible (permalink) I love audiobooks. When I was a high-school-aged page at a public library in the 1980s, I would pass endless hours shelving and repairing books while listening to "books on tape" from the library's collection. By the time iTunes came along, I'd amassed a huge collection of cassette and CD audiobooks and I painstakingly ripped them to my collection. Then ca…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deepfakes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2650/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2650/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/deepfakes.png" title="If so great a deductive mind as Arthur Conan Doyle can be fooled by the Cottingley Deepfakes, what chance do we mortals have? Soon our very reality will be dictated by the whims of Frances (9) and Elsie (16)." alt="If so great a deductive mind as Arthur Conan Doyle can be fooled by the Cottingley Deepfakes, what chance do we mortals have? Soon our very reality will be dictated by the whims of Frances (9) and Elsie (16)." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Presents: A nerdcore rap artist defying expectations]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69408</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/firefox-presents-nerdcore-rap-lex-the-lexicon-artist/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-22T15:53:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As far as music subgenres go, nerdcore hip-hop wouldn’t exist in its current form without the internet. Those who create it — self-proclaimed nerds who rap about video games, science fiction or just everyday life as a misfit — record music at home, collaborate via web file transfers and find cheerleaders out of strangers online.  […]
The post Firefox Presents: A nerdcore rap artist defying expectations appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physics Cost-Saving Tips]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2649/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2649/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/physics_cost_saving_tips.png" title="I got banned from the county fair for handing out Helium-2 balloons. Apparently the instant massive plasma explosions violated some local ordinance or something." alt="I got banned from the county fair for handing out Helium-2 balloons. Apparently the instant massive plasma explosions violated some local ordinance or something." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What happens when you press a key in your terminal?]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/07/20/pseudoterminals/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/07/20/pseudoterminals/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-20T20:57:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been confused about what’s going on with terminals for a long time.
But this past week I was using xterm.js to display an
interactive terminal in a browser and I finally thought to ask a pretty basic
question: when you press a key on your keyboard in a terminal (like Delete, or Escape, or a), which
bytes get sent?
As usual we’ll answer that question by doing some experiments and seeing what happens :)
remote terminals are very old technology
First, I want to say that displaying a terminal in the browser with xterm.js
might seem like a New Thing, but it’s really not. In the 70s, computers were
expensive. So many employees at an institution would share a single computer,
and each person could have their own “terminal” to that computer.
For example, here’s a photo of a VT100 terminal fro…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking Device Emulation in browsers]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7287</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/07/20/rethinking-device-emulation-in-browsers/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-20T15:48:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Device Emulation in developer tools is great, but it doesn’t deliver to all users of it and could be much better. Please help us improve it. When developer tools of browsers came out with Device Emulation and reponsive design tooling , everything changed. As a developer, you didn’t need to resize the browser window any […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemicals]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2648/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2648/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/chemicals.png" title="It's hard to believe, but lots of kids these days ONLY know how to buy prepackaged molecules." alt="It's hard to believe, but lots of kids these days ONLY know how to buy prepackaged molecules." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capri Suns]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2647/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2647/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/capri_suns.png" title="[As security is dragging me away] &quot;Come on, at least I didn't make the mistake in the other direction!&quot;" alt="[As security is dragging me away] &quot;Come on, at least I didn't make the mistake in the other direction!&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-July Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42736</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/07/15/mid-july-link-assortment-7/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T17:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events ParserComp games are still available to play and vote on through July 31, and players are reviewing these games over on the intfiction forum. Hops Ahead: The Art of Alternate Histories, Presents, and Futures is an exhibition of interactive narrative works, curated by Clara Fernández-Vara and Nick Montfort, running December 4-7 at UC Santa … Continue reading "Mid-July Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minkowski Space]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2646/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2646/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/minkowski_space.png" title="My liege, we were able to follow the ship into Minkowski space, but now they've jumped to Hilbert space and they could honestly be anywhere." alt="My liege, we were able to follow the ship into Minkowski space, but now they've jumped to Hilbert space and they could honestly be anywhere." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kesimpta [blog]]]></title>
        <id>kesimpta</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/07/15/kesimpta"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As much as this sounds like a new webapp (and indeed over a decade ago I owned the domain Kajinka - can't remember what it was though), no, this is the start of my multiple sclerosis (MS) drug treatment which, I guess lasts as long as I do.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The browser console has a count method]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7285</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/07/14/the-browser-console-has-a-count-method/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-14T21:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When debugging or analysing JavaScript, you often see people trying to find out how often a certain function is called. The common way to do that is to use a global counter variable to increment and log in the function. var i = 0; function test(){ // other functionality i++; console.log(i); // other functionality } […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bridget Todd, the new host of Mozilla’s IRL podcast, on online communities, The X-Files & raising marginalized voices]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69385</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/bridget-todd-irl-podcast-host-interview/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-14T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Bridget Todd, the new host of Mozilla’s IRL podcast, on online communities, The X-Files & raising marginalized voices appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the best way to mark up an exclusive button group?]]></title>
        <id>https://lea.verou.me/?p=3484</id>
        <link href="https://lea.verou.me/2022/07/button-group/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-14T14:47:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago I asked Twitter a seemingly simple question (I meant aria-pressed, not aria-selected but Twitter doesn’t allow edits…): For background, I was implementing a web component for an app I’m working on at work and I was getting into some pretty weird rabbit holes with my approach of generating radios and labels. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lea Verou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Rety: live coding, without the stress]]></title>
        <id>https://lea.verou.me/?p=3478</id>
        <link href="https://lea.verou.me/2022/07/rety/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-13T16:50:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently spoke at CSS Day in Amsterdam. It was only my second f2f talk after the pandemic. It went down really well, both in person, and recently that the video was released: Here is a sample of tweets about it that made me particularly warm and fuzzy inside: There’s a lot more where these […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lea Verou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Camera]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2645/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2645/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/the_best_camera.png" title="The best camera is the one at L2." alt="The best camera is the one at L2." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statements Vs. Expressions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/javascript/statements-vs-expressions/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/javascript/statements-vs-expressions/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-11T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the most foundational things to understand about JavaScript is that programs are made up of statements, and statements have slots for expressions. In this blog post, we'll dig into how these two structures work, and see how building an intuition about this can help us solve practical problems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[fMRI Billboard]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2644/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2644/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/fmri_billboard.png" title="[other side] If the first word of an instruction you're given starts with the same letter as your crush's name, for that step imagine the experimenter is your crush." alt="[other side] If the first word of an instruction you're given starts with the same letter as your crush's name, for that step imagine the experimenter is your crush." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring tiny web services]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/07/09/monitoring-small-web-services/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/07/09/monitoring-small-web-services/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-09T09:25:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I’ve started to run a few more servers recently
(nginx playground,
mess with dns,
dns lookup), so I’ve been
thinking about monitoring.
It wasn’t initially totally obvious to me how to monitor these websites, so I
wanted to quickly write up what how I did it.
I’m not going to talk about how to monitor Big Serious Mission Critical
websites at all, only tiny unimportant websites.
goal: spend approximately 0 time on operations
I want the sites to mostly work, but I also want to spend approximately 0% of
my time on the ongoing operations.
I was initially very wary of running servers at all because at my last job I
was on a 24⁄7 oncall rotation for some critical services, and in my mind “being
responsible for servers” meant “get woken up at 2am to fix the servers” and
“have lots of compli…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The journey to Roe and after – a Pocket Collection unveils the stories behind Slate’s 7th season of Slow Burn]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69390</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/pocket/the-journey-to-roe-and-after-a-pocket-collection-unveils-the-stories-behind-slates-7th-season-of-slow-burn/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T20:19:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the recent overturn of Roe v. Wade, many of us can’t help but wonder: How did we get here? It didn’t happen overnight — no, it was more of a slow burn. Just in time for the seventh season of Slate’s Slow Burn, host and executive editor Susan Matthews explores the path to Roe […]
The post The journey to Roe and after – a Pocket Collection unveils the stories behind Slate’s 7th season of Slow Burn appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Vasquez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3877</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/08/jubilant/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T17:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Finance caused the fall of Rome: A politics of protecting contracts and property is a civilizational suicide pact. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Finance caused the fall of Rome (permalink) It's hard to overstate the impact that David Graeber's 2012 blockbuster Debt: The First Five Thousand Years had on society; it's a truly magisterial history of the way that debt – and debt forgiveness – played in the establishment of advanced civilization and its downfall: https://www.tor.com/2012/04/16/the-best-science-fiction-ideas-in-any-non-fiction-ever-david-graebers-debt-the-first-five-thousand-years/ Graeber – a key Occupy …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cosmologist Gift]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2643/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2643/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/cosmologist_gift.png" title="These neutrinos were freshly produced by a local source just 8 minutes ago" alt="These neutrinos were freshly produced by a local source just 8 minutes ago" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3867</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/07/collectivism/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-07T16:42:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Countervailing power: Finding the hairball's loose ends. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Countervailing power (permalink) It's hard not to feel powerless. The rich are getting richer, the middle class is disappearing, and poor people are evermore exposed to labor abuses, predatory finance, police violence, and food-, fuel- and housing-insecurity. Our cities are increasingly segregated into the haves and have-nots, and the haves hoard the parks, schools and clean air: https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/06/us/economic-segregation-income.html The rich don't just own all the good stuff, they also own the political process. The now…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meta-Alternating Current]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2642/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2642/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/meta_alternating_current.png" title="It's always bothered me that you can't cancel out an inverter by putting a second inverter after it." alt="It's always bothered me that you can't cancel out an inverter by putting a second inverter after it." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing for Games: Theory & Practice (Hannah Nicklin)]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42745</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/07/05/writing-for-games-theory-practice-hannah-nicklin/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing for Games: Theory & Practice is a new book from Hannah Nicklin, focused very specifically on the writing rather than the narrative design aspects of the field. If the difference feels fuzzy to you, you’re not alone: many indie game roles require writers/designers to do a bit of both of those things. There’s a … Continue reading "Writing for Games: Theory & Practice (Hannah Nicklin)"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3856</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/05/grab-the-wheel/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T15:27:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links "The Swerve": My Locus column on hope in the dark. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading "The Swerve" (permalink) My latest Locus Magazine column is "The Swerve," a short essay about the shape that hope takes when happy endings are off the table – it's specifically about the looming environmental collapse, but it also describes my view on the polycrisis of musketfuckery, forced birth, and covid denial: https://locusmag.com/2022/07/cory-doctorow-the-swerve/ In this metaphor, we are in a bus barreling toward a cliff. The people in the front seats – who control the driver – insist that we don't need to turn the bus before we g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TIL: Visual Studio Code does markdown autocompletion for in-page links]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7278</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/07/05/til-visual-studio-code-does-autocompletion-in-markdown-for-auto-generated-targets-of-headlines/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T14:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you write markdown files, headings automatically also get an ID generated so they become in-page targets to link to. This is also used to create a table of contents in various publishing systems. Today I learned that VS Code also offers these generated IDs as an autocomplete when you type links. If you wrap […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mouse Turbines]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2641/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2641/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/mouse_turbines.png" title="It's sad seeing those videos of turbine blade being torn apart in high winds, but it's the only way they can disperse their seeds." alt="It's sad seeing those videos of turbine blade being torn apart in high winds, but it's the only way they can disperse their seeds." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for July]]></title>
        <id>log.html#july2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#july2022"/>
        <updated>2022-07-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of July. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Adelie, added image maps, animation controls, and wrote a guide. Rekka also drew an Adelie penguin mascot.
Cccc, created a graphical calculator.
Orca, added new font to make it easier to discern letters and numbers from afar (if projected onto a screen).
Noodle, re-designed noodle.
Minesweeper, completed the game.
News
Sometimes we find an anchorage that is so nice, so ideal, that we end up staying for weeks. We stayed in Von Donop Bay (hathayim marine park) for well over a month. The southernmost anchorage is near many trails that snake and branch out deep into the woods, and the bay is so large that we kept finding new corners to explore by dinghy. The water in the area is warmer than in Victoria, we can dive, and check Pino's bottom without freezing. This is our first real summer on the boat, when we have no big boat projects to do, nor big transits to plan, and it feels amazing.
We have stretched our food stores to the limit (it has been 2 months since we last stocked up in full). A 5 km trek through the woods takes us to a little General Store, they never have fresh produce (or it gets bought out before we get there) but we go once in a while to replenish our stock of potatoes and onions. We are relying on sprouts a lot (see growing food).
This month, we made a Keynote talk for Nime 2022, and Devine started work on a little OS project called Potato, see some footage(Mastodon). There is no documentation yet, but soon.
Pino book club
We're reading The Stories of Ray Bradbury by Ray Bradbury.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for June]]></title>
        <id>log.html#june2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#june2022"/>
        <updated>2022-07-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of June. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Uxn, improved the Uxntal reference sheet and improved the Uxntal cheatsheet.
Dexe, added menu bar.
Nasu, added menu bar.
Noodle}, added menu bar.
100r.co, updated boom tent, and added lpg refit (backdated update).
News
Pino is currently in Desolation Sound, enjoying the quiet. We've written a few posts about some of the anchorages we've visited, like {melanie cove}, {grace harbour} and {hathayim marine park}. We're updating our track as we go.
Devine has been adding a lot of notes to the permacomputing wiki this month. We also started a little arcade game named Inle, something that we could play together on the boat in the style of Gunbound/Tank Wars... but with rabbits (we finished reading Watership Down last month, so we blame that, haha). We don't have a project page yet for it, but we shared some images on the post for grace harbour, where we started working on the game.
Rekka produced a video about image optimization for the Photographer's Gallery (as part of their Green Hacks video series) last month.
Pino book club
We're reading The Man who Mistook his Wife for a Hat by Oliver Sacks.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3837</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/01/whip-it-good/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T16:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links After inflation, the whip-crack: Broken telephone, but for back-orders. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading After inflation, the whip-crack (permalink) There's a school of economics that likens the economy to a computer, one that we all power. Every time we buy something – or walk away from an offer – we feed data to the computer, which transmits this price- and demand-information from consumers to producers to financiers, so that demand can be met with supply. The proponents of this theory admit that this "computer" produces a lot of waste as it buds off different solutions – new businesses, products and services – and then pr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of June Link Assortment, Slightly Late]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42728</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/07/01/end-of-june-link-assortment-slightly-late/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T12:31:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events July 2 (tomorrow!), the San Francisco Bay IF Meetup gets together. July 10, 2-4 PM PDT, is the next session of the Seattle/Tacoma IF group. It will meet via Discord, and will feature a discussion on working with the Dialog development system. ParserComp games are now available to play and vote on through July 31. There’s … Continue reading "End of June Link Assortment, Slightly Late"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web development is like assembling IKEA furniture]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7275</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/07/01/web-development-is-like-assembling-ikea-furniture/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T11:06:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m currently putting things together for a new flat and I realised that there are a lot of similarities between assembling IKEA furniture and doing web development. You get a huge bag of seemingly random parts and you should sort them before you start Everything is standardised and uses building blocks The manual is meant […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Killian Wells, CEO of Fragrance House Xyrena, Shares The Joy He Finds In His Corner Of The Internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69362</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/killian-wells-ceo-of-fragrance-house-xyrena-shares-the-joy-he-finds-in-his-corner-of-the-internet/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Killian Wells, CEO of Fragrance House Xyrena, Shares The Joy He Finds In His Corner Of The Internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Killian Wells, CEO of Fragrance House Xyrena, Shares The Joy He Finds In His Corner Of The Internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69362</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/internet-culture/killian-wells-ceo-of-fragrance-house-xyrena-shares-the-joy-he-finds-in-his-corner-of-the-internet/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Killian Wells, CEO of Fragrance House Xyrena, Shares The Joy He Finds In His Corner Of The Internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When software makes you laugh! (…creativity as a mechanic, how it exists in games, and the ethics of either empowering or exploiting creation)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5431</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/when-software-makes-you-laugh-creativity-as-a-mechanic-how-it-exists-in-games-and-the-ethics-of-either-empowering-or-exploiting-creation"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T01:47:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of exciting tool related developments have been happening in the indie game space since my last post. Go get lost checking out all The Tool Jam 2 submissions… also my Cool Tools itch.io collection is at its 400th addition as of today! When I started writing about tools, and putting together that curation, I thought I would stop at maybe 30… or 100 if I felt like doing too much work. I only got into paying attention to all this because of the Electric Zine Maker, and I wanted to highlight other exciting work done in this space....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Universe by Scientific Field]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2640/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2640/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/the_universe_by_scientific_field.png" title="The math and philosophy people also claim everything, but the astronomers argue that the stuff they study really only comprises a small number of paper surfaces." alt="The math and philosophy people also claim everything, but the astronomers argue that the stuff they study really only comprises a small number of paper surfaces." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Pocket collection for your wellness journey, as curated by the team behind ‘The Science of Happiness’ podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69374</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/pocket/science-of-happiness-podcast-wellness-dacher-keltner/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-30T17:24:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to live a more fulfilling life? The internet gives plenty of advice. But finding guidance backed by research can get tricky. That’s where The Science of Happiness podcast comes in. Co-produced by PRX and UC Berkeley’s Greater Good Science Center, the popular podcast explores science-backed strategies to cultivate a happier life. Its new series, […]
The post A Pocket collection for your wellness journey, as curated by the team behind ‘The Science of Happiness’ podcast appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Pocket collection for your wellness journey, as curated by the team behind ‘The Science of Happiness’ podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69374</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/products/pocket/science-of-happiness-podcast-wellness-dacher-keltner/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-30T17:24:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to live a more fulfilling life? The internet gives plenty of advice. But finding guidance backed by research can get tricky. That’s where The Science of Happiness podcast comes in. Co-produced by PRX and UC Berkeley’s Greater Good Science Center, the popular podcast explores science-backed strategies to cultivate a happier life. Its new series, […]
The post A Pocket collection for your wellness journey, as curated by the team behind ‘The Science of Happiness’ podcast appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3832</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/30/mckinsey-mafia/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-30T17:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links McKinsey, consiglieri of the opioid crisis: "Without admitting any wrongdoing." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading McKinsey, consiglieri of the opioid crisis (permalink) McKinsey is a global "consulting" giant, with its tendrils in every unsavory industry from private ICE gulags to (mis)managing violent prisons to publicly funded private charter schools. Internally, McKinsey promotes itself as akin to the Jesuits and the Marines (no, really): "analytically rigorous, deeply principled seekers of knowledge and truth." https://www.propublica.org/article/how-mckinsey-makes-its-own-rules McKinsey has been embroiled in an endl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 29 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3827</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/29/no-i-in-uter-us/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-29T16:15:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Abortion surveillance only incidentally involves period-trackers: It's all your digital stuff, plus snitchy friends and doctors. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Abortion surveillance only incidentally involves period-trackers (permalink) I get it. The deeper we get into this GOP christofascist Handmaid's Tale LARP, the more it feels like we are living in a dystopian novel and the more draw on stories to understand our experience. The idea that a cyberpunk Red State sheriff – Boss Hogg meets Robocop – would use period-tracking apps for dragnet abortion surveillance is a great setup for a novel, but it's not very reflective o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Releasing Color.js: A library that takes color seriously]]></title>
        <id>https://lea.verou.me/?p=3463</id>
        <link href="https://lea.verou.me/2022/06/releasing-colorjs/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-29T11:24:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Related: Chris’ blog post for the release of Color.js This post has been long overdue: Chris and I started working on Color.js in 2020, over 2 years ago! It was shortly after I had finished the Color lecture for the class I was teaching at MIT and I was appalled by the lack of color […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lea Verou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Periodic Table Changes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2639/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2639/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/periodic_table_changes.png" title="It's nice how the end of the periodic table is flush with the edge these days, so I think we should agree no one should find any new elements after #118 unless they discover a whole row at once." alt="It's nice how the end of the periodic table is flush with the edge these days, so I think we should agree no one should find any new elements after #118 unless they discover a whole row at once." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why did Safari go batman? [blog]]]></title>
        <id>why-did-safari-go-batman</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/06/29/why-did-safari-go-batman"/>
        <updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week I released the first round of tickets for ffconf 2022 an in a last minute change (literally 20 minutes before the tickets went live), I decided to add a live countdown which would switch out and then show the "Buy Now" button at 10am.
Except, of course, Safari didn't work.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking screenshots of streaming video services using Browser Developer Tools]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7272</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/06/28/taking-screenshots-of-streaming-video-services-using-browser-developer-tools/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-28T19:58:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the more overly strict features of video players in modern operating systems is that you can not use screen recording or screenshot tools to record content from streaming video platforms like Netflix or Disney+. Whilst I understand the need for DRM and preventing recording a streaming program, taking screenshots is a different matter. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3822</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/28/bartlebytron-3000/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-28T17:38:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Decrapify cookie consent dialogs with the Consent-O-Matic: Comcom steps in where GDPR enforcement failed. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Decrapify cookie consent dialogs with the Consent-O-Matic (permalink) Remember when they sneered at Geocities pages for being unusable eyesores? It's true, those old sites had some, uh, idiosyncratic design choices, but at least they reflected a real person's exuberant ideas about what looked and worked well. Today's web is an unusable eyesore by design. Start with those fucking "sign up for our newsletter" interruptors. Email is the last federated protocol standing, so everyone who…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on running containers with bubblewrap]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/06/28/some-notes-on-bubblewrap/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/06/28/some-notes-on-bubblewrap/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-28T12:24:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! About a year ago I got mad about Docker container startup time. This was
because I was building an nginx playground
where I was starting a new “container” on every HTTP request, and so for it to
feel reasonably snappy, nginx needed to start quickly.
Also, I was running this project on a pretty small cloud machine (256MB RAM), a
small CPU, so I really wanted to avoid unnecessary overhead.
I’ve been looking for a way to run containers faster since then, but I couldn’t
find one until last week when I discovered
bubblewrap!! It’s very fast and I
think it’s super cool, but I also ran into a bunch of fun problems that I
wanted to write down for my future self.
some disclaimers
I’m not sure if the way I’m using bubblewrap in this post is maybe not how it’s intended to be used
there are a l…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recording Academy’s VP of D.E.I. Ryan Butler Tells Us What Brings Him Joy Online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69351</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/internet-culture/recording-academys-vp-of-d-e-i-ryan-butler-tells-us-what-brings-him-joy-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Recording Academy’s VP of D.E.I. Ryan Butler Tells Us What Brings Him Joy Online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recording Academy’s VP of D.E.I. Ryan Butler Tells Us What Brings Him Joy Online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69351</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/recording-academys-vp-of-d-e-i-ryan-butler-tells-us-what-brings-him-joy-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Recording Academy’s VP of D.E.I. Ryan Butler Tells Us What Brings Him Joy Online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3817</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/27/reps-and-warranties/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T15:36:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Reasonable Agreement": "On the Crapification of Literary Contracts." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Reasonable Agreement" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my recent @Medium column, "Reasonable Agreement: On the Crapification of Literary Contracts," about the alarming standardization of non-negotiable (and terrible) contracting terms in freelance writing contracts: https://doctorow.medium.com/reasonable-agreement-ea8600a89ed7 I started selling to magazines in the 1980s, a moment when Reagan's antitrust deregulation drove waves of mergers in the market. The major magazines were changi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Wonderful HTML Email Workflow]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/wonderful-emails-with-mjml-and-mdx/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/wonderful-emails-with-mjml-and-mdx/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've ever had the misfortune of being tasked with building a template for HTML emails, you know it's tricky business! In this blog post, I share the approach I took to build responsive, client-friendly emails without a single 
 tag.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extended NFPA Hazard Diamond]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2638/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2638/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/extended_nfpa_hazard_diamond.png" title="With most labs, the hushed horror stories are about something like dimethylmercury or prions, but occasionally you'll get a weird lab where it's about the soda machine or the drop ceiling." alt="With most labs, the hushed horror stories are about something like dimethylmercury or prions, but occasionally you'll get a weird lab where it's about the soda machine or the drop ceiling." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 25 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3813</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/25/roe-v-wade-v-abortion/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-25T15:58:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The oligarchs' Supreme Court: Getting turkeys to vote for Christmas ain't cheap. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The oligarchs' Supreme Court (permalink) Here's something weird: in the wake of Roe v Wade in the 1970s, the Southern Baptist Convention repeatedly passed resolutions affirming the right to abortion and rejecting government interference in the decision to bear a child to term: https://text.npr.org/734303135 Back then, white evangelicals were deeply suspicious of people who opposed abortion. Getting too worked up about the issue was a sign of crypto-papacy, and back then, white evangelicals hated Catholics: …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discussing two "holy war" topics at the same time]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-17T23:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cutting to the chase: text editors *and* tabs vs. spaces!  Ooooh!


I've had this thing called "e" for a while now.  It's a stupid little 
script which serves to do a couple of things.  It starts my 
editor
with a given file, and it kicks it with the right arguments to make it 
disable line wrapping and to make the [TAB] key actually put in two 
spaces.


So, my dumb script would use "-w -E -T 2" most of the time, except when it 
was running on a Makefile, at which point it would skip those args.  
Simple enough, right?


pico is back?  Yes indeed, on Macs, as of 12.3, pico is in fact back.  To 
make sure I wasn't imagining things, I tracked down a machine that hadn't 
been upgraded yet and checked there.  Sure enough, it was in fact nano and 
not pico.


macOS 12.3 has nano as a symlink... pointing to pico!


At some point, I switched from literal tab characters in my source code to 
blobs of spaces, probably due to using that style at work and not hating 
it.  So, somewhere along the line I actually started depending on nano 
behavior without realizing it.


As for the lack of a feature in pico itself, it's kind of strange, really.  
If you go digging into the source, they have this random.c with a function 
called tab which claims to "simulate tab stop" using spaces.  That said, I 
can't find any place where it would be called with the magic values which 
would make it behave that way.


It wouldn't surprise me if this switch is just more of Apple removing 
GPLed things from their OS - pico seems to use the Apache license.  They 
dumped bash for zsh (MIT license) at some point (Big Sur, I think), and 
now this?  Okay then.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dumb things you can sometimes do with hard links]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-16T01:51:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a very old and stupid trick you could do with some filesystems in 
some situations back in the day... and might still be able to do in a 
few places today.


The problem is that while version X might eventually have an exploit, 
it'll get removed and it'll be replaced by version Y without that
particular hole.  By the time you get your hands on a tool to break into 
X, it'll be gone.


What you'd do is create a hard link pointing at the file you wanted to 
preserve, storing it in a spot which was writable by your account.  
Then, say, /usr/bin/sudo (because that never has security 
issues...) gets replaced at some point with a new file and you get to 
keep the old version.  When you get the tool to pop it, off you go!


Of course, these days, it's not quite so easy on the more modern systems 
you find.  Debian 11 here won't let me do it - it's EPERM city.  Rocky 8 
(so CentOS 8 and RHEL 8 too) also won't do it.  They both have some gunk
in /usr/lib/sysctl.d to lock this down.  But, my old Slackware 14.2 
install of my workstation let me do it the last time I tried about 
a year ago.  How about that, huh?  I bet it'd still work if I dug out 
the old drives and booted them up.


Incidentally, this is the magic sauce: /proc/sys/fs/protected_hardlinks
Read the man page for proc(5) to learn more about it.

here it is,
the thread I read a long time ago.  It's interesting to note that as far 
as I can tell, nothing actually changed upstream.  This left paranoid 
admins like me with no option but to use the (most excellent) Openwall 
patches to lock down this kind of stuff.  I used that on my machines at 
work which had non-staff users... just in case.


This whole situation is scary.  
Read more about it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More stories about stacks of modems]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-14T23:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in January, you might have seen my
post
about a very large BBS which seemed to solve for the problem of "how do 
we host a bunch of users" by having one physical box per user.  It might 
have been one physical box per *two* users, maybe, but it's hard to say.


Now, keep in mind digital cameras weren't easy to come by, so I have 
very few actual pictures.  I'll have to do a lot of explaining to make 
up for the lack of detail and alternate angles.  Clearly, I had no 
notion of ever using these pictures to tell stories 25+ years later.


Some friends at a local company had some bandwidth to spare (a T1 to 
Alternet somewhere, as I recall), so they parked a Zoom modem on one of 
their boxes and plugged it into a phone line.  We got an identical model 
to avoid cross-brand issues (Zoom m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking away the berries]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-13T02:14:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I sometimes write the beginnings of posts but don't post them.  I still 
save them in case conditions change or other things happen and make me 
want to follow up on the topic.  In this case, I wrote something about 
offices before the whole COVID lockdown thing happened and people 
largely stopped going to offices every day.  With that in mind, let's 
proceed.


However, tech companies decided to go past this at some point and 
brought about this whole notion of "microkitchens".  This is where 
they'd put their branding on the coolers (instead of "Coca-Cola" or 
"Pepsi") and would load it up with every kind of fizzy sugary liquid 
they could get their hands on.  They'd have racks and racks of shelving 
packed with all sorts of interesting crunchy, sugary and carb-loaded 
snacks.  They'd a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at the outlying data points]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T07:04:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the fun things I used to do at a prior job was to dig through the 
raw data points which were collected from the *many* servers we had.  I 
could just pick an interesting-sounding metric and then would just ask 
the system to show me the top 10 or bottom 10 out of a population of 
thousands or more.


To get my feet wet with the whole "investigations" thing that we'd do, I 
started looking into this one day and chose one of the many temp sensors 
which were being logged by the servers.  I forget exactly which one it 
was, for there were many.  The CPUs logged it, the chassis logged it, 
the power supply logged it, and so on.  There were so many choices.


I went looking for a reason.  What could possibly explain this?  First 
off, it didn't line up with any obvious pattern in the host names.  The 
hosts were named for whichever team owned them, followed by a sequence 
number that was bumped any time a new one was provisioned.  There was no 
signal to be found in that.


There was more, though.  You could also see a "rack position" in this 
data, and now it started getting interesting.  It seems that all of the 
really hot machines had a rack position of something low, like 04 or 05, 
and never anything higher than that.  In fact, when looking at a whole 
rack, it was always the lowest number of all of the positions that were 
being used.  Now this was worth chasing!


It's good that I asked, since they told me something surprising: 
position 04 or 05 or whatever was the *bottom* of the rack.  Yes, 
somehow, the lowest machine in the rack was the hottest!  They found 
this interesting, too, and wound up digging into it.  Given that I was 
far away in a distant office, this was the best way for us to proceed.


The problem was that the bottommost server would have nothing below it 
but just open space until it got to the floor.  That space would not 
move air efficiently, and it obviously mattered.


This rolled out and my hot spots disappeared.  Fantastic!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Questions about construction trucks on train tracks]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T01:26:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another day, another bit of local flavor, but this time it's something I 
wish I didn't have to write about.

wrote
about seeing a maintenance truck rolling down the Caltrain line in 
Mountain View.  It had a special attachment to let it stay on the rails.  
At no point did the arms come down for the crossing.  It managed to 
approach, then the people inside looked around and went through, and the 
arms never budged.  There were no flashing lights or bells.




caught fire.  A bunch of people were hurt.  More were shaken 
up.


I'm assuming their construction trucks don't trigger the "short the 
rails together to signal various things" logic, either.  This would 
mean that crossing arms stay up... and I have to assume it also means 
the signals along the way stay green instead of going red.

We will presumably hear more about whatever the signals said, and 
whether the train went past a red signal or not.  I just have a bad 
feeling that they saw a green and kept on going.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toll signs on 101 report your transponder setting]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-10T03:50:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a little bit of Silicon Valley local flavor for a change.  We 
have this freeway that runs from San Jose to San Francisco called US 
101, or around here, just "101".  (Southern California has it too, but 
they call it "the" 101.  That's how we detect invaders.)  Anyway, this 
thing is usually eight or more lanes up and down the peninsula, and it's 
had a "diamond" or car pool lane on the #1 (innermost/"fast") lane for 
many years.  You had to have a certain number of people in the car (or 
some other conditions met) during certain hours (AM and PM rush, 
weekdays), or you'd be in for a hefty ticket.


How does the system know what to charge you?  Well, you either have an 
old-style toll transponder that always bills you as a solo driver, or 
you have a new-style transponder with a 1/2/3+ switch that tells the 
road how to handle you.


Think about what this does to enforcement.  Now, instead of just "is 
there a vehicle in the lane", "is it the right time during a weekday", 
and "how many people are in the car", now it's also a matter of "do they 
have their transponder set properly".


Check this out.



CHP
could roll up on them and give them a ticket.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A parasitic RPC service that broke core dumps]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T04:39:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I already told a
story
about how you can hose your machine by pointing the Linux kernel at a 
custom core dump handler and then have that handler fail to function.  
This'll clog up the pipe (really), and then everything else will just 
stack up behind it.  Pretty soon, every crashing process will be stuck 
just the same.


Once upon a time, in a big company environment, someone decided that 
they wanted to provide a service to other things running on the same 
Linux box.  But, instead of either writing Yet Another Service (tm) 
that would go through release processes and all of that good stuff, they 
went for a different design entirely.


There are so many problems with this.  You have the issue of a "server" 
that appears out of thin air depending on who or what starts first on 
the mac…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A sysadmin's rant about feed readers and crawlers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-08T17:49:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If a web site makes an RSS or Atom feed available, it's not a bad idea 
to poll it from time to time.  Actually doing that poll like a good 
netizen (remember that concept?) takes a little attention to detail.


Given the reality of the situation, does it make sense to poll every 10 
seconds?  Probably not, right?  Someone set up something like that and 
left it running for a couple of months until I finally noticed it and 
dealt with it myself.


Given this, you can keep track of the "Last-Modified" header when you 
get a copy of the feed.  Then, you can turn around and use that same 
value in an "If-Modified-Since" header the next time you come to look 
for an update.  If nothing's changed, the web server will notice it's 
the same as what it already has, and it'll send you a HTTP 304 co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editing stuff in prod]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-05T21:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a concept: "ssh to prod and edit directly on the machine" is 
generally bad news.


I should point out that I didn't know this person and had no idea how 
they would respond to such feedback - it might have been fine!  They 
might be a well-adjusted person who can take a request like that and not 
turn it around into a full-on nuclear attack.  But, I didn't know either 
way.


At some point, I actually had a meeting with this developer for some 
other reason, and what happened was kind of amazing.  First thing, he 
brought it up and asked me about it.  I said something like, "well, I 
didn't want to get into it, but since you asked", and proceeded into 
something along the lines of "obviously it would be best if you didn't 
do that - sshing in and twiddling Python files on the actual production 
AWS instance of the service".


"But... I suspect you are doing it for some reason?"


My response was... I hope... reasonable: "So as much as I would love to 
say 'don't do that!!!', I'm not going to stand in the way of you 
literally doing your job.  So please proceed with care, and keep an eye 
open for some day when (first dumb thing) and (second dumb thing) aren't 
problems any more and you need not do this any more."


It was either "edit in prod" or endure DAY LONG development cycles: make 
a change, wait 24 hours, come back tomorrow, and try it again.  That's 
how broken it was.


The best part about this was that we had a totally reasonable 
conversation about it.  It's the kind of thing which had become a rare 
commodity in those days at that place.


Would I expect someone else to go to that level of insanity every single 
time they just want to get their job done?  Absolutely not.

Editing files in prod to develop them?  That's bad news.  Deliberately 
rigging tunnels to spoof a connection from prod?  That's also bad news.  
Having to do them to get your job done?  You might be in the bad place.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's now your fault they don't know about it]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-04T00:14:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quite a while back, I wrote a post that basically went like this: if 
someone has a problem with someone else or something that person is 
doing, they're going to find a way to get to "no".  They will find some 
reason, some excuse, or some problem with it.  They'll bring up a point 
and you'll show that this is not in fact a thing.  They will then pivot 
again and again.


But, as I said, that was back then, and this time I'm talking about 
something else: when it happens in person with a coworker.  I had an 
experience like this a few years back, and figured I'd share how it goes 
for the sake of others who might not have encountered it yet, or who 
have and thought they were alone in this.


Coworker: There are no docs for [this thing you're doing].


Coworker: You could make a wiki pag…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universally unique identifier?  Sometimes...]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-02T03:44:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a short one since it's somewhere between a random bit of 
"grab some popcorn" amusement and a "huh, that might be a problem some 
day".  In short, it looks like every Raspberry Pi filesystem installed 
from any given release image probably ends up with the same
UUID.


For instance, if you downloaded the "lite" version of Raspbian between 
roughly November 8th and January 28th, you probably got a file called 
2021-10-30-raspios-bullseye-armhf-lite.zip.  Inside, there's an image, 
and the idea is that you dump that straight to your SD card, cram it in 
the Pi, and off you go.  The second partition on that image is an ext4 
filesystem which was created on some build machine somewhere.  The UUID 
on it never gets "evolved" to something else after the install.


You can see it inside the image itself here:


Or, if you actually installed a few of these things like I did over the 
past couple of months, you can just 'tune2fs -l /dev/mmcblk0p2' and see 
the same value in there.


Don't end up with a pile of SD cards on your desk and think "I know, 
I'll use the filesystem UUIDs to track which one goes where", in other 
words.


If it's not breaking anything for you, it's probably best to just let it 
be.  Untangling a boot mess on these weird little boxes is anything but 
fun.

Note: if you're actually on a recent Raspberry Pi, odds are good that 
your /etc/fstab will be using *partition* UUIDs (PARTUUID=...) and not 
those of the filesystem.  If in doubt, use blkid to see what's what.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Command-V (or CTRL-V) is your "copilot"]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-28T22:54:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A reader wrote in asking what I thought about the whole GitHub "copilot" 
thing.  If you haven't heard of it yet, it's apparently this thing that 
was trained on a whole mess of repositories and their code, and you can 
"prompt" it and it'll spit out code that may or may not do what you 
want.  It doesn't seem to know about licensing (BSD, GPL, MIT, that sort 
of thing), or plagiarism, or any of that other good stuff.


This is actually a story about somewhere I used to work, and someone who 
was on one of my teams back in the day.  One day, I heard that one of 
the people in a far-away office had created some kind of tool that would 
let you look at the status of different machines - that is, Linux boxes. 
I don't remember the finer points of it or why this person even 
bothered, but they…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[C++ header files and inter-class connections]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-27T11:35:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are some interesting implications to the way that you have to 
handle references to other bits of code when you write a C++ header 
file.  There are things you can do which turn out to be suboptimal, and 
until or unless you work someplace with a coding style document or get 
some mentor who's already been there, you're likely to make some
mistakes.


Anyway, a common way to do this is to set up the outer class such that 
it has a pointer to the inner one.  You *could* have it just own it 
directly, but then that introduces problems.



 private:
  Bar bar_;



Of course, bar.h probably has its own dependencies which get #included, 
and so now you end up with this evil web of slow compiles.  It sucks.


What used to happen next is that someone would say, okay, let's make it 
a pointe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Results without all of the brackets]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-22T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, I
put forth
a bunch of API possibilities for the problem of needing to return a 
value but also indicating the lack of a value and being able to comment 
on why.  In it, the notion of a "wrapper" around a string was presented, 
such that it might look like "Result<string>", and those brackets 
started looking like a pain.  There was also the possibility of having 
something like "ResultString", but didn't that open the door to having a 
bunch of code duplication?


After this had existed for a while, the general happy feeling of having 
this stuff in place became infectious.  I wanted it to cover other 
things with it, too.  I wanted it to handle something a bit more 
complicated than a mere string, and so decided to try my hand at the 
template-wrangling metaprogramming cruft t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Returning values and errors]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-20T21:33:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you agree with the notion that you need to be able to tell the 
difference between the absence of a value and a value itself, then this 
has some impacts on the code you write.  If you want to keep 'em 
separated (so they can come out and play), then it gets you looking at 
your API designs in certain ways.


Imagine we're talking about a helper function that is intended to be run 
inside a program that's handling the access to a web page.  It's 
probably a CGI program, but it could also be buried inside some much 
bigger thing, too.  This is all about C++ styles, but you can probably 
see slices of other languages in here, too.


string UserIP() -- No more lifetime worries here, but oops, uh, well, 
what if we don't know what it is and need to provide an error?  If it's 
a CGI situatio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My "daily drivers", and what happened to Slackware here]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T21:48:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In
yesterday's post,
I mentioned taking my old Mac Mini out of the OS X/macos ecosystem and 
bringing it into Debian, and then what kind of hilarity followed when I 
attempted to install a Javascript linter (and it tried to drag in 180+ 
node-related packages).


Readers are advised that this post will probably contain 
definitely contains a even higher than usual amount of 
navel-gazing as I dish out the details of my setup.  My usual 
disclaimer of "this works for me and probably won't work for you, so if 
you have different tastes, then great, go with that" definitely applies 
here.


First of all, the one that most people actually notice is the actual box 
which is serving rachelbythebay.com, which at the moment is a box called 
snowgoose.  I had installed it in early 2020 as CentOS 8 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A twisted maze of dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T03:07:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh sure, everyone laughs about things having a lot of dependencies, but 
do they ever really think about the implications of having hundreds of 
teeny little libraries, all moving independently?  This is how it 
manifests in the real world.


My relative inexperience with Debian systems means I'm constantly being 
delighted to discover that such and such has already been packaged up 
and is just an apt command away.  Things that I would have done by hand 
in the years up to this point now have someone else worrying about them.


This is what happened next:


... huh.  The story basically ends there.  I'm going to handle this some 
other way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add 4740180 to the list of silly magic numbers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T08:11:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh dear.  The software fungus where bits of code take the
literal characters "HTTP" as a number
has expanded.  Now it has a variant: 4740180.


Where does this one come from?  
Go and gRPC, apparently!


I found this while searching the web for "1213486160" to see how things 
have been going in the past few years.  Unfortunately, it's still biting 
people all over the place.  There are far too many posts asking people 
to upgrade their software, or restart things, or do any number of 
useless rubber-chicken-waving techniques which ultimately will 
accomplish nothing.

When you see a funny-looking number, figure out where it comes from.
That's the only way to have any chance of understanding what's actually 
going on.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feedback: environments, old BBSes, Honda's 2022 bug]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T23:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yep, it's time for another round of reader feedback.

"process infection" story:

https://lwn.net/Articles/883547/):


If you do privileged execution of specific operations via IPC you get 
the guarantee that whatever is done, is done from a well-defined, 
pristine execution environment, without leaking context implicitly. The 
IPC message is the *full* vulnerable surface, and that's as minimal as 
it can get. And that's great.




Oh wow, thank you for mentioning that, unnamed reader!  I definitely 
read that post on LWN at some point in the past couple of days when the 
pkexec thing started going around.  It must have really worked its way 
into my head, and then eventually stirred up the memory of everything 
getting "nicely infected" at $OLD_JOB.


Every time I talk about trying to par…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A nice story about Unix processes "infecting" each other]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T19:24:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I once worked at a place that had an interesting little problem stemming 
from the way they managed machines and some of the fun side-effects 
processes can have on each other.  This is back in the pre-systemd days 
of running services, such that things tended to be started or restarted 
by someone or something that itself ran as root.  That is, if you 
started something, it might inherit one or more things from your 
environment.  Likewise, if you ran something with an unusual 
environment, it might bestow those "gifts" onto anything it happened to 
touch.


After locking themselves out of machines too many times, people 
generally learned that after you mess with a glibc upgrade, you restart 
the sshd listener on port 22.  Of course, they also had to learn to not 
whack EVERY sshd at the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An old photo of a very large BBS]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 30 years ago, I was given this picture.  I wanted to present it 
in a post all by itself to give it a chance to "sink in" before I went 
and used it in an analogy.  First, I'll just show the image and explain 
what you're looking at here.




I do remember the description from the back: this is a picture of *part 
of* something that was called the Software Creations BBS.  It was a 
multi-line bulletin board system where you could dial up and send 
messages to people, upload and download files, and (presumably) play 
online games ("doors") and anything else they cared to offer.

64 machines in a little space.  I have to assume 
they are at least 
286s (ATs, more or 
less), but it's impossible to tell from just this picture.  They could 
have been 386s or even 486s by that point, but …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One machine can go pretty far if you build things properly]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, so yesterday I 
posted
a picture of an old multi-line bulletin board system which had 
apparently taken over an entire bedroom with dozens of computers.  I 
mentioned that I intended to come back to the topic to throw in my own 
two cents, and so here we go.


Or, were you someone who found it horrific and wished there was a 
simpler way?  Did you wonder if it would be possible to pack all of that 
into one or maybe two boxes, instead?  Did you want a way to negate all 
of that complexity while still providing the same level of service?


Now, things are different.  I look at that and just sigh at the lost 
opportunities.  The actual amount of work being done on behalf of any of 
the users who are connected is tiny.  If we ignore the fact that the 
actual BBS software and related acc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>