<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html</id>
    <title>Ajour / Spitlo.com</title>
    <updated>2022-07-12T00:37:56.382Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statements Vs. Expressions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/javascript/statements-vs-expressions/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/javascript/statements-vs-expressions/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-11T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the most foundational things to understand about JavaScript is that programs are made up of statements, and statements have slots for expressions. In this blog post, we'll dig into how these two structures work, and see how building an intuition about this can help us solve practical problems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring tiny web services]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/07/09/monitoring-small-web-services/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/07/09/monitoring-small-web-services/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-09T09:25:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I’ve started to run a few more servers recently
(nginx playground,
mess with dns,
dns lookup), so I’ve been
thinking about monitoring.
It wasn’t initially totally obvious to me how to monitor these websites, so I
wanted to quickly write up what how I did it.
I’m not going to talk about how to monitor Big Serious Mission Critical
websites at all, only tiny unimportant websites.
goal: spend approximately 0 time on operations
I want the sites to mostly work, but I also want to spend approximately 0% of
my time on the ongoing operations.
I was initially very wary of running servers at all because at my last job I
was on a 24⁄7 oncall rotation for some critical services, and in my mind “being
responsible for servers” meant “get woken up at 2am to fix the servers” and
“have lots of compli…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3877</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/08/jubilant/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T17:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Finance caused the fall of Rome: A politics of protecting contracts and property is a civilizational suicide pact. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Finance caused the fall of Rome (permalink) It's hard to overstate the impact that David Graeber's 2012 blockbuster Debt: The First Five Thousand Years had on society; it's a truly magisterial history of the way that debt – and debt forgiveness – played in the establishment of advanced civilization and its downfall: https://www.tor.com/2012/04/16/the-best-science-fiction-ideas-in-any-non-fiction-ever-david-graebers-debt-the-first-five-thousand-years/ Graeber – a key Occupy …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cosmologist Gift]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2643/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2643/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/cosmologist_gift.png" title="These neutrinos were freshly produced by a local source just 8 minutes ago" alt="These neutrinos were freshly produced by a local source just 8 minutes ago" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3867</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/07/collectivism/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-07T16:42:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Countervailing power: Finding the hairball's loose ends. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Countervailing power (permalink) It's hard not to feel powerless. The rich are getting richer, the middle class is disappearing, and poor people are evermore exposed to labor abuses, predatory finance, police violence, and food-, fuel- and housing-insecurity. Our cities are increasingly segregated into the haves and have-nots, and the haves hoard the parks, schools and clean air: https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/06/us/economic-segregation-income.html The rich don't just own all the good stuff, they also own the political process. The now…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meta-Alternating Current]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2642/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2642/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/meta_alternating_current.png" title="It's always bothered me that you can't cancel out an inverter by putting a second inverter after it." alt="It's always bothered me that you can't cancel out an inverter by putting a second inverter after it." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing for Games: Theory & Practice (Hannah Nicklin)]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42745</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/07/05/writing-for-games-theory-practice-hannah-nicklin/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing for Games: Theory & Practice is a new book from Hannah Nicklin, focused very specifically on the writing rather than the narrative design aspects of the field. If the difference feels fuzzy to you, you’re not alone: many indie game roles require writers/designers to do a bit of both of those things. There’s a … Continue reading "Writing for Games: Theory & Practice (Hannah Nicklin)"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3856</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/05/grab-the-wheel/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T15:27:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links "The Swerve": My Locus column on hope in the dark. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading "The Swerve" (permalink) My latest Locus Magazine column is "The Swerve," a short essay about the shape that hope takes when happy endings are off the table – it's specifically about the looming environmental collapse, but it also describes my view on the polycrisis of musketfuckery, forced birth, and covid denial: https://locusmag.com/2022/07/cory-doctorow-the-swerve/ In this metaphor, we are in a bus barreling toward a cliff. The people in the front seats – who control the driver – insist that we don't need to turn the bus before we g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TIL: Visual Studio Code does markdown autocompletion for in-page links]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7278</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/07/05/til-visual-studio-code-does-autocompletion-in-markdown-for-auto-generated-targets-of-headlines/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T14:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you write markdown files, headings automatically also get an ID generated so they become in-page targets to link to. This is also used to create a table of contents in various publishing systems. Today I learned that VS Code also offers these generated IDs as an autocomplete when you type links. If you wrap […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mouse Turbines]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2641/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2641/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/mouse_turbines.png" title="It's sad seeing those videos of turbine blade being torn apart in high winds, but it's the only way they can disperse their seeds." alt="It's sad seeing those videos of turbine blade being torn apart in high winds, but it's the only way they can disperse their seeds." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for June]]></title>
        <id>log.html#june2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#june2022"/>
        <updated>2022-07-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of June. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Uxn, improved the Uxntal reference sheet and improved the Uxntal cheatsheet.
Dexe, added menu bar.
Nasu, added menu bar.
Noodle}, added menu bar.
100r.co, updated boom tent, and added lpg refit (backdated update).
News
Pino is currently in Desolation Sound, enjoying the quiet. We've written a few posts about some of the anchorages we've visited, like {melanie cove}, {grace harbour} and {hathayim marine park}. We're updating our track as we go.
Devine has been adding a lot of notes to the permacomputing wiki this month. We also started a little arcade game named Inle, something that we could play together on the boat in the style of Gunbound/Tank Wars... but with rabbits (we finished reading Watership Down last month, so we blame that, haha). We don't have a project page yet for it, but we shared some images on the post for grace harbour, where we started working on the game.
Rekka produced a video about image optimization for the Photographer's Gallery (as part of their Green Hacks video series) last month.
Pino book club
We're reading The Man who Mistook his Wife for a Hat by Oliver Sacks.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Jul 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3837</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/07/01/whip-it-good/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T16:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links After inflation, the whip-crack: Broken telephone, but for back-orders. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading After inflation, the whip-crack (permalink) There's a school of economics that likens the economy to a computer, one that we all power. Every time we buy something – or walk away from an offer – we feed data to the computer, which transmits this price- and demand-information from consumers to producers to financiers, so that demand can be met with supply. The proponents of this theory admit that this "computer" produces a lot of waste as it buds off different solutions – new businesses, products and services – and then pr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of June Link Assortment, Slightly Late]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42728</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/07/01/end-of-june-link-assortment-slightly-late/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T12:31:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events July 2 (tomorrow!), the San Francisco Bay IF Meetup gets together. July 10, 2-4 PM PDT, is the next session of the Seattle/Tacoma IF group. It will meet via Discord, and will feature a discussion on working with the Dialog development system. ParserComp games are now available to play and vote on through July 31. There’s … Continue reading "End of June Link Assortment, Slightly Late"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web development is like assembling IKEA furniture]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7275</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/07/01/web-development-is-like-assembling-ikea-furniture/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T11:06:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m currently putting things together for a new flat and I realised that there are a lot of similarities between assembling IKEA furniture and doing web development. You get a huge bag of seemingly random parts and you should sort them before you start Everything is standardised and uses building blocks The manual is meant […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Killian Wells, CEO of Fragrance House Xyrena, Shares The Joy He Finds In His Corner Of The Internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69362</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/internet-culture/killian-wells-ceo-of-fragrance-house-xyrena-shares-the-joy-he-finds-in-his-corner-of-the-internet/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Killian Wells, CEO of Fragrance House Xyrena, Shares The Joy He Finds In His Corner Of The Internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When software makes you laugh! (…creativity as a mechanic, how it exists in games, and the ethics of either empowering or exploiting creation)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5431</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/when-software-makes-you-laugh-creativity-as-a-mechanic-how-it-exists-in-games-and-the-ethics-of-either-empowering-or-exploiting-creation"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T01:47:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of exciting tool related developments have been happening in the indie game space since my last post. Go get lost checking out all The Tool Jam 2 submissions… also my Cool Tools itch.io collection is at its 400th addition as of today! When I started writing about tools, and putting together that curation, I thought I would stop at maybe 30… or 100 if I felt like doing too much work. I only got into paying attention to all this because of the Electric Zine Maker, and I wanted to highlight other exciting work done in this space....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Universe by Scientific Field]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2640/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2640/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/the_universe_by_scientific_field.png" title="The math and philosophy people also claim everything, but the astronomers argue that the stuff they study really only comprises a small number of paper surfaces." alt="The math and philosophy people also claim everything, but the astronomers argue that the stuff they study really only comprises a small number of paper surfaces." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Pocket collection for your wellness journey, as curated by the team behind ‘The Science of Happiness’ podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69374</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/products/pocket/science-of-happiness-podcast-wellness-dacher-keltner/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-30T17:24:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to live a more fulfilling life? The internet gives plenty of advice. But finding guidance backed by research can get tricky. That’s where The Science of Happiness podcast comes in. Co-produced by PRX and UC Berkeley’s Greater Good Science Center, the popular podcast explores science-backed strategies to cultivate a happier life. Its new series, […]
The post A Pocket collection for your wellness journey, as curated by the team behind ‘The Science of Happiness’ podcast appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3832</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/30/mckinsey-mafia/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-30T17:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links McKinsey, consiglieri of the opioid crisis: "Without admitting any wrongdoing." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading McKinsey, consiglieri of the opioid crisis (permalink) McKinsey is a global "consulting" giant, with its tendrils in every unsavory industry from private ICE gulags to (mis)managing violent prisons to publicly funded private charter schools. Internally, McKinsey promotes itself as akin to the Jesuits and the Marines (no, really): "analytically rigorous, deeply principled seekers of knowledge and truth." https://www.propublica.org/article/how-mckinsey-makes-its-own-rules McKinsey has been embroiled in an endl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 29 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3827</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/29/no-i-in-uter-us/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-29T16:15:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Abortion surveillance only incidentally involves period-trackers: It's all your digital stuff, plus snitchy friends and doctors. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Abortion surveillance only incidentally involves period-trackers (permalink) I get it. The deeper we get into this GOP christofascist Handmaid's Tale LARP, the more it feels like we are living in a dystopian novel and the more draw on stories to understand our experience. The idea that a cyberpunk Red State sheriff – Boss Hogg meets Robocop – would use period-tracking apps for dragnet abortion surveillance is a great setup for a novel, but it's not very reflective o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Releasing Color.js: A library that takes color seriously]]></title>
        <id>https://lea.verou.me/?p=3463</id>
        <link href="https://lea.verou.me/2022/06/releasing-colorjs/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-29T11:24:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Related: Chris’ blog post for the release of Color.js This post has been long overdue: Chris and I started working on Color.js in 2020, over 2 years ago! It was shortly after I had finished the Color lecture for the class I was teaching at MIT and I was appalled by the lack of color […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lea Verou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Periodic Table Changes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2639/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2639/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/periodic_table_changes.png" title="It's nice how the end of the periodic table is flush with the edge these days, so I think we should agree no one should find any new elements after #118 unless they discover a whole row at once." alt="It's nice how the end of the periodic table is flush with the edge these days, so I think we should agree no one should find any new elements after #118 unless they discover a whole row at once." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why did Safari go batman? [blog]]]></title>
        <id>why-did-safari-go-batman</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/06/29/why-did-safari-go-batman"/>
        <updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week I released the first round of tickets for ffconf 2022 an in a last minute change (literally 20 minutes before the tickets went live), I decided to add a live countdown which would switch out and then show the "Buy Now" button at 10am.
Except, of course, Safari didn't work.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking screenshots of streaming video services using Browser Developer Tools]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7272</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/06/28/taking-screenshots-of-streaming-video-services-using-browser-developer-tools/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-28T19:58:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the more overly strict features of video players in modern operating systems is that you can not use screen recording or screenshot tools to record content from streaming video platforms like Netflix or Disney+. Whilst I understand the need for DRM and preventing recording a streaming program, taking screenshots is a different matter. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3822</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/28/bartlebytron-3000/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-28T17:38:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Decrapify cookie consent dialogs with the Consent-O-Matic: Comcom steps in where GDPR enforcement failed. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Decrapify cookie consent dialogs with the Consent-O-Matic (permalink) Remember when they sneered at Geocities pages for being unusable eyesores? It's true, those old sites had some, uh, idiosyncratic design choices, but at least they reflected a real person's exuberant ideas about what looked and worked well. Today's web is an unusable eyesore by design. Start with those fucking "sign up for our newsletter" interruptors. Email is the last federated protocol standing, so everyone who…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on running containers with bubblewrap]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/06/28/some-notes-on-bubblewrap/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/06/28/some-notes-on-bubblewrap/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-28T12:24:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! About a year ago I got mad about Docker container startup time. This was
because I was building an nginx playground
where I was starting a new “container” on every HTTP request, and so for it to
feel reasonably snappy, nginx needed to start quickly.
Also, I was running this project on a pretty small cloud machine (256MB RAM), a
small CPU, so I really wanted to avoid unnecessary overhead.
I’ve been looking for a way to run containers faster since then, but I couldn’t
find one until last week when I discovered
bubblewrap!! It’s very fast and I
think it’s super cool, but I also ran into a bunch of fun problems that I
wanted to write down for my future self.
some disclaimers
I’m not sure if the way I’m using bubblewrap in this post is maybe not how it’s intended to be used
there are a l…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recording Academy’s VP of D.E.I. Ryan Butler Tells Us What Brings Him Joy Online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69351</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/internet-culture/recording-academys-vp-of-d-e-i-ryan-butler-tells-us-what-brings-him-joy-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Recording Academy’s VP of D.E.I. Ryan Butler Tells Us What Brings Him Joy Online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recording Academy’s VP of D.E.I. Ryan Butler Tells Us What Brings Him Joy Online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69351</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/recording-academys-vp-of-d-e-i-ryan-butler-tells-us-what-brings-him-joy-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Recording Academy’s VP of D.E.I. Ryan Butler Tells Us What Brings Him Joy Online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3817</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/27/reps-and-warranties/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T15:36:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Reasonable Agreement": "On the Crapification of Literary Contracts." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Reasonable Agreement" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my recent @Medium column, "Reasonable Agreement: On the Crapification of Literary Contracts," about the alarming standardization of non-negotiable (and terrible) contracting terms in freelance writing contracts: https://doctorow.medium.com/reasonable-agreement-ea8600a89ed7 I started selling to magazines in the 1980s, a moment when Reagan's antitrust deregulation drove waves of mergers in the market. The major magazines were changi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Wonderful HTML Email Workflow]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/wonderful-emails-with-mjml-and-mdx/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/wonderful-emails-with-mjml-and-mdx/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've ever had the misfortune of being tasked with building a template for HTML emails, you know it's tricky business! In this blog post, I share the approach I took to build responsive, client-friendly emails without a single 
 tag.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extended NFPA Hazard Diamond]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2638/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2638/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/extended_nfpa_hazard_diamond.png" title="With most labs, the hushed horror stories are about something like dimethylmercury or prions, but occasionally you'll get a weird lab where it's about the soda machine or the drop ceiling." alt="With most labs, the hushed horror stories are about something like dimethylmercury or prions, but occasionally you'll get a weird lab where it's about the soda machine or the drop ceiling." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 25 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3813</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/25/roe-v-wade-v-abortion/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-25T15:58:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The oligarchs' Supreme Court: Getting turkeys to vote for Christmas ain't cheap. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The oligarchs' Supreme Court (permalink) Here's something weird: in the wake of Roe v Wade in the 1970s, the Southern Baptist Convention repeatedly passed resolutions affirming the right to abortion and rejecting government interference in the decision to bear a child to term: https://text.npr.org/734303135 Back then, white evangelicals were deeply suspicious of people who opposed abortion. Getting too worked up about the issue was a sign of crypto-papacy, and back then, white evangelicals hated Catholics: …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roman Numerals]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2637/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2637/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/roman_numerals.png" title="100he100k out th1s 1nno5at4e str1ng en100o501ng 15e been 500e5e50op1ng! 1t's 6rtua100y perfe100t! ...hang on, what's a &quot;virtuacy&quot;?" alt="100he100k out th1s 1nno5at4e str1ng en100o501ng 15e been 500e5e50op1ng! 1t's 6rtua100y perfe100t! ...hang on, what's a &quot;virtuacy&quot;?" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BlueSuburbia Progress Update (screenshots of what I’m working on)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5424</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/bluesuburbia-progress-update-screenshots-of-what-im-working-on"/>
        <updated>2022-06-23T23:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you probably know from following me on either Mastodon or Twitter, I’ve been working hard on my next “game” (the appropriate label for it is still undecided)… built in UE5. This post is an excuse to share a bunch of screenshots! There have been points where I wasn’t sure if what I was making would even run on any other computer, but I tested it today on my work laptop… omg it runs! Smoothly too! When I started I didn’t completely understand performance, or settings, or all the fancy things Unreal lets you do with optimization… so it was...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 23 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3806</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/23/peek-a-boo/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-23T16:08:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Daycare apps are insecure surveillance dumpster-fires: Apps are like software, only worse. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Daycare apps are insecure surveillance dumpster-fires (permalink) When my EFF colleague Alexis Hancock signed her baby up for daycare, she was told that she had to download a childcare management app – to monitor and specify "feedings, diaper changes, pictures, activities, and which guardian picked-up/dropped-off the child." https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2022/06/daycare-apps-are-dangerously-insecure This was during the lockdown, and the app was a way to comply with social distancing and contact tracing …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Missy [blog]]]></title>
        <id>missy</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/06/22/missy"/>
        <updated>2022-06-22T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We've had Missy for 17 years, she was part of a litter that her brothers Dizzy and Ninja came from.
She died early this morning at home. Thankfully it was quick for her. There's been a lot of tears today from all of us, and I know I'll miss her dearly, she was a great friend.
I wanted to use my blog to remember some of what made her special to me.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What If? 2 Countdown]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2636/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2636/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/what_if_2_countdown.png" title="If you don't end the 99 Bottles of Beer recursion at N=0 it just becomes The Other Song That Never Ends." alt="If you don't end the 99 Bottles of Beer recursion at N=0 it just becomes The Other Song That Never Ends." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 21 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3799</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/21/early-adopters/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-21T17:46:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The sex industry isn't technophilic: Why sex workers are the first in – and first out – of new technologies. Schroedinger's streaming service just died: When is a "sale" a "license?" Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The sex industry isn't technophilic (permalink) The sex industry has pioneered every new communications tool since the printing press: in my own lifetime, I've watched it take the lead in VCRs, desktop publishing, BBSes, digital text, digital images, digital videos, live streaming services, cryptocurrency, and VR. It would be easy to conclude that being interested in sex is somehow correlated with being fas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joey Amato, Publisher of Pride Journeys, Shares What Brings Him Joy Online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69339</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/internet-culture/joey-amato-publisher-of-pride-journeys-shares-what-brings-him-joy-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-21T16:55:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Joey Amato, Publisher of Pride Journeys, Shares What Brings Him Joy Online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joey Amato, Publisher of Pride Journeys, Shares What Brings Him Joy Online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69339</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/joey-amato-publisher-of-pride-journeys-shares-what-brings-him-joy-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-21T16:55:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Joey Amato, Publisher of Pride Journeys, Shares What Brings Him Joy Online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on 10 years of time well spent with Pocket]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69308</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/products/pocket/reflecting-on-10-years-of-time-well-spent-with-pocket/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-21T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ten years ago, a small, yet mighty team launched Pocket because we felt that people deserved a better way to consume content on the internet. We wanted it to be easy — “as simple an action as putting it in your pocket” — and empowering, giving people the means to engage with the web on […]
The post Reflecting on 10 years of time well spent with Pocket appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Apple’s Private Click Measurement]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69335</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/mozilla/understanding-apples-private-click-measurement/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-21T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Private advertising technology proposals could greatly improve privacy for web users. Web advertising has a reputation for poor privacy practices. Firefox, other browsers, and the web community are collaborating on finding ways to support advertising while maintaining strong, technical privacy protections for users. This series of posts aims to contribute to the ongoing conversation regarding […]
The post Understanding Apple’s Private Click Measurement appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Thomson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on 10 years of time well spent with Pocket]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69308</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/pocket/reflecting-on-10-years-of-time-well-spent-with-pocket/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-21T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ten years ago, a small, yet mighty team launched Pocket because we felt that people deserved a better way to consume content on the internet. We wanted it to be easy — “as simple an action as putting it in your pocket” — and empowering, giving people the means to engage with the web on […]
The post Reflecting on 10 years of time well spent with Pocket appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Apple’s Private Click Measurement]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69335</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/understanding-apples-private-click-measurement/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-21T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Private advertising technology proposals could greatly improve privacy for web users. Web advertising has a reputation for poor privacy practices. Firefox, other browsers, and the web community are collaborating on finding ways to support advertising while maintaining strong, technical privacy protections for users. This series of posts aims to contribute to the ongoing conversation regarding […]
The post Understanding Apple’s Private Click Measurement appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Thomson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One line of CSS to add basic dark/light mode]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7268</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/06/20/one-line-of-css-to-add-basic-dark-light-mode/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-20T22:33:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you have your OS set up in dark mode seeing bright form elements is grating. By starting your style sheet with a single line of CSS, you can make sure that people using dark mode get dark form elements and backgrounds and those using light mode, light ones. You can see it in this […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superintelligent AIs]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2635/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2635/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/superintelligent_ais.png" title="Your scientists were so preoccupied with whether or not they should, they didn't stop to think if they could." alt="Your scientists were so preoccupied with whether or not they should, they didn't stop to think if they could." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Queer Singer/Songwriter Criibaby Finds Pride and Joy at the Intersection of Tech and Music]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69152</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/internet-culture/queer-singer-songwriter-criibaby-finds-pride-and-joy-at-the-intersection-of-tech-and-music/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-17T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Queer Singer/Songwriter Criibaby Finds Pride and Joy at the Intersection of Tech and Music appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Queer Singer/Songwriter Criibaby Finds Pride and Joy at the Intersection of Tech and Music]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69152</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/queer-singer-songwriter-criibaby-finds-pride-and-joy-at-the-intersection-of-tech-and-music/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-17T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Queer Singer/Songwriter Criibaby Finds Pride and Joy at the Intersection of Tech and Music appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Presents: Redefining love and identity, one viral video at a time]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69247</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/products/firefox/brandon-kyle-goodman-big-mouth-messy-mondays-online-community/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-17T13:15:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Monday and Thursday, queer comedy writer and actor Brandon Kyle Goodman asks their 176,000 Instagram followers to tell them something good or messy.  People who tune into the Instagram Stories series, called “Messy Mondays” and “Thot Thursdays,” send in submissions that are indeed good, messy or both. Some share their kinks. Others inquire about […]
The post Firefox Presents: Redefining love and identity, one viral video at a time appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Presents: Redefining love and identity, one viral video at a time]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69247</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/brandon-kyle-goodman-big-mouth-messy-mondays-online-community/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-17T13:15:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Monday and Thursday, queer comedy writer and actor Brandon Kyle Goodman asks their 176,000 Instagram followers to tell them something good or messy.  People who tune into the Instagram Stories series, called “Messy Mondays” and “Thot Thursdays,” send in submissions that are indeed good, messy or both. Some share their kinks. Others inquire about […]
The post Firefox Presents: Redefining love and identity, one viral video at a time appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3788</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/17/no-gods-no-masters/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-17T08:55:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Facebook's right, Apple is too powerful: And so is Facebook. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Facebook's right, Apple is too powerful (permalink) On the one hand, Facebook's comments to the NTIA on Apple's market power are supremely ironic. Facebook, complaining about excessive market power? https://downloads.regulations.gov/NTIA-2022-0001-0145/attachment_1.pdf Even worse is what Facebook is complaining about: Apple's App Tracking Transparency update to Ios devices like the Iphone, which allowed users to comprehensively and easily block all the apps on their phones from spying on them. When Apple gave users this choice, nearly all of them chose privacy. https…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Line Through HTTPS]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2634/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2634/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/red_line_through_https.png" title="Some organization has been paying to keep this up and it hasn't been removed from search results. Seems like two votes of confidence to me." alt="Some organization has been paying to keep this up and it hasn't been removed from search results. Seems like two votes of confidence to me." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kids are growing up in a very online world. What’s a concerned parent to do?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69106</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/internet-culture/kids-mental-health-screen-time-technology/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-16T18:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technology is easy to blame for the mental health crisis that kids are facing. But according to experts, it’s not that simple.  A rare public advisory from the U.S. surgeon general in December 2021 warned that young people are facing unprecedented challenges that have had a “devastating” effect on their mental health. These difficulties were […]
The post Kids are growing up in a very online world. What’s a concerned parent to do? appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kids are growing up in a very online world. What’s a concerned parent to do?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69106</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/kids-mental-health-screen-time-technology/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-16T18:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technology is easy to blame for the mental health crisis that kids are facing. But according to experts, it’s not that simple.  A rare public advisory from the U.S. surgeon general in December 2021 warned that young people are facing unprecedented challenges that have had a “devastating” effect on their mental health. These difficulties were […]
The post Kids are growing up in a very online world. What’s a concerned parent to do? appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-June Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42723</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/06/15/mid-june-link-assortment-7/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-15T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events Games may be submitted for ParserComp, a jam for parser-based interactive fiction, through June 30; then there will be a judging window July 1 – July 31, where players can try all the games and weigh in on their favourites. July 2, the San Francisco Bay IF Meetup gets together. July 10, 2-4 PM … Continue reading "Mid-June Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to easily switch from Chrome to Firefox]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69205</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/products/firefox/how-to-switch-from-chrome-to-firefox/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-15T13:47:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s never been a better time to switch from Chrome to Firefox, if we do say so ourselves.  Some of the internet’s most popular ad blockers, such as uBlock Origin — tools that save our digital sanity from video ads that auto-play, banners that take up half the screen and pop-up windows with infuriatingly tiny […]
The post How to easily switch from Chrome to Firefox appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to easily switch from Chrome to Firefox]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69205</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/how-to-switch-from-chrome-to-firefox/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-15T13:47:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s never been a better time to switch from Chrome to Firefox, if we do say so ourselves.  Some of the internet’s most popular ad blockers, such as uBlock Origin — tools that save our digital sanity from video ads that auto-play, banners that take up half the screen and pop-up windows with infuriatingly tiny […]
The post How to easily switch from Chrome to Firefox appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 15 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3771</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/15/simple-as-abc/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-15T07:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Boy, gig companies sure hire disastrously sloppy lawyers: $100m flushed down the drain in Massachusetts. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Boy, gig companies sure hire disastrously sloppy lawyers (permalink) In the run-up to the 2020 election, "gig work" companies, led by Uber and Lyft, firehosed $225m to back the passage of Proposition 22, a law that would permanently allow them to misclassify employees as contractors, not entitled to benefits or workplace protections. More than a decade after Citizen United – the Supreme Court ruling that paved the way for unlimited dark money in US election spending – it's sometimes …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Astronomer Hotline]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2633/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2633/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/astronomer_hotline.png" title="Employment statistics have to correct for the fact that the Weird Bug Hotline hires on a bunch of extra temporary staff every 17 years." alt="Employment statistics have to correct for the fact that the Weird Bug Hotline hires on a bunch of extra temporary staff every 17 years." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to set Firefox as your default browser on Windows]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.mozilla.org/foxtail/2020/01/20/how-to-set-firefox-as-your-default-browser-on-windows/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/products/firefox/how-to-set-firefox-as-your-default-browser-on-windows/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-14T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During a software update, your settings can sometimes change or revert back to their original state. For example, if your computer has multiple browsers installed, you may end up with a different default browser than Firefox. That’s easy to fix so that Firefox is there for you when you expect it, like when you click […]
The post How to set Firefox as your default browser on Windows appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M.J. Kelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to set Firefox as your default browser on Windows]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.mozilla.org/foxtail/2020/01/20/how-to-set-firefox-as-your-default-browser-on-windows/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/how-to-set-firefox-as-your-default-browser-on-windows/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-14T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During a software update, your settings can sometimes change or revert back to their original state. For example, if your computer has multiple browsers installed, you may end up with a different default browser than Firefox. That’s easy to fix so that Firefox is there for you when you expect it, like when you click […]
The post How to set Firefox as your default browser on Windows appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M.J. Kelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox rolls out Total Cookie Protection by default to all users worldwide]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69120</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/firefox-rolls-out-total-cookie-protection-by-default-to-all-users-worldwide/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-14T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Take back your privacy Starting today, Firefox is rolling out Total Cookie Protection by default to all Firefox users worldwide, making Firefox the most private and secure major browser available across Windows, Mac and Linux. Total Cookie Protection is Firefox’s strongest privacy protection to date, confining cookies to the site where they were created, thus […]
The post Firefox rolls out Total Cookie Protection by default to all users worldwide appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calling for Antitrust Reform]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69126</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/calling-for-antitrust-reform/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla supports the American Innovation and Choice Online Act (AICOA). The time for change is now. It’s time for governments to address the reality that five tech companies—not everyday consumers—control our online experiences today. Updated competition laws are essential for the internet to be private, secure, interoperable, open, accessible, transparent, and a balance between commercial […]
The post Calling for Antitrust Reform appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Urmika Devi Shah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 14 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3766</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/14/this-way-to-the-egress/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-14T09:41:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Adventure Capitalism: A history of "Libertarian Exit" movements. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Adventure Capitalism (permalink) The 17th century philosopher John Locke is a key grifter thinkfluencer, and his "labor theory of property" is key to understanding the libertarian mind-palace. https://locusmag.com/2019/03/cory-doctorow-terra-nullius/ Locke says that property arises when the empty, unimproved natural places are mixed with human labor. You own your body, so you own its labor and the fruits of its labor. No one owns an empty place, so when you influse your body's labor into a place, it becomes yours. There's only one teensy problem with this: there are no…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CEO and Founder of HER Robyn Exton Shares Celebrates Pride from Her Corner of the Internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69108</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/ceo-and-founder-of-her-robyn-exton-shares-celebrates-pride-from-her-corner-of-the-internet/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-13T17:42:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post CEO and Founder of HER Robyn Exton Shares Celebrates Pride from Her Corner of the Internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 13 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3761</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/13/public-choice/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-13T12:40:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Regulatory Capture": My column about the difference between a left and a right theory of sound regulation. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2012, 2017. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Regulatory Capture" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my Medium column, "Regulatory Capture: Beyond Revolving Doors and Against Regulatory Nihilism," about the left/right split on theories of sound regulation: https://doctorow.medium.com/regulatory-capture-59b2013e2526 If you'd like an essay-formatted version of this thread to read or share, here's a link to it on pluralistic.net, my surveillance-free, ad-free, tracker-free blog: https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/13/…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One decade waiting for web APIs [blog]]]></title>
        <id>one-decade-waiting-for-web-apis</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/06/13/one-decade-waiting-for-web-apis"/>
        <updated>2022-06-13T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the last couple of years (rather slowed by the pandemic), a number of new browser APIs have started to land that I had wanted over a decade ago. That's not to say that the process is slow, more that the technology simply didn't exist a 10 years ago, and now the APIs exist, it took me a matter of hours to build the small bit of software I so desperately needed back then.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greatest Scientist]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2632/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2632/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/greatest_scientist.png" title="&quot;Ow! One of the petri dishes I left on the tower railing fell and hit me on the head! Hey, that gives me an idea...&quot;" alt="&quot;Ow! One of the petri dishes I left on the tower railing fell and hit me on the head! Hey, that gives me an idea...&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 12 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3758</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/12/hot-coffee/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-12T15:05:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Geico STD story is the new McDonald's Hot Coffee story: The real story is binding arbitration. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Geico STD story is the new McDonald's Hot Coffee story (permalink) Here's a media literacy rule of thumb: any time you hear about how the courts have done something outrageous and absurd to some poor, long-suffering, gigantic, wildly profitable corporation…dig deeper. The canonical example is the "McDonald's Hot Coffee Lawsuit" (aka Liebeck v. McDonald's Restaurants). You know, that time that an old lady got burned by her McDonald's coffee and then sued for for $2.7 million?! Most peop…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 10 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3753</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/10/loopers/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-10T17:57:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Monopolists want to create human inkjet printers: The war on your pancreas continues. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Monopolists want to create human inkjet printers (permalink) Even if you don't have diabetes, you can't have missed that there's something really terrible going on with how Americans with diabetes control their illness. Insulin – a century-old drug whose inventors refused any patents – has experienced double-digit, year-on-year price hikes (1123% between 2009-2017 alone!): https://www.nbcnews.com/business/consumer/desperate-families-driven-black-market-insulin-n730026 Moreover, this is a uniquely American circumst…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tony-nominated Arnulfo Maldonado Shares Pride and Joy From His Corner of the Internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69090</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/tony-nominated-arnulfo-maldonado-shares-pride-and-joy-from-his-corner-of-the-internet/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-10T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Tony-nominated Arnulfo Maldonado Shares Pride and Joy From His Corner of the Internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exercise Progression]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2631/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2631/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/exercise_progression.png" title="They said after I got into a routine, I'd enjoy getting progressively stronger and stop whining so much about how hard exercise was. Well, they were half right!" alt="They said after I got into a routine, I'd enjoy getting progressively stronger and stop whining so much about how hard exercise was. Well, they were half right!" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile-First CSS: Is It Time for a Rethink?]]></title>
        <id>https://alistapart.com/article/mobile-first-css-is-it-time-for-a-rethink/</id>
        <link href="https://alistapart.com/article/mobile-first-css-is-it-time-for-a-rethink/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-09T02:13:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The mobile-first design methodology is great—it focuses on what really matters to the user, it’s well-practiced, and it’s been a common design pattern for years. So developing your CSS mobile-first should also be great, too…right? 
Well, not necessarily. Classic mobile-first CSS development is based on the principle of overwriting style declarations: you begin your CSS with default style declarations, and overwrite and/or add new styles as you add breakpoints with min-width media queries for larger viewports (for a good overview see “What is Mobile First CSS and Why Does It Rock?”). But all those exceptions create complexity and inefficiency, which in turn can lead to an increased testing effort and a code base that’s harder to maintain. Admit it—how many of us willingly want that?
On your…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>by</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3744</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/08/chair-ish/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-08T15:16:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Powered wheelchairs and Right to Repair: An unprecedented legislative victory in Colorado. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Powered wheelchairs and Right to Repair (permalink) Here's a miserable story with a mostly happy ending, one that leaves us with work to do, sure, but also with clarity on what to do next and how to do it. It's about Colorado's HB22-1031, "Consumer Right To Repair Powered Wheelchairs," which Governor Jared Polis signed into law last week: https://leg.colorado.gov/bills/hb22-1031#:~:text=Concerning%20a%20requirement%20that%20a,repair%20the%20manufacturer%27s%20powered%20wheelchairs Three million American…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shuttle Skeleton]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2630/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2630/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/shuttle_skeleton.png" title="It's believed to be related to the Stellar Sea Cow." alt="It's believed to be related to the Stellar Sea Cow." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot explaining code and translating it from one language to another]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7265</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/06/07/github-copilot-explaining-code-and-translating-it-from-one-language-to-another/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T20:57:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot is already the dog’s bollocks, but I just installed the GitHub Labs extension and my jaw is still open. Code explanation This one allows you to highlight a piece of code and get explanations of what it does: For example: async function downloadZipFile(downloadUrl) { await fs.remove(‘out/edge’); const file = fs.createWriteStream(‘edge.zip’); https.get(downloadUrl, function(response) { […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3736</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/07/more-than-human/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T16:26:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links James Bridle's "Ways of Being": Dispatches from the more than human world. Fake Christian health insurance and other big cons: If you have to trick people into hearing your message, you are in a cult. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading James Bridle's "Ways of Being" (permalink) It's hard to pin down the thesis of James Bridle's Ways of Being, published today in the USA by Farrar, Strauss, Giroux – it's a big, lyrical, strange and inspiring book about the "more than human world" – a world that encompasses the worldview of animals, ecosystems, and software. https://us.macmillan.com/books/9780374601119/waysofbeing Bridle, an Engl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 06 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3732</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/06/fortress-mentality/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T16:35:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Against Cozy Catastrophes": My Medium column about the failure of market-based pensions. MBAs and wage stagnation: Going to business school makes you a dick. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Against Cozy Catastrophes" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my recent Medium column, "Against Cozy Catastrophies: Cowering in a luxury bunker is a lousy retirement plan." It's a column about the failure of a market-based, individual based approach to the collective problem of retirement savings. https://doctorow.medium.com/against-cozy-catastrophies-7ac0a62f0922 One of the major contributors to the national wealth of the world's "advanced econ…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Or Whatever]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2629/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2629/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/or_whatever.png" title="Oh yeah, I didn't even know they renamed it the Willis Tower in 2009, because I know a normal amount about skyscrapers." alt="Oh yeah, I didn't even know they renamed it the Willis Tower in 2009, because I know a normal amount about skyscrapers." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3726</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/05/heavenly-nostrils/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T15:20:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Big Box of Sparkly Unicorn Magic: If Hobbes was a snarky unicorn and Calvin was an awesome little girl. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Big Box of Sparkly Unicorn Magic (permalink) Back in 2015, when my daughter Poesy was seven, I read her a story every night at bedtime. It was a glorious time, not just for our father-daughter relationship, but for my own relationship with kids' literature, which is a spectacular and rich part of the publishing world that grownups frequently have no contact with. One of the great successes of our bedtime story ritual was our discovery of Dana Simpson's "Phoebe and Her Unicorn" comic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trevor Project’s Kevin Wong Shares What’s In His Corner of the Internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69069</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/trevor-projects-kevin-wong-shares-whats-in-his-corner-of-the-internet/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T19:55:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Trevor Project’s Kevin Wong Shares What’s In His Corner of the Internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trevor Project’s Kevin Wong Shares What’s In His Corner of the Internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69069</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/pride-month/trevor-projects-kevin-wong-shares-whats-in-his-corner-of-the-internet/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T19:55:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Trevor Project’s Kevin Wong Shares What’s In His Corner of the Internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3714</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/03/gambling-home/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T17:54:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links House sales are cratering but inventory is soaring: You are the sucker at the table. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading House sales are cratering but inventory is soaring (permalink) When I moved to the UK in the early 2000s, nearly everyone I met fancied themselves a real-estate investment genius. Young people all had plans to "get on the housing ladder." Each of these schemes was more crackpot than the last – the most plausible involved buying minuscule flats, "doing them up," and flipping them. The weirder ones involved buying unbuilt holiday homes in Spain or Croatia – places these people couldn't afford to visit, es…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Motion Blur]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2628/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2628/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/motion_blur.png" title="I can't speak for your other subjects, but MY motion was as smooth and natural as the framerate allowed." alt="I can't speak for your other subjects, but MY motion was as smooth and natural as the framerate allowed." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Jun 2022 (supplemental)]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3720</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/02/residential-casino/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T18:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NB: This duplicate post exists solely to correct a broken Twitter link Today's links House sales are cratering but inventory is soaring: You are the sucker at the table. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading House sales are cratering but inventory is soaring (permalink) When I moved to the UK in the early 2000s, nearly everyone I met fancied themselves a real-estate investment genius. Young people all had plans to "get on the housing ladder." Each of these schemes was more crackpot than the last – the most plausible involved buying minuscule flats, "doing them up," and flipping them. The weirder ones involved buying unbuilt holiday homes…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social media’s ‘Doomscrolling Reminder Lady’ on her favorite corners of the internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69042</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/karen-ho-twitter-doomscrolling-reminder-lady/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T15:55:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Social media’s ‘Doomscrolling Reminder Lady’ on her favorite corners of the internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social media’s ‘Doomscrolling Reminder Lady’ on her favorite corners of the internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69042</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/interviews/karen-ho-twitter-doomscrolling-reminder-lady/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T15:55:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Social media’s ‘Doomscrolling Reminder Lady’ on her favorite corners of the internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla releases local machine translation tools as part of Project Bergamot]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69082</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/local-translation-add-on-project-bergamot/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T15:23:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In January of 2019, Mozilla joined the University of Edinburgh, Charles University, University of Sheffield and University of Tartu as part of a project funded by the European Union called Project Bergamot. The ultimate goal of this consortium was to build a set of neural machine translation tools that would enable Mozilla to develop a […]
The post Mozilla releases local machine translation tools as part of Project Bergamot appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3702</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/01/factories-to-condos-pipeline/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T16:16:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Inflation is caused by too little capacity: Not too much money. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Inflation is caused by too little capacity (permalink) Inflation is here, and there are a lot of explanations for it. People who worry about the monetary supply – especially people in the deflation-loving cryptocurrency world – blame it on excessive money creation during the pandemic and uppity workers demanding higher wages: https://www.businessinsider.com/elon-musk-remote-work-makes-you-less-productive-wrong-2022-6 Anti-monopolists blame inflation on price-gouging. This is a persuasive argument. After all, CEOs of compani…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Abusing you was by the book” (documenting two years of abuse from Game Journalism, after sharing my #metoo… the whole painful story all in one place)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5386</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/abusing-you-was-by-the-book-documenting-two-years-of-abuse-from-game-journalism-after-sharing-my-metoo-the-whole-painful-story-all-in-one-place"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T08:09:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been about a full year since the Kotaku article that exploited my sexual assault, and exploited the other victims of my rapist, has been removed. A full year since I had to argue with journalists for my life, and trying to show them the extent of the harm this has caused. I am told that what I achieved was “unprecedented” (I hate that word). That articles don’t get removed without lawyers, this, that, or the other fancy thing only rich or powerful people have. Nevertheless, I don’t feel victorious. I feel burned out, abused, laughed at, and alienated....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for May]]></title>
        <id>log.html#may2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#may2022"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of May. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Combinatory Logic, wrote a guide to combinatory logic, using talking birds.
, released a linter, and optimized uxnasm.
Dexe, released an updated version.
100r.co, added batteries, and regulator.
News
From this month until next October, our updates may be delayed. We are sailing northward, towards Desolation Sound and the Broughtons, where cell towers are few. We will wander in and out of such regions all summer. So far, we sailed up to the Gulf Islands, and over to Nanaimo from Victoria, and then crossed the Strait of Georgia over to the Sunshine Coast(close-reaching in 20-knot winds). This was a good shakedown for Pino, a good way to re-awaken our little vessel. All went well, but we ought to have secured our produce better... some of our potatoes escaped their nest and went out for an afternoon roll around the cabin floor.
Start of May, we had some issues with our batteries. They've been acting out for some time, we think because of a dead cell. We have been operating at half battery capacity for a month, and realized that yet again we don't need that much power, especially in the summer when the days are long.
The combinatory logic guide is the first of many projects we plan to release this summer. We also released an sign language version of Uxntal.
In other news, a version of Collapse OS was ported to Uxn.
Pino book club
We're reading Watership Down by Richard Adams.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Types of Scopes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2627/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2627/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/types_of_scopes.png" title="An x-ray gyroscope is used to determine exactly which toppings they included in the pita." alt="An x-ray gyroscope is used to determine exactly which toppings they included in the pita." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of May Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42708</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/05/31/end-of-may-link-assortment-8/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T17:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events June 4 is the next meeting of the SF Bay IF Meetup. June 5 is the next meeting of the Seattle IF group, 2-4 PM PDT. Narrascope registrations are now open for July 30-31: the event is low-cost and remote, and features speakers on many aspects of interactive narrative. Releases Hannah Nicklin’s Writing for … Continue reading "End of May Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marketing our privacy products while preserving privacy]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69067</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/mozilla-vpn/marketing-our-privacy-products-while-preserving-privacy/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T16:22:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When we launched Mozilla VPN, a fast and easy-to-use VPN, it was in a market crowded by companies making promises about privacy and security and we believed our reputation for building products that help you keep your information safe would make our product stand-out. To date, tens of thousands of people have signed up to […]
The post Marketing our privacy products while preserving privacy  appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenifer Boscacci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 31 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3697</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/31/dealers-choice/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T15:10:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How John Deere leverages repair-blocking into gag orders: A farmer's only local dealership refuses to fix his tractor because he advocates for Right to Repair. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How John Deere leverages repair-blocking into gag orders (permalink) John Deere is justifiably notorious for its campaign to block farmers from fixing their own agricultural equipment. The company is #RightToRepair's archnemesis, and no amount of misleading feel-good stories about how it keeps its heavy hand on farmers' tractors forever can change that. https://doctorow.medium.com/about-those-kill-switched-ukrainian-tractors-bc93f471b9c8 The…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do we have a lack of developers or a false assumption what the job is?]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7259</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/31/do-we-have-a-lack-of-developers-or-a-false-assumption-what-the-job-is/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T10:03:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week I was at build Europe and talked to a lot of people about the developer market. The general consensus was that there is a huge lack of developers to hire. That there is not enough talent. When I poked further and asked about how people assess talent, it boiled down to people having […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3692</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/30/80-lbs/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T19:18:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Apple's Cement Overshoes": Thinking different about right to repair. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Apple's Cement Overshoes" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my recent Medium column, "Apple's Cement Overshoes," about the incredible, cynical fuckery that Apple engages in to sabotage right to repair and ensure that its devices end up in overseas e-waste landfills rather than being fixed and kept in service. https://doctorow.medium.com/apples-cement-overshoes-329856288d13 For all the debate around Right to Repair, it's amazing how simple the actual issue is. On the anti- side, you have comp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[d65536]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2626/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2626/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/d65536.png" title="They're robust against quantum attacks because it's hard to make a quantum system that large." alt="They're robust against quantum attacks because it's hard to make a quantum system that large." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3684</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/27/voluntary-carbon-market/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T16:35:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Wework founder raises $70m for blockchain-based, "voluntary" carbon credits: It's a scam matrioshka. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: None Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Wework founder raises $70m for blockchain-based, "voluntary" carbon credits (permalink) Even crypto's biggest boosters admit that the industry has a scam problem. This is especially hard to deny now that hundred of billions of (real) dollars' worth of (fake) "stablecoins" have gone up in smoke. Crypto apologists will tell you that there are scams everywhere, and they're not wrong. The productive economy has been systematic dismantled and replaced with financialized grifts: private equity, REITs, SPACs, MLMs, ad…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What people think that web developers do vs. what we really do]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7256</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/27/what-people-think-that-web-developers-do-vs-what-we-really-do/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T09:09:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What people think web developers do: Code, deploy and use, with coding being the main task What web developers really do: Coding Require random 3rd party framework code Updating Node/NPM Try the last command again with `sudo` Checking on mobile Shaking fist towards Cupertino Looking things up on the web Pasting Stack Overflow solutions Resize […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Field Topology]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2625/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2625/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/field_topology.png" title="The combination croquet set/10-lane pool can also be used for some varieties of foosball and Skee-Ball." alt="The combination croquet set/10-lane pool can also be used for some varieties of foosball and Skee-Ball." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 26 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3680</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/26/initialization-bias/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T10:41:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Attacking machine learning training by re-ordering data: Boy it's hard to audit an AI. This day in history: 2012, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Attacking machine learning training by re-ordering data (permalink) We have increasingly outsourced our decision-making to machine learning models ("the algorithm"). The whole point of building recommendation, sorting, and "decision support" systems on ML is to undertake assessments at superhuman speed and scale, which means that the idea of a "human in the loop" who validates machine judgment is a mere figleaf, and it only gets worse from here. There are real consequences to this. I mean, for starters, if you get killed by a US military drone, chances are th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A teleprompter script for video recordings]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7253</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/25/a-teleprompter-script-for-video-recordings/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T21:03:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Currently I am recording a lot of videos and I found the fastest way to do them is to write the script and read it out to my camera and then record screencasts and edit them to fit the narration. In order to make sure I read from the top of the screen and reading […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 25 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3667</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/25/the-wild-places/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T11:56:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Talking with Kim Stanley Robinson about "The High Sierra": An interview for Fatherly Magazine. Kim Stanley Robinson's "The High Sierra": A love story. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Talking with Kim Stanley Robinson about "The High Sierra" (permalink) This month, the great Kim Stanley Robinson published "The High Sierra," an odd combination of memoir, natural history, mountaineering guidebook, and environmental manifesto. At one point, Robinson told me it would be his last book. Thankfully, he changed his mind, but I can see why he'd think of this as a career capstone. https://www.littlebrown.com/titles/kim-stanley-robinso…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Return to Monkey Island Dev Diary]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/dev_diary</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/dev_diary"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jul 17, 2020
First official day is Monday but I've started setting up Slack and other web services.
Jul 18, 2020
Ordered Linux machine. Talked to Dave about maybe controlling Elaine for a section of the game.  
Starting to worry about finding great people. It's going to be hard because we have to keep the project a secret.
Played MI1 again. Taking a lot of notes about what made MI MI.  After TWP and fast walk and other almost invisible improvements, it's painful to play a 35 year-old adventure game.
I was surprised at how many objects didn't have custom default responses. A large number of objects just said "That doesn't seem to work."
Jul 19, 2020
Played MI again.
Jul 20, 2020
Working with the lawyer to get contractor contracts done that conform to Disney's requirements. Taking longer than I thought.
Hope to get Dave's contract done by tomorrow.
Jul 23, 2020
First "real" design meeting with dave.  Laying down the backbone puzzles for Act 1.
Jul 24, 2020
Started the Puzzle Dependency Chart for Act 1.
Jul 27, 2020
Jenn started
Jul 28, 2020
Making good progress on design.  I know we'll slow down when we have to do all the details.  Looking forward to getting a concept artist.  Things come alive for me when concepts start to come in.
Nov 17, 2020
Starting up diary again... maybe I'll be able to keep it going this time.
Thinking about the ui. I hate the current status-quo.
Nov 18, 2020
Meeting with Disney.
May 25, 2022
Yep, this dev diary didn't last long.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voyager Wires]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2624/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2624/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/voyager_wires.png" title="Also, they're getting increasingly worried that someone will accidentally hit the 'retract' button, and that the end of the cable thrashing around as it winds up could devastate the Earth's surface." alt="Also, they're getting increasingly worried that someone will accidentally hit the 'retract' button, and that the end of the cable thrashing around as it winds up could devastate the Earth's surface." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 24 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3661</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/24/moral-money/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T14:24:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links HSBC: "Who cares if Miami is underwater?": Scenes from the "Moral Money Summit." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading HSBC: "Who cares if Miami is underwater?" (permalink) Before I tell you about how HSBC just announced it wants to literally render the planet Earth unfit for human habitation, I want to talk about HSBC's other crimes. Remember the LIBOR scandal? HSBC was neck-deep in it, costing the world's public coffers trillions through fraud? https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-05-23/banks-are-ordered-by-court-to-defend-libor-antitrust-lawsuit HSBC used laundered money from the world's most corrupt people to cash out on it…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 23 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3656</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/23/you-got-spacced/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T15:50:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links SPACs were hugely successful (for banks): But you lost your shirt. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading SPACs were hugely successful (for banks) (permalink) Remember SPACs? For a while, you couldn't turn around without hearing about a celeb who was backing a "blank check" IPO. It was confusing, because SPACs don't make any sense: you buy into a company at $10/share. The company has no business, no products, nothing. But it plans on going public, and then buying another company. In theory, you're betting that some celebrity-endorsed randos will take all the $10 share buy-ins and use the money to buy another company – a comp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goofs]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2623/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2623/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/goofs.png" title="The film is set in 2018, but when Commander Bremberly chases the hologram through Times Square, there's a billboard for Avengers: Age of Ultron. Depending on the date, that billboard would have been advertising either Infinity War or this movie." alt="The film is set in 2018, but when Commander Bremberly chases the hologram through Times Square, there's a billboard for Avengers: Age of Ultron. Depending on the date, that billboard would have been advertising either Infinity War or this movie." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 20 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3652</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/20/self-destruct-button/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T17:05:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "About Those Killswitched Ukrainian Tractors": Good spaceships don't have self-destruct buttons. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "About Those Killswitched Ukrainian Tractors" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my Medium column, "About Those Killswitched Ukrainian Tractors," in which I am a bit of a buzzkill about that feel-good story of a Ukrainian John Deere dealership bricking $5m worth of tractors stolen by Russian looters: https://doctorow.medium.com/about-those-kill-switched-ukrainian-tractors-bc93f471b9c8 In case you missed the underlying story, here's a quick recap. Russian looters, abetted by the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Presents: A YouTube creator blending femininity and engineering]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68990</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/xyla-foxlin-youtube-engineering/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T15:44:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being feminine and having technical skills are not mutually exclusive. This should be obvious, but Xyla Foxlin has had to work hard to prove femininity and engineering can go hand in hand. While in college, she started a YouTube channel called Beauty and the Bolt, where she co-produced tutorials on STEM topics like electronics, math […]
The post Firefox Presents: A YouTube creator blending femininity and engineering appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angular Diameter Turnaround]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2622/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2622/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/angular_diameter_turnaround.png" title="Thank you to Katie Mack for teaching me about this effect, and to Janelle Shane for describing redshifts as 'like galaxies sinking into a pool of dilute blood,' which is how I'll see them from now on." alt="Thank you to Katie Mack for teaching me about this effect, and to Janelle Shane for describing redshifts as 'like galaxies sinking into a pool of dilute blood,' which is how I'll see them from now on." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global Accessbility Awareness Day – Does your web product support the needs of the many?]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7249</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/19/global-accessbility-awareness-day-does-your-web-product-support-the-needs-of-the-many/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T17:07:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You never create one product on the web – you create a product that people can change to their needs. At least you should. I’ve been working on the web since 1997 and one thing I realised early on is a big basic idea of the web: You do not control how your web product […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 19 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3641</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/19/the-weakest-link/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T16:13:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Your mom is a tech ninja: Your boss? Not so much. The impossible scam of US drug plans: Even the guy who invented them can't figure them out. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Your mom is a tech ninja (permalink) What makes someone "good at technology?" In part, it's an understanding of the underlying technical principles and industry conventions – what a "power on" icon looks like, say. I have a lot of that. But there's another component, one that's often invisible to people like me: the extent to which your technology was designed to suit your needs. I have a lot of that, too. I'm a 50 year old, middle-class, tech-ind…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 18 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3635</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/18/turfed/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T07:01:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A(nother) way in which Facebook is the 21st Century's tobacco industry: Millions for front groups who insist that only Mark Zuckerberg can save us from Xi Jinping. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A(nother) way in which Facebook is the 21st Century's tobacco industry (permalink) Have you noticed some extremely normal ads from extremely normal "grassroots activists" who are really, really worried that if we break up Facebook, China will destroy America and that is why Congress must absolutely stop trying to regulate America's tech giants, the bristling colossi that stand guard to defend us from the menace across the ocean? https://www.djournal.com/opinion/columnists…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mainly Known For]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2621/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2621/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/mainly_known_for.png" title="Oh sure, I know Keira Knightly, from the first movie in that series by The Land Before Time producer. You know, the franchise with the guy from Jurassic Park and Ghostwriter, and script work by Billie Lourd's mom?" alt="Oh sure, I know Keira Knightly, from the first movie in that series by The Land Before Time producer. You know, the franchise with the guy from Jurassic Park and Ghostwriter, and script work by Billie Lourd's mom?" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3621</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/17/dollars-for-docs/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T15:45:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How Big Pharma bribed docs to overprescribe opioids: Analysis from UCSF's "Opioid Industry Documents" repository. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How Big Pharma bribed docs to overprescribe opioids (permalink) I have complex chronic pain, and I've seen a lot of specialists. One of them prescribed long-term opioids for me. I dodged a bullet there, I think. Here's a little story about how hard it is to know whether to trust your doctor when you have a pain condition. One day, I was in a neurologist's office here in Burbank, waiting for a nerve timing study. I picked up the neurology journal on the waiting-room table and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing the accessibility of Inspection overlays]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7246</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/17/fixing-the-accessibility-of-inspection-overlays/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T14:56:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Inspect tool is a great way to get information about different page elements before selecting then. Once it is enabled, it shows an information overlay as you move from element to element. The main problem with the tool is that sometimes it is tough to get the information about the right element, as they […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Surprising Truth About Pixels and Accessibility]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/surprising-truth-about-pixels-and-accessibility/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/surprising-truth-about-pixels-and-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Should I use pixels or rems?”. In this comprehensive blog post, we'll answer this question once and for all. You'll learn about the accessibility implications, and how to determine the best unit to use in any scenario.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3617</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/16/through-the-meat-grinder/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T16:50:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Amy's Kitchen, a case-study in the problems with consumerism: You are not an ambulatory wallet. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Amy's Kitchen, a case-study in the problems with consumerism (permalink) As theories of change go, consumerism has a lot going for it. "Voting with your dollars" cuts out the middleman: rather than voting for a politician and hoping that they do the right thing, you can just reward good companies directly by buying their products (and punish bad companies by not buying their products). But voting with your dollars has some obvious deficits. The first one is that you can't shop your way out of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health Data]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2620/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2620/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/health_data.png" title="Donate now to help us find a cure for causality. No one should have to suffer through events because of other events." alt="Donate now to help us find a cure for causality. No one should have to suffer through events because of other events." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-May Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42646</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/05/15/mid-may-link-assortment-5/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-15T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events June 4 is the next meeting of the SF Bay IF Meetup.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discussing two "holy war" topics at the same time]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-17T23:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cutting to the chase: text editors *and* tabs vs. spaces!  Ooooh!


I've had this thing called "e" for a while now.  It's a stupid little 
script which serves to do a couple of things.  It starts my 
editor
with a given file, and it kicks it with the right arguments to make it 
disable line wrapping and to make the [TAB] key actually put in two 
spaces.


So, my dumb script would use "-w -E -T 2" most of the time, except when it 
was running on a Makefile, at which point it would skip those args.  
Simple enough, right?


pico is back?  Yes indeed, on Macs, as of 12.3, pico is in fact back.  To 
make sure I wasn't imagining things, I tracked down a machine that hadn't 
been upgraded yet and checked there.  Sure enough, it was in fact nano and 
not pico.


macOS 12.3 has nano as a symlink... pointing to pico!


At some point, I switched from literal tab characters in my source code to 
blobs of spaces, probably due to using that style at work and not hating 
it.  So, somewhere along the line I actually started depending on nano 
behavior without realizing it.


As for the lack of a feature in pico itself, it's kind of strange, really.  
If you go digging into the source, they have this random.c with a function 
called tab which claims to "simulate tab stop" using spaces.  That said, I 
can't find any place where it would be called with the magic values which 
would make it behave that way.


It wouldn't surprise me if this switch is just more of Apple removing 
GPLed things from their OS - pico seems to use the Apache license.  They 
dumped bash for zsh (MIT license) at some point (Big Sur, I think), and 
now this?  Okay then.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dumb things you can sometimes do with hard links]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-16T01:51:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a very old and stupid trick you could do with some filesystems in 
some situations back in the day... and might still be able to do in a 
few places today.


The problem is that while version X might eventually have an exploit, 
it'll get removed and it'll be replaced by version Y without that
particular hole.  By the time you get your hands on a tool to break into 
X, it'll be gone.


What you'd do is create a hard link pointing at the file you wanted to 
preserve, storing it in a spot which was writable by your account.  
Then, say, /usr/bin/sudo (because that never has security 
issues...) gets replaced at some point with a new file and you get to 
keep the old version.  When you get the tool to pop it, off you go!


Of course, these days, it's not quite so easy on the more modern systems 
you find.  Debian 11 here won't let me do it - it's EPERM city.  Rocky 8 
(so CentOS 8 and RHEL 8 too) also won't do it.  They both have some gunk
in /usr/lib/sysctl.d to lock this down.  But, my old Slackware 14.2 
install of my workstation let me do it the last time I tried about 
a year ago.  How about that, huh?  I bet it'd still work if I dug out 
the old drives and booted them up.


Incidentally, this is the magic sauce: /proc/sys/fs/protected_hardlinks
Read the man page for proc(5) to learn more about it.

here it is,
the thread I read a long time ago.  It's interesting to note that as far 
as I can tell, nothing actually changed upstream.  This left paranoid 
admins like me with no option but to use the (most excellent) Openwall 
patches to lock down this kind of stuff.  I used that on my machines at 
work which had non-staff users... just in case.


This whole situation is scary.  
Read more about it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More stories about stacks of modems]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-14T23:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in January, you might have seen my
post
about a very large BBS which seemed to solve for the problem of "how do 
we host a bunch of users" by having one physical box per user.  It might 
have been one physical box per *two* users, maybe, but it's hard to say.


Now, keep in mind digital cameras weren't easy to come by, so I have 
very few actual pictures.  I'll have to do a lot of explaining to make 
up for the lack of detail and alternate angles.  Clearly, I had no 
notion of ever using these pictures to tell stories 25+ years later.


Some friends at a local company had some bandwidth to spare (a T1 to 
Alternet somewhere, as I recall), so they parked a Zoom modem on one of 
their boxes and plugged it into a phone line.  We got an identical model 
to avoid cross-brand issues (Zoom m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking away the berries]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-13T02:14:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I sometimes write the beginnings of posts but don't post them.  I still 
save them in case conditions change or other things happen and make me 
want to follow up on the topic.  In this case, I wrote something about 
offices before the whole COVID lockdown thing happened and people 
largely stopped going to offices every day.  With that in mind, let's 
proceed.


However, tech companies decided to go past this at some point and 
brought about this whole notion of "microkitchens".  This is where 
they'd put their branding on the coolers (instead of "Coca-Cola" or 
"Pepsi") and would load it up with every kind of fizzy sugary liquid 
they could get their hands on.  They'd have racks and racks of shelving 
packed with all sorts of interesting crunchy, sugary and carb-loaded 
snacks.  They'd a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at the outlying data points]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T07:04:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the fun things I used to do at a prior job was to dig through the 
raw data points which were collected from the *many* servers we had.  I 
could just pick an interesting-sounding metric and then would just ask 
the system to show me the top 10 or bottom 10 out of a population of 
thousands or more.


To get my feet wet with the whole "investigations" thing that we'd do, I 
started looking into this one day and chose one of the many temp sensors 
which were being logged by the servers.  I forget exactly which one it 
was, for there were many.  The CPUs logged it, the chassis logged it, 
the power supply logged it, and so on.  There were so many choices.


I went looking for a reason.  What could possibly explain this?  First 
off, it didn't line up with any obvious pattern in the host names.  The 
hosts were named for whichever team owned them, followed by a sequence 
number that was bumped any time a new one was provisioned.  There was no 
signal to be found in that.


There was more, though.  You could also see a "rack position" in this 
data, and now it started getting interesting.  It seems that all of the 
really hot machines had a rack position of something low, like 04 or 05, 
and never anything higher than that.  In fact, when looking at a whole 
rack, it was always the lowest number of all of the positions that were 
being used.  Now this was worth chasing!


It's good that I asked, since they told me something surprising: 
position 04 or 05 or whatever was the *bottom* of the rack.  Yes, 
somehow, the lowest machine in the rack was the hottest!  They found 
this interesting, too, and wound up digging into it.  Given that I was 
far away in a distant office, this was the best way for us to proceed.


The problem was that the bottommost server would have nothing below it 
but just open space until it got to the floor.  That space would not 
move air efficiently, and it obviously mattered.


This rolled out and my hot spots disappeared.  Fantastic!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Questions about construction trucks on train tracks]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T01:26:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another day, another bit of local flavor, but this time it's something I 
wish I didn't have to write about.

wrote
about seeing a maintenance truck rolling down the Caltrain line in 
Mountain View.  It had a special attachment to let it stay on the rails.  
At no point did the arms come down for the crossing.  It managed to 
approach, then the people inside looked around and went through, and the 
arms never budged.  There were no flashing lights or bells.




caught fire.  A bunch of people were hurt.  More were shaken 
up.


I'm assuming their construction trucks don't trigger the "short the 
rails together to signal various things" logic, either.  This would 
mean that crossing arms stay up... and I have to assume it also means 
the signals along the way stay green instead of going red.

We will presumably hear more about whatever the signals said, and 
whether the train went past a red signal or not.  I just have a bad 
feeling that they saw a green and kept on going.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toll signs on 101 report your transponder setting]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-10T03:50:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a little bit of Silicon Valley local flavor for a change.  We 
have this freeway that runs from San Jose to San Francisco called US 
101, or around here, just "101".  (Southern California has it too, but 
they call it "the" 101.  That's how we detect invaders.)  Anyway, this 
thing is usually eight or more lanes up and down the peninsula, and it's 
had a "diamond" or car pool lane on the #1 (innermost/"fast") lane for 
many years.  You had to have a certain number of people in the car (or 
some other conditions met) during certain hours (AM and PM rush, 
weekdays), or you'd be in for a hefty ticket.


How does the system know what to charge you?  Well, you either have an 
old-style toll transponder that always bills you as a solo driver, or 
you have a new-style transponder with a 1/2/3+ switch that tells the 
road how to handle you.


Think about what this does to enforcement.  Now, instead of just "is 
there a vehicle in the lane", "is it the right time during a weekday", 
and "how many people are in the car", now it's also a matter of "do they 
have their transponder set properly".


Check this out.



CHP
could roll up on them and give them a ticket.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A parasitic RPC service that broke core dumps]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T04:39:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I already told a
story
about how you can hose your machine by pointing the Linux kernel at a 
custom core dump handler and then have that handler fail to function.  
This'll clog up the pipe (really), and then everything else will just 
stack up behind it.  Pretty soon, every crashing process will be stuck 
just the same.


Once upon a time, in a big company environment, someone decided that 
they wanted to provide a service to other things running on the same 
Linux box.  But, instead of either writing Yet Another Service (tm) 
that would go through release processes and all of that good stuff, they 
went for a different design entirely.


There are so many problems with this.  You have the issue of a "server" 
that appears out of thin air depending on who or what starts first on 
the mac…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A sysadmin's rant about feed readers and crawlers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-08T17:49:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If a web site makes an RSS or Atom feed available, it's not a bad idea 
to poll it from time to time.  Actually doing that poll like a good 
netizen (remember that concept?) takes a little attention to detail.


Given the reality of the situation, does it make sense to poll every 10 
seconds?  Probably not, right?  Someone set up something like that and 
left it running for a couple of months until I finally noticed it and 
dealt with it myself.


Given this, you can keep track of the "Last-Modified" header when you 
get a copy of the feed.  Then, you can turn around and use that same 
value in an "If-Modified-Since" header the next time you come to look 
for an update.  If nothing's changed, the web server will notice it's 
the same as what it already has, and it'll send you a HTTP 304 co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editing stuff in prod]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-05T21:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a concept: "ssh to prod and edit directly on the machine" is 
generally bad news.


I should point out that I didn't know this person and had no idea how 
they would respond to such feedback - it might have been fine!  They 
might be a well-adjusted person who can take a request like that and not 
turn it around into a full-on nuclear attack.  But, I didn't know either 
way.


At some point, I actually had a meeting with this developer for some 
other reason, and what happened was kind of amazing.  First thing, he 
brought it up and asked me about it.  I said something like, "well, I 
didn't want to get into it, but since you asked", and proceeded into 
something along the lines of "obviously it would be best if you didn't 
do that - sshing in and twiddling Python files on the actual production 
AWS instance of the service".


"But... I suspect you are doing it for some reason?"


My response was... I hope... reasonable: "So as much as I would love to 
say 'don't do that!!!', I'm not going to stand in the way of you 
literally doing your job.  So please proceed with care, and keep an eye 
open for some day when (first dumb thing) and (second dumb thing) aren't 
problems any more and you need not do this any more."


It was either "edit in prod" or endure DAY LONG development cycles: make 
a change, wait 24 hours, come back tomorrow, and try it again.  That's 
how broken it was.


The best part about this was that we had a totally reasonable 
conversation about it.  It's the kind of thing which had become a rare 
commodity in those days at that place.


Would I expect someone else to go to that level of insanity every single 
time they just want to get their job done?  Absolutely not.

Editing files in prod to develop them?  That's bad news.  Deliberately 
rigging tunnels to spoof a connection from prod?  That's also bad news.  
Having to do them to get your job done?  You might be in the bad place.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's now your fault they don't know about it]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-04T00:14:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quite a while back, I wrote a post that basically went like this: if 
someone has a problem with someone else or something that person is 
doing, they're going to find a way to get to "no".  They will find some 
reason, some excuse, or some problem with it.  They'll bring up a point 
and you'll show that this is not in fact a thing.  They will then pivot 
again and again.


But, as I said, that was back then, and this time I'm talking about 
something else: when it happens in person with a coworker.  I had an 
experience like this a few years back, and figured I'd share how it goes 
for the sake of others who might not have encountered it yet, or who 
have and thought they were alone in this.


Coworker: There are no docs for [this thing you're doing].


Coworker: You could make a wiki pag…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universally unique identifier?  Sometimes...]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-02T03:44:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a short one since it's somewhere between a random bit of 
"grab some popcorn" amusement and a "huh, that might be a problem some 
day".  In short, it looks like every Raspberry Pi filesystem installed 
from any given release image probably ends up with the same
UUID.


For instance, if you downloaded the "lite" version of Raspbian between 
roughly November 8th and January 28th, you probably got a file called 
2021-10-30-raspios-bullseye-armhf-lite.zip.  Inside, there's an image, 
and the idea is that you dump that straight to your SD card, cram it in 
the Pi, and off you go.  The second partition on that image is an ext4 
filesystem which was created on some build machine somewhere.  The UUID 
on it never gets "evolved" to something else after the install.


You can see it inside the image itself here:


Or, if you actually installed a few of these things like I did over the 
past couple of months, you can just 'tune2fs -l /dev/mmcblk0p2' and see 
the same value in there.


Don't end up with a pile of SD cards on your desk and think "I know, 
I'll use the filesystem UUIDs to track which one goes where", in other 
words.


If it's not breaking anything for you, it's probably best to just let it 
be.  Untangling a boot mess on these weird little boxes is anything but 
fun.

Note: if you're actually on a recent Raspberry Pi, odds are good that 
your /etc/fstab will be using *partition* UUIDs (PARTUUID=...) and not 
those of the filesystem.  If in doubt, use blkid to see what's what.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Command-V (or CTRL-V) is your "copilot"]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-28T22:54:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A reader wrote in asking what I thought about the whole GitHub "copilot" 
thing.  If you haven't heard of it yet, it's apparently this thing that 
was trained on a whole mess of repositories and their code, and you can 
"prompt" it and it'll spit out code that may or may not do what you 
want.  It doesn't seem to know about licensing (BSD, GPL, MIT, that sort 
of thing), or plagiarism, or any of that other good stuff.


This is actually a story about somewhere I used to work, and someone who 
was on one of my teams back in the day.  One day, I heard that one of 
the people in a far-away office had created some kind of tool that would 
let you look at the status of different machines - that is, Linux boxes. 
I don't remember the finer points of it or why this person even 
bothered, but they…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[C++ header files and inter-class connections]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-27T11:35:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are some interesting implications to the way that you have to 
handle references to other bits of code when you write a C++ header 
file.  There are things you can do which turn out to be suboptimal, and 
until or unless you work someplace with a coding style document or get 
some mentor who's already been there, you're likely to make some
mistakes.


Anyway, a common way to do this is to set up the outer class such that 
it has a pointer to the inner one.  You *could* have it just own it 
directly, but then that introduces problems.



 private:
  Bar bar_;



Of course, bar.h probably has its own dependencies which get #included, 
and so now you end up with this evil web of slow compiles.  It sucks.


What used to happen next is that someone would say, okay, let's make it 
a pointe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Results without all of the brackets]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-22T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, I
put forth
a bunch of API possibilities for the problem of needing to return a 
value but also indicating the lack of a value and being able to comment 
on why.  In it, the notion of a "wrapper" around a string was presented, 
such that it might look like "Result<string>", and those brackets 
started looking like a pain.  There was also the possibility of having 
something like "ResultString", but didn't that open the door to having a 
bunch of code duplication?


After this had existed for a while, the general happy feeling of having 
this stuff in place became infectious.  I wanted it to cover other 
things with it, too.  I wanted it to handle something a bit more 
complicated than a mere string, and so decided to try my hand at the 
template-wrangling metaprogramming cruft t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Returning values and errors]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-20T21:33:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you agree with the notion that you need to be able to tell the 
difference between the absence of a value and a value itself, then this 
has some impacts on the code you write.  If you want to keep 'em 
separated (so they can come out and play), then it gets you looking at 
your API designs in certain ways.


Imagine we're talking about a helper function that is intended to be run 
inside a program that's handling the access to a web page.  It's 
probably a CGI program, but it could also be buried inside some much 
bigger thing, too.  This is all about C++ styles, but you can probably 
see slices of other languages in here, too.


string UserIP() -- No more lifetime worries here, but oops, uh, well, 
what if we don't know what it is and need to provide an error?  If it's 
a CGI situatio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My "daily drivers", and what happened to Slackware here]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T21:48:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In
yesterday's post,
I mentioned taking my old Mac Mini out of the OS X/macos ecosystem and 
bringing it into Debian, and then what kind of hilarity followed when I 
attempted to install a Javascript linter (and it tried to drag in 180+ 
node-related packages).


Readers are advised that this post will probably contain 
definitely contains a even higher than usual amount of 
navel-gazing as I dish out the details of my setup.  My usual 
disclaimer of "this works for me and probably won't work for you, so if 
you have different tastes, then great, go with that" definitely applies 
here.


First of all, the one that most people actually notice is the actual box 
which is serving rachelbythebay.com, which at the moment is a box called 
snowgoose.  I had installed it in early 2020 as CentOS 8 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A twisted maze of dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T03:07:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh sure, everyone laughs about things having a lot of dependencies, but 
do they ever really think about the implications of having hundreds of 
teeny little libraries, all moving independently?  This is how it 
manifests in the real world.


My relative inexperience with Debian systems means I'm constantly being 
delighted to discover that such and such has already been packaged up 
and is just an apt command away.  Things that I would have done by hand 
in the years up to this point now have someone else worrying about them.


This is what happened next:


... huh.  The story basically ends there.  I'm going to handle this some 
other way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add 4740180 to the list of silly magic numbers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T08:11:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh dear.  The software fungus where bits of code take the
literal characters "HTTP" as a number
has expanded.  Now it has a variant: 4740180.


Where does this one come from?  
Go and gRPC, apparently!


I found this while searching the web for "1213486160" to see how things 
have been going in the past few years.  Unfortunately, it's still biting 
people all over the place.  There are far too many posts asking people 
to upgrade their software, or restart things, or do any number of 
useless rubber-chicken-waving techniques which ultimately will 
accomplish nothing.

When you see a funny-looking number, figure out where it comes from.
That's the only way to have any chance of understanding what's actually 
going on.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feedback: environments, old BBSes, Honda's 2022 bug]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T23:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yep, it's time for another round of reader feedback.

"process infection" story:

https://lwn.net/Articles/883547/):


If you do privileged execution of specific operations via IPC you get 
the guarantee that whatever is done, is done from a well-defined, 
pristine execution environment, without leaking context implicitly. The 
IPC message is the *full* vulnerable surface, and that's as minimal as 
it can get. And that's great.




Oh wow, thank you for mentioning that, unnamed reader!  I definitely 
read that post on LWN at some point in the past couple of days when the 
pkexec thing started going around.  It must have really worked its way 
into my head, and then eventually stirred up the memory of everything 
getting "nicely infected" at $OLD_JOB.


Every time I talk about trying to par…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A nice story about Unix processes "infecting" each other]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T19:24:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I once worked at a place that had an interesting little problem stemming 
from the way they managed machines and some of the fun side-effects 
processes can have on each other.  This is back in the pre-systemd days 
of running services, such that things tended to be started or restarted 
by someone or something that itself ran as root.  That is, if you 
started something, it might inherit one or more things from your 
environment.  Likewise, if you ran something with an unusual 
environment, it might bestow those "gifts" onto anything it happened to 
touch.


After locking themselves out of machines too many times, people 
generally learned that after you mess with a glibc upgrade, you restart 
the sshd listener on port 22.  Of course, they also had to learn to not 
whack EVERY sshd at the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An old photo of a very large BBS]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 30 years ago, I was given this picture.  I wanted to present it 
in a post all by itself to give it a chance to "sink in" before I went 
and used it in an analogy.  First, I'll just show the image and explain 
what you're looking at here.




I do remember the description from the back: this is a picture of *part 
of* something that was called the Software Creations BBS.  It was a 
multi-line bulletin board system where you could dial up and send 
messages to people, upload and download files, and (presumably) play 
online games ("doors") and anything else they cared to offer.

64 machines in a little space.  I have to assume 
they are at least 
286s (ATs, more or 
less), but it's impossible to tell from just this picture.  They could 
have been 386s or even 486s by that point, but …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One machine can go pretty far if you build things properly]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, so yesterday I 
posted
a picture of an old multi-line bulletin board system which had 
apparently taken over an entire bedroom with dozens of computers.  I 
mentioned that I intended to come back to the topic to throw in my own 
two cents, and so here we go.


Or, were you someone who found it horrific and wished there was a 
simpler way?  Did you wonder if it would be possible to pack all of that 
into one or maybe two boxes, instead?  Did you want a way to negate all 
of that complexity while still providing the same level of service?


Now, things are different.  I look at that and just sigh at the lost 
opportunities.  The actual amount of work being done on behalf of any of 
the users who are connected is tiny.  If we ignore the fact that the 
actual BBS software and related acc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>