<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html</id>
    <title>Ajour / Spitlo.com</title>
    <updated>2022-11-16T00:37:45.876Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 ways a Firefox account comes in handy]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70631</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/firefox-tips/firefox-account-password-manager-bookmarks-credit-card-autofill/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-15T19:57:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even people who are very online can use some help navigating the internet – from keeping credit card details safe when online shopping to generating a password when one simply doesn’t have any more passwords in them. Using Firefox as your main browser helps take care of that. Want to level up? With a Firefox […]
The post 4 ways a Firefox account comes in handy appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 15 Nov 2022 Tracers In the Dark]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4394</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/15/public-immutable-crimes/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-15T08:08:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Tracers in the Dark: Andy Greenberg's gripping true crime tale of cryptocurrency forensics. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Tracers in the Dark (permalink) In Tracers in the Dark, Andy Greenberg traces the fascinating, horrifying, and complicated story of the battle over Bitcoin secrecy, as law enforcement agencies, tax authorities and private-sector sleuths seek to trace and attribute the cryptocurrency used in a variety of crimes, some relatively benign (selling weed online), some absolutely ghastly (selling videos of child sex abuse). https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/690603/tracers-in-the-dark-by-andy-greenberg/ …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 14 Nov 2022 Even if you're paying for the product, you're still the product]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4389</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/14/luxury-surveillance/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-14T08:01:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Even if you're paying for the product, you're still the product: Incentives matter, but impunity matters more. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Even if you're paying for the product, you're still the product (permalink) There's something oddly comforting about the idea that "if you're not paying for the product, you're the product," namely, the corollary: "If you can afford to pay for a product, you won't be the product." But it's bullshit. Companies don't make you the product because you don't pay – they make you the product because you can't stop them. The theory behind "if you're not paying for the product…" is that…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bad Date]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2698/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2698/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/bad_date.png" title="&quot;Even split between us, this will pay way better than the Jumanji sponsorship I came into the date with.&quot;" alt="&quot;Even split between us, this will pay way better than the Jumanji sponsorship I came into the date with.&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 13 Nov 2022 The Framework is the most exciting laptop I've ever broken]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4384</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/13/graceful-failure/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-13T11:47:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Framework is the most exciting laptop I've ever broken: If you only pay attention to how things work, you'll be screwed when they fail. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Framework is the most exciting laptop I've ever broken (permalink) From the moment I started using computers, I wanted to help other people use them. I was everyone's tech support for years, which prepared me for the decade or so when I was a CIO-for-hire. In the early days of the internet, I spent endless hours helping my BBS friends find their way onto the net. Helping other people use technology requires humility: you have to want to help the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 11 Nov 2022 Apple's business model made Chinese oppression inevitable]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4379</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/11/foreseeable-consequences/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-11T09:04:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Apple's business model made Chinese oppression inevitable: A photon torpedo on the bridge in Act I will go off by Act III. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Apple's business model made Chinese oppression inevitable (permalink) A month ago, a wave of rare political protests swept China, centered on Beijing, where Premier Xi Jinping was consolidating his already-substantial power by claiming an unprecedented third term: https://www.cnn.com/2022/10/22/china/china-party-congress-overseas-students-protest-intl-hnk Protest organizers in China struggle with the serious legal and extrajudicial penalties for anti-government activities…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Y2K and 2038]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2697/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2697/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/y2k_and_2038.png" title="It's taken me 20 years, but I've finally finished rebuilding all my software to use 33-bit signed ints." alt="It's taken me 20 years, but I've finally finished rebuilding all my software to use 33-bit signed ints." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over a quarter of parents believe their children don’t know how to protect their information online – Firefox can help with that]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70565</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/over-a-quarter-of-parents-believe-their-children-dont-know-how-to-protect-their-information-online-firefox-can-help-with-that/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parenting has never been easy. But with a generation growing up with groundbreaking technology, families are facing new challenges along with opportunities as children interact with screens everywhere they go — while learning at school, playing with friends and for on-the-go entertainment.  We are previewing a new Mozilla Firefox survey conducted in partnership with YouGov […]
The post Over a quarter of parents believe their children don’t know how to protect their information online – Firefox can help with that  appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 10 Nov 2022 Amazon and Apple have an illegal price-fixing conspiracy]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4375</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/10/you-had-one-job/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T09:07:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Amazon and Apple have an illegal price-fixing conspiracy: The creatures outside looked from pig to man, and from man to pig, and from pig to man again; but already it was impossible to say which was which. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Amazon and Apple have an illegal price-fixing conspiracy (permalink) A class action law firm has filed a suit against Apple and Amazon, accusing the companies of price-fixing Ios devices through an agreement that blocks third-party sellers from Amazon unless they're authorized by Apple. The suit should be a slam-dunk – but even more, the conduct it accuses Apple and Amazon of should n…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to talk to kids about social media]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70407</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-talk-to-kids-about-social-media/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-09T16:40:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joy Cho is the founder and creative director of the lifestyle brand and design company Oh Joy! For two years in a row, she was named one of Time’s 30 Most Influential People on the Internet and has the most followed account on Pinterest with over 15 million followers. You can also follow her on […]
The post How to talk to kids about social media appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 09 Nov 2022 Delegating trust is really, really, really hard (infosec edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4368</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/09/infosec-blackpill/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-09T11:12:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Delegating trust is really, really, really hard (infosec edition): Who knows what secrets lurk in your browser's root certificate store? Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Delegating trust is really, really, really hard (infosec edition) (permalink) I've got trust issues. We all do. Some infosec pros go so far as to say "trust no one," a philosophy more formally known as "Zero Trust," that holds that certain elements of your security should never be delegated to any third party. The problem is, it's trust all the way down. Say you maintain your own cryptographic keys on your own device. How do you know the software you use to …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Precision vs Accuracy]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2696/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2696/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/precision_vs_accuracy.png" title="'Barack Obama is much less likely than the average cat to jump in and out of cardboard boxes for fun' is low precision, but I'm not sure about the accuracy." alt="'Barack Obama is much less likely than the average cat to jump in and out of cardboard boxes for fun' is low precision, but I'm not sure about the accuracy." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links, 2, 3, 4: Accessibility]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7404</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/11/08/links-2-3-4-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-08T11:32:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here are some recent links on the topic of accessibility you might enjoy and learn something from: Manuel Matuzovic has a course together with SmashingMag on Deep Dive on Accessibility Testing starting on the 14th of November 2022. On that topic I also have a class on Skillshare Product Management: Tools for Improving Product Accessibility […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Nov 2022 Tech a la carte]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4358</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/08/divisibility/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-08T09:19:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Tech a la carte: A new antitrinitarian technognosticism. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Tech a la carte (permalink) "Oblique Strategies" is Brian Eno and Peter Schmidt's deck of 100+ cards, each with a sentence of gnomic advice. They inspired Roxy Music, David Bowie, Talking Heads and Devo. My favorite? "Be the first person to not do something that no one else has ever not done before." Why that one? Because it challenges us to imagine how something that we perceive as unitary and indivisible might be decomposed into smaller units. It's a challenge to the notion that one must "take the bad with the good." What if we could …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Position Statement for the 2022 W3C TAG Election]]></title>
        <id>https://lea.verou.me/?p=3531</id>
        <link href="https://lea.verou.me/2022/11/tag-2/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-07T21:01:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Context: In 2020, I ran for the TAG election for the first time and had the great honor of being elected by the W3C membership. This year, I’m running for re-election. The W3C Technical Architecture Group (TAG) is the Working Group that ensures that Web Platform technologies are usable and follow consistent design principles, whether they […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lea Verou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Nov 2022 The good news is that Penguin Random House can't buy all the other publishers]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4352</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/07/random-penguins/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-07T11:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The good news is that Penguin Random House can't buy all the other publishers: Now for the bad news. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The good news is that Penguin Random House can't buy all the other publishers (permalink) Last week, a US District Court blocked the merger of Penguin Random House, the world's largest publisher, and Simon and Schuster, the world's third-largest publisher. This is very, very good news. https://www.npr.org/2022/11/01/1133032238/judge-blocks-penguin-random-house-simon-schuster-merger During the trial, the Penguin Random House argued it they would continue to compete with Simon and Schuster for b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soil]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2695/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2695/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/soil.png" title="You might want to bring your frost-sensitive plants in from the patio. The high-level aerosols may result in short-term cooling across the entire backyard." alt="You might want to bring your frost-sensitive plants in from the patio. The high-level aerosols may result in short-term cooling across the entire backyard." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making a DNS query in Ruby from scratch]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/11/06/making-a-dns-query-in-ruby-from-scratch/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/11/06/making-a-dns-query-in-ruby-from-scratch/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-06T08:31:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! A while back I wrote a post about how to write a toy DNS resolver in Go.
In that post I left out “how to generate and parse DNS queries” because I
thought it was boring, but a few people pointed out that they did not know how
to parse and generate DNS queries and they were interested in how to do it.
This made me curious – how much work is it do the DNS parsing? It turns out
we can do it in a pretty nice 120-line Ruby program, which is not that bad.
So here’s a quick post on how to generate DNS queries and parse DNS responses!
We’re going to do it in Ruby because I’m giving a talk at a Ruby conference
soon, and this blog post is partly prep for that talk :). I’ve tried to keep it
readable for folks who don’t know Ruby though, I’ve only used pretty basic Ruby
code.
At the end we’re g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Removing the camera overlay icon on images in Microsoft Edge]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7397</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/11/04/removing-the-camera-overlay-icon-on-images-in-microsoft-edge/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-04T10:41:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you use Microsoft Edge, you get a camera icon when you hover your mouse over any image: This is a great tool for users as it allows them to do a visual search in a sidebar for that image. During local development, the icon appears on images, too, but the results don’t show up. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Königsberg]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2694/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2694/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/konigsberg.png" title="At first I thought I would need some gold or something to pay him, but then I realized that it was the 18th century and I could just bring a roll of aluminum foil." alt="At first I thought I would need some gold or something to pay him, but then I realized that it was the 18th century and I could just bring a roll of aluminum foil." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to talk to kids about video games]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70420</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-talk-to-kids-about-video-games/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-02T15:03:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr. Naomi Fisher is a U.K.-based clinical psychologist specializing in trauma and autism. She’s the author of “Changing Our Minds: How Children Can Take Control of Their Own Learning.” Her writing has also appeared in the British Psychological Society’s The Psychologist, among other publications. You can follow her on Twitter. Photo: Justine Diamond I spend a […]
The post How to talk to kids about video games appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla Ventures: Investing in Responsible Tech]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70406</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/mozilla-ventures-investing-in-responsible-tech/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-02T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Early next year, we will launch Mozilla Ventures, a first of its kind impact venture fund to invest in startups that push the internet — and the tech industry — in a better direction  _____ Many people complain about today’s tech industry. Some say the internet has lost its soul. And some even say it’s […]
The post Mozilla Ventures: Investing in Responsible Tech appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Surman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla Launches First-of-its-Kind Venture Fund to Fuel Responsible Tech Companies, Products]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70418</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/mozilla-launches-first-of-its-kind-venture-fund-to-fuel-responsible-tech-companies-products/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-02T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Initial $35M will foster an ecosystem of startups that push the internet — and the tech industry — in a better direction   Industry veteran Mohamed Nanabhay will head the venture  _____ November 2, 2022 (LISBON, Portugal) — Today, amid a sea of internet companies and products that routinely put profits ahead of people, Mozilla is […]
The post Mozilla Launches First-of-its-Kind Venture Fund to Fuel Responsible Tech Companies, Products  appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Zawacki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wirecutter Recommendation]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2693/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2693/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/wirecutter_recommendation.png" title="Their 'best philosophy of epistemology' picks are great, but you can tell they're struggling a little in the 'why you should trust us' section." alt="Their 'best philosophy of epistemology' picks are great, but you can tell they're struggling a little in the 'why you should trust us' section." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Nov 2022 "When Franny Stands Up," Eden Robins' debut novel]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4319</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/01/eden-robins/"/>
        <updated>2022-11-01T07:01:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links "When Franny Stands Up," Eden Robins' debut novel: Supernaturual comediennes of WWII. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading "When Franny Stands Up," Eden Robins' debut novel (permalink) Of all the alternate history premises in fiction, the McGuffin of Eden Robins's debut, "When Franny Stands Up," is one of the most unlikely and – it turns out – rich. Robins' novel opens on Franny, a teenage Jewish girl from the Chicago suburbs who's snuck out on Christmas Eve to hear the notorious comedian Boopsie Baxter do standup. https://read.sourcebooks.com/fiction/9781728256009-when-franny-stands-up-tp.html It's an all-female audience…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of October Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42921</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/10/31/end-of-october-link-assortment-7/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-31T16:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events IF Comp is still running, now through November 15. There are lots of games to play; you need only vote on five to participate as a judge in the competition. (Though you’re very welcome to vote on more than five, of course!) And as if the bounty of IF Comp were not enough, October … Continue reading "End of October Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for October]]></title>
        <id>log.html#oct2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#oct2022"/>
        <updated>2022-10-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of October. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
TinyBASIC, implemented TinyBASIC in Uxntal.
Left, added a variant of the Smalltalk-76 font.
Hakum, released a short comic sequence called Chase.
Wunderland Rabbits, added a new rabbit pic.
100r.co, updated galley plumbing(serviced our water pump) and curtains(modified the design). Added lazy lazy jacks.
News
Pino is in Victoria again, and we're diving back into our favorite fall activities like pumpkin carving (see halloween pumpkins), and fruit picking. The boat is now filled with apple jam. October was a drawing month for the both of us. Devine participated in drawtober and completed 28 drawings using Noodle. Rekka finished a sequence for the ongoing comic project Hakum.
For those in the Pacific Northwest, Devine will be giving a talk called Weathering Software Winter at Handmade Seattle on November 17th.
As you know, we share a community online with a fantastic group of people. Some months ago Lizbeth designed a burgee for Merveilles and this month we decided to make one for Pino. See the Merveilles burgee.
Pino book club
We're reading Life, the Universe and Everything by Douglas Adams, and What The Doormouse Said by John Markoff.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interior Decorating]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2692/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2692/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/interior_decorating.png" title="It all came flat-packed in Pandora's Box." alt="It all came flat-packed in Pandora's Box." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Presents: Cosplayer Rachel Maksy gives main character energy]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70323</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/rachel-maksy-youtube/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-28T16:43:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rachel Maksy has been Wonder Woman, Princess Leia, and, for one week, multiple Jane Austen characters. She goes to conventions to meet other cosplayers wearing costumes that she created. But mostly, her handmade outfits are seen and watched by her nearly 1.5 million followers across YouTube and Instagram.  “Just like a kid dressing up on […]
The post Firefox Presents: Cosplayer Rachel Maksy gives main character energy appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Oct 2022 Adobe steals your color]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4314</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/28/fade-to-black/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-28T08:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Adobe steals your color: A SaaS on the mantel in Act I must go off by Act III. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Adobe steals your color (permalink) When a company breaks a product you rely on – wrecking decades of work – it's natural to feel fury. Companies know this, so they try to deflect your rage by blaming their suppliers. Sometimes, it's suppliers who are at fault – but other times, there is plenty of blame to go around. For example, when Apple deleted all the working VPNs from its Chinese App Store and backdoored its Chinese cloud servers, it blamed the Chinese government. But the Chinese state knew that Apple had lo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reminder: JSON.stringify can create Multi-line, formatted and filtered strings from JSON]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7394</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/10/28/reminder-json-stringify-can-create-multi-line-formatted-and-filtered-strings-from-json/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-28T06:11:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can use `JSON.stringify()` to turn a JSON object into a string. let obj = {“a”: 1, “b”: 3, “c”: “boo!”}; console.log(JSON.stringify(obj)) This results in a single line string: {]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Encryption]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2691/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2691/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/encryption.png" title="WARNING: PEOPLE NAMED EVE ARE PROHIBITED FROM INSTALLING THIS APP!" alt="WARNING: PEOPLE NAMED EVE ARE PROHIBITED FROM INSTALLING THIS APP!" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Oct 2022 Substituting economics for politics is a failure]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4307</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/27/economism/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-27T17:09:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Substituting economics for politics is a failure: The verdict is in on "economism." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Substituting economics for politics is a failure (permalink) Most of us believe that we do stuff because we want to be good people, and that other people act the same. But the dominant political philosophy for the last half-century, "economism," views us as slaves to "incentives" and nothing more. Economism is the philosophy of the neoclassical economists, whose ideology has consumed both the Democrats and Republicans. They dismiss all "non-market" solutions (that is, projects of democratically accountable go…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Developer Advocacy Handbook is now available as an eBook on Leanpub and Amazon Kindle]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7388</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/10/27/the-developer-advocacy-handbook-is-now-available-as-an-ebook-on-leanpub-and-amazon-kindle/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-27T13:45:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People often asked me if I can make the Developer Advocacy Handbook available as an eBook to read on their devices. When Jens Oliver Meiert also asked me I told him there were no immediate plans, so he took on that task and converted the book. You can now purchase the eBook either on Amazon […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 26 Oct 2022 Uline's billions fund voter suppression]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4303</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/26/boxed-in/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-26T15:29:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Uline's billions fund voter suppression: The Uihlein family used to fund the John Birch Society, today it's the Big Lie. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Uline's billions fund voter suppression (permalink) Every billionaire is a policy failure, but every billionaire is also a factory for producing policy failures at scale. The political power conferred by massive wealth accumulation makes a sham of democracy, because "one person, one vote" is easily swamped by "one dollar, one vote." That's why we need to abolish all billionaires, even the "good" ones who promise to support charities or causes we support. But today, I …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Mozilla product manager on his career path and what creating safe spaces online means to him]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70288</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/privacy-security/product-manager-career-firefox-relay/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-26T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a staff product manager for Mozilla’s security and privacy team, Tony Amaral-Cinotto thinks a lot about how you can protect your personal information, including, most recently, your phone number.  Firefox Relay has been protecting email addresses from spammers since 2020. Tony’s team just released a new feature applying the same idea to your phone […]
The post A Mozilla product manager on his career path and what creating safe spaces online means to him appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cool S]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2690/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2690/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/cool_s.png" title="Although I hear they were caught cheating off of Rosalind, who sat at a desk in front of them." alt="Although I hear they were caught cheating off of Rosalind, who sat at a desk in front of them." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep your family’s internet private with Total Cookie Protection on Firefox]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70249</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/firefox-tips/internet-safety-for-families-total-cookie-protection/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By the time a kid turns 13, more than 72 million pieces of personal data have been collected about them on the internet, according to a 2018 report. These can include name, date of birth, address, family members, where they hang out, the people they interact with, what they do in the classroom, and which […]
The post Keep your family’s internet private with Total Cookie Protection on Firefox appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 24 Oct 2022 An hour of interwar Halloween music]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4298</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/24/spooky-season/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T10:23:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links An hour of interwar Halloween music: Spooky season listening from Centuries of Sound. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading An hour of interwar Halloween music (permalink) Through his delightful Centuries of Sound project, JM Errington is producing an hour-long mix of music for every year since 1853 – the dawn of music recording itself. Interspersed with these "annual" mixes are some thematic ones. His latest, "Halloween Between the Wars," is an hour of spooky interwar music and radio/film horror excerpts: https://centuriesofsound.com/2022/10/24/halloween-between-the-wars-original-recordings-1927-1938/ The track-list for th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fermat's First Theorem]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2689/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2689/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/fermats_first_theorem.png" title="Mathematicians quickly determined that it spells ANT BNECN, an unusual theoretical dish which was not successfully cooked until Andrew Wiles made it for breakfast in the 1990s." alt="Mathematicians quickly determined that it spells ANT BNECN, an unusual theoretical dish which was not successfully cooked until Andrew Wiles made it for breakfast in the 1990s." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 23 Oct 2022 The Persuaders (how minds really change)]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4292</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/23/narrative-warfare/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-23T16:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Persuaders (how minds really change): No mind control required. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Persuaders (how minds really change) (permalink) I have always been interested in how people change their minds. I think it started with my Dad's story – he was a conservative, religious Jew until he was 18, then he had an argument with a union activist on a picket line, and within a year had renounced his faith and become a lifelong revolutionary communist. My dad was and is an arguer, as am I. He was raised on vigorous debate, and when he lost to someone who had arguments he couldn't refute, he returned to the picket line, da…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Joy of Silly Useless Software]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5445</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/the-joy-of-silly-useless-software"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T20:34:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was invited by the wonderful organizers of the “Gamez & ruleZ” conference to speak. I’m grateful to have been given an opportunity to discuss a topic that I’m passionate about: silly software (like desktop pets or other unusual programs that are hard to classify). Following is my talk turned into a blog post. There are a lot of recommendations here, and I hope you enjoy these wonderful, strange, silly finds… As you may know, I’m an experimental game designer, and make weird software that kind of exists in the space between games and “something else”. It’s the type of...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We're Breaking Up with CSS-in-JS [link]]]></title>
        <id>2022-10-21-98c59dd2</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/links/2022-10-21-98c59dd2"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T16:25:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2nd most active maintainer of Emotion writes on why they're leaving CSS-in-JS.
Mostly this is written documentation and proof of what I've been seeing and feeling every time I have to use a CSS-in-JS library.
Via Bruce Lawson https://twitter.com/brucel/status/1582787411469533184
Source: dev.to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 21 Oct 2022 Backdooring a summarizerbot to shape opinion]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4286</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/21/let-me-summarize/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T13:59:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Backdooring a summarizerbot to shape opinion: Model spinning maintains accuracy metrics, but changes the point of view. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Backdooring a summarizerbot to shape opinion (permalink) What's worse than a tool that doesn't work? One that does work, nearly perfectly, except when it fails in unpredictable and subtle ways. Such a tool is bound to become indispensable, and even if you know it might fail eventually, maintaining vigilance in the face of long stretches of reliability is impossible: https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/20/mit-study-finds-tesla-drivers-become-inattentive-when-autopilot-is-activated…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bubble Universes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2688/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2688/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/bubble_universes.png" title="The theory finally unifies cosmic inflation and regular inflation." alt="The theory finally unifies cosmic inflation and regular inflation." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 20 Oct 2022 It was all downhill after the Cuecat]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4279</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/20/benevolent-dictators/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-20T17:11:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links It was all downhill after the Cuecat: On the origins of "user manipulation and surveillance." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading It was all downhill after the Cuecat (permalink) Sometime in 2001, I walked into a Radio Shack on San Francisco's Market Street and asked for a Cuecat: a handheld barcode scanner that looked a bit like a cat and a bit like a sex toy. The clerk handed one over to me and I left, feeling a little giddy. I didn't have to pay a cent. The Cuecat was a good idea and a terrible idea. The good idea was to widely distribute barcode scanners to computer owners, along with software that could read and decode bar…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prep for the U.S. midterm elections with these online tools]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70214</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/uncategorized/midterms-2022-election-prep/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Avoiding misinformation online can be tricky, especially during election season. And while the media cycle may be more low-key than it would be for a U.S. presidential election (coming up soon in 2024), this November’s midterm has not been immune to internet discord. Americans have got some big decisions to make after all, like how […]
The post Prep for the U.S. midterm elections with these online tools appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prep for the U.S. midterm elections with these online tools]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70214</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/midterms-2022-election-prep/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Avoiding misinformation online can be tricky, especially during election season. And while the media cycle may be more low-key than it would be for a U.S. presidential election (coming up soon in 2024), this November’s midterm has not been immune to internet discord. Americans have got some big decisions to make after all, like how […]
The post Prep for the U.S. midterm elections with these online tools appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A glossary of terms about cyberattacks, from ransomware to DDoS]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68641</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/cyberattacks-glossary-of-terms-ransomware-ddos/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-19T14:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you read news about technology, you’re bound to run into some jargon. Here at Mozilla, we believe that information should be as accessible as possible regardless of your level of expertise. We want to help you approach stories about technology with more curiosity and with a little less head-scratching involved. We’ll break down headline-making […]
The post A glossary of terms about cyberattacks, from ransomware to DDoS appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Division Notation]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2687/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2687/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/division_notation.png" title="Science tip: Scientists hardly ever use the two-dot division sign, and when they do it often doesn't even mean division, but they still get REALLY mad when you repurpose it to write stuff like SALE! ALL SHOES 30÷ OFF!" alt="Science tip: Scientists hardly ever use the two-dot division sign, and when they do it often doesn't even mean division, but they still get REALLY mad when you repurpose it to write stuff like SALE! ALL SHOES 30÷ OFF!" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You don’t have to be an astronaut to explore space, Mozilla Hubs can take you there]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70140</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/you-dont-have-to-be-an-astronaut-to-explore-space-mozilla-hubs-can-take-you-there/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T16:35:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This month, Mozilla Hubs, a place where you can get together with friends online in a virtual-social space, partnered with conceptual artist Ashley Zelinskie on her New York exhibition, “Unfold the Universe: First Light.” The exhibition features her VR artwork “Unfolding the Universe: A NASA Webb VR Experience” in Mozilla Hubs. The exhibit runs through […]
The post You don’t have to be an astronaut to explore space, Mozilla Hubs can take you there appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenifer Boscacci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 18 Oct 2022 Being good at your job is praxis]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4273</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/18/administrative-competence/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T15:10:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Being good at your job is praxis: The FTC can mandate Right to Repair without (further) Congressional authorization. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: None Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Being good at your job is praxis (permalink) You know the joke. Office manager: "$75 just to kick the photocopier?" Photocopier technician: "No, it's $5 to kick the photocopier and $70 to know where to kick it." The trustbusters in the Biden administration know precisely where to kick the photocopier, and they're kicking the shit out of it. You love to see it. Last July, the Biden admin published an Executive Order enumerating 72 actions that administrative agencies could take without any furthe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy online just got easier with today’s Firefox release]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70098</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/privacy-online-just-got-easier-with-todays-firefox-release/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T13:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[October is one of our favorite months of the year with Autumn and Cybersecurity Awareness Month. We’re supporting Cybersecurity Awareness with Private Browsing mode upgrades. Additionally, we’re rolling out new features to help you pick up where you last left off with Firefox View and new Colorways and wallpapers to refresh your look. Earlier this […]
The post Privacy online just got easier with today’s Firefox release appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox makes browsing more colorful with new ‘independent voices’]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70023</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/firefox-news/independent-voices/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The internet we know today has evolved from a place to perform a specific task into a creative and essential platform touching most aspects of our lives.  Despite advances since the personal computer was invented decades ago, the same lackluster color palette that plagued its original design still remains present on many digital spaces today. […]
The post Firefox makes browsing more colorful with new ‘independent voices’ appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Vasquez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 Oct 2022 A giant grocery merger will send "inflation" through the roof]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4267</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/17/united-states-vs-vons/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T15:50:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A giant grocery merger will send "inflation" through the roof: The Kroger-Albertson's merger will trigger massive price-hikes. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A giant grocery merger will send "inflation" through the roof (permalink) Sometimes it's hard to know why prices are going up. Between the oil shock, a tight employment market and the climate polycrisis, is it even possible to tell if companies are using the widespread belief in inflation to hike prices? Uh, yeah, as it turns out, we absolutely can. Yes, it's hard to peer into the minds of executives at large companies and know whether their price hikes are due to greed or necessity. But we don't have peer i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Space Adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2686/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2686/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/space_adventure.png" title="&quot;Sir, it looked really cool.&quot; &quot;Oh no--prestige TV. Okay, which of you has a terrible secret that's being slowly revealed to the audience through flashbacks? Just spit it out so we can escape this arc!&quot;" alt="&quot;Sir, it looked really cool.&quot; &quot;Oh no--prestige TV. Okay, which of you has a terrible secret that's being slowly revealed to the audience through flashbacks? Just spit it out so we can escape this arc!&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 Oct 2022 RIP, Roger Wood, genius assemblage sculptor]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4262</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/16/klockwerks/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-16T13:42:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links RIP, Roger Wood, genius assemblage sculptor: Sorely missed already. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading RIP, Roger Wood, genius assemblage sculptor (permalink) Last week, my dear old friend Roger Wood died, very suddenly, of cancer. He was 80. Roger was a brilliant sculptor, a Canadian veteran navy gunner, and gay. He was my neighbour for a decade. I miss him already. Roger and I both lived in an old WWI munitions factory in Toronto, which had been turned into 15 illegal live-work studios with 20-foot ceilings which leaked, massive south-facing windows (which leaked), and a warm and collegial vibe of weirdos and artists. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 15 Oct 2022 How lawyers became sadists]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4258</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/15/lex-sadist/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-15T16:09:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How lawyers became sadists: What about the incentive not to be perceived as a colossal asshole? Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2020. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How lawyers became sadists (permalink) There is plentiful evidence that we are, as a species, prone to empathy and kindness. That isn't to say that we're always mindful of the ways our actions harm others, but for most of us, acts of overt cruelty require a special effort, at least at first. Greed and hatred have to be nurtured and trained. Even in war, violence doesn't come naturally. The majority of US riflemen in WWII did not fire their weapons, refusing to shoot at the enemy. Many fired …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-October Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42909</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/10/15/mid-october-link-assortment-8/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-15T15:57:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IF Comp is currently in full swing. This annual competition has been running now for nearly three decades, and continues to showcase interesting new work in the field. The IF Comp website has gotten some sweet upgrades to help judges find the games they’ll like the most: you can have the website serve you a … Continue reading "Mid-October Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 14 Oct 2022 Medieval Times invents a modern union-busting tactic; Billionaire dilletantes vs good Democrats]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4253</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/14/competitors-critics-customers/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-14T15:51:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Medieval Times invents a modern union-busting tactic: Trademark, like all "IP," is a tool to control critics, customers and competitors. Billionaire dilettantes vs good Democrats: Even the best Democratic candidate is no match for the worst Republican when wealthy "Democratic" donors meddle. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Medieval Times invents a modern union-busting tactic (permalink) In the summer of 2020, I committed a minor heresy: I published a column that argued that – contrary to the orthodoxy of free culture and free software advocates – the term "IP" has a very crisp meaning: "IP" is any law or rule that can be used to contr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2045]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2685/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2685/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/2045.png" title="&quot;Sorry, doctor, I'm going to have to come in on a different day--I have another appointment that would be really hard to move, in terms of the kinetic energy requirements.&quot;" alt="&quot;Sorry, doctor, I'm going to have to come in on a different day--I have another appointment that would be really hard to move, in terms of the kinetic energy requirements.&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 13 Oct 2022 US health insurers get more and more federal funding, deliver less and less care]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4246</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/13/sicko/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-13T12:36:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links US health insurers get more and more federal funding, deliver less and less care: Medicare Advantage will murder your grandparents – and you're next. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: None Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading US health insurers get more and more federal funding, deliver less and less care (permalink) The American healthcare system is the worst of all possible worlds. Unlike every other wealthy country, the US leaves its health insurance to the private sector, where your health and your life are a distant second to shareholder profits. But it's worse, because the majority of the money those terrible, "private" insurance companies "earn" comes from public subsidies. In …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two JavaScripts [blog]]]></title>
        <id>two-javascripts</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/10/13/two-javascripts"/>
        <updated>2022-10-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been looking at enhance.dev and their docs and though I've not tried it in anger yet, I think it's a framework to developing that's leaning on something that's been on my mind: there are two JavaScripts.
One for the server - where you can go wild.
One for the client - that should be thoughtful and careful.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A longtime NPR education reporter on her favorite corners of the internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70044</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/npr-education-reporter-anya-kamenetz/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T13:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post A longtime NPR education reporter on her favorite corners of the internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Road Space Comparison]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2684/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2684/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/road_space_comparison.png" title="I wonder how hard it would be to ride an electric scooter in a hamster ball." alt="I wonder how hard it would be to ride an electric scooter in a hamster ball." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 11 Oct 2022 Trusting (machine learning) trust; The housing market turns (more) toxic]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4237</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/11/rene-descartes-was-a-drunken-fart/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T18:18:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Undetectable, undefendable back-doors for machine learning: IMPNet will give your model hallucination and you can't stop it. Shelter in place: Prison for homelessness and lock-ins for home owners. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: None Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Undetectable, undefendable back-doors for machine learning (permalink) Machine learning's promise is decisions at scale: using software to classify inputs (and, often, act on them) at a speed and scale that would be prohibitively expensive or even impossible using flesh-and-blood humans. There aren't enough idle people to train half of them to read all the tweets in the other half's timeline and put them in ranked or…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protect your privacy and your phone number with Firefox Relay]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=70045</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/privacy-security/hide-your-phone-number-with-firefox-relay/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T16:02:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you share your personal phone number with anyone outside your circle of family and friends, it essentially gives them permission to call you anytime of the day. This can mean robocallers at lunch and dinner, not to mention spam text messages throughout the day.  Think about it: How many times have you shared your […]
The post Protect your privacy and your phone number with Firefox Relay appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A World-Class Code Playground with Sandpack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/next-level-playground/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/next-level-playground/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-11T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No developer blog or technical documentation site is complete without an interactive code playground. The CodeSandbox team recently released a wonderful tool called Sandpack, to help us create these live-updating code editors. In this tutorial, I'll show you how I use it on this blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 10 Oct 2022 Antitrust is – and always has been – about fairness]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4227</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/10/play-fair/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-10T15:43:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Antitrust is – and always has been – about fairness: SCOTUS is entitled to its own (judicial) opinions, but not its own facts. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Antitrust is – and always has been – about fairness (permalink) It's easy to take the Supreme Court's flurry of judicial atrocities as a contemporary phenomenon, but all the way back in 1993, SCOTUS engaged in a historical fantasy that has taken a terrible toll on the American people and American political legitimacy. Long before Citizens United, there was Brooke Group Ltd. v. Brown & Williamson Tobacco Corp: https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/509/209/ It was an an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fan Theories]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2683/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2683/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/fan_theories.png" title="The universe fandom is great. Such sweet and enthusiastic people." alt="The universe fandom is great. Such sweet and enthusiastic people." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 09 Oct 2022 $100 billion later, autonomous vehicles are still a car-wreck]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4222</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/09/herbies-revenge/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-09T19:52:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links $100 billion later, autonomous vehicles are still a car-wreck: The self-driving car fraud was great business for Uber and Tesla. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading $100 billion later, autonomous vehicles are still a car-wreck (permalink) Autonomous vehicles were always a shell-game. The last time I wrote about them was a year ago, when Uber declared massive losses. Uber's profitability story was always, "Sure, we're losing money now, but once we create self-driving cars, we can fire our drivers and make a bundle." https://pluralistic.net/2020/09/30/death-to-all-monopoly/#pogo-stick-problem But Uber never came close to b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Oct 2022 "Don't spy on a privacy lab," and other career advice for university provosts]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4214</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/07/sensory-deprivation/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-07T18:42:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links "Don't spy on a privacy lab" (and other career advice for university provosts): Northeastern grad student vs surveillance-driven austerity. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading "Don't spy on a privacy lab" (and other career advice for university provosts) (permalink) This is a wild and hopeful story: grad students at Northeastern successfully pushed back against invasive digital surveillance in their workplace, through solidarity, fearlessness, and the bright light of publicity. It's a tale of hand-to-hand, victorious combat with the "shitty technology adoption curve." What's the "shitty tech adoption curve?" It's the proc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easy or Hard]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2682/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2682/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/easy_or_hard.png" title="&quot;Friction-driven static electrification is familiar and fundamental in daily life, industry, and technology, but its basics have long been unknown and have continually perplexed scientists from ancient Greece to the high-tech era. [...] To date, no single theory can satisfactorily explain this mysterious but fundamental phenomenon.&quot; --Eui-Cheol Shin et. al. (2022)" alt="&quot;Friction-driven static electrification is familiar and fundamental in daily life, industry, and technology, but its basics have long been unknown and have continually perplexed scientists from ancient Greece to the high-tech era. [...] To date, no single theory can satisfactorily explain this mysterious but fundamental phenomenon.&quot; --Eui-Cheol Shin et. al. (2022)" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unless you’re in the mafia, your company isn’t your family]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7385</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/10/06/unless-youre-in-the-mafia-your-company-isnt-your-family/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-06T22:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dedication to your employer is a tradition in some cultures. My father was a dedicated coal miner and when the mine closed up he became a factory worker. He worked 40+ years in that factory in three shifts. He kept complaining about “those up there” in the hierarchy and yet the company was a big […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI Code completion is like cruise control – and that’s great news for bigger teams]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7364</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/10/05/ai-code-completion-is-like-cruise-control-and-thats-great-news-for-bigger-teams/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T14:43:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When machine learning assisted code completion came around in the form of GitHub CoPilot and the fast-follow Amazon Codewhisperer it was impressive to see just how fast new ideas follow the Gartner Hype Cycle. The first impression was that this would be the end of development as we know it and that it is yet […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Archimedes Principle]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2681/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2681/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/archimedes_principle.png" title="&quot;I've always wanted to run naked through town, but I don't want to get in trouble with the king or be remembered by history as a weirdo. I wonder how I could ... EUREKA!&quot;" alt="&quot;I've always wanted to run naked through town, but I don't want to get in trouble with the king or be remembered by history as a weirdo. I wonder how I could ... EUREKA!&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Oct 2022 An antitrust murder whodunnit]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4200</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/03/powell-memo/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-03T19:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links An antitrust murder whodunnit: I accuse Judge Bork with the Powell Memo in the smoke-filled room. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading An antitrust murder whodunnit (permalink) 40-some years ago, US antitrust enforcement took sick. In the years since, it has been largely comatose – right up until the very recent past, when the Biden administration began to take muscular – but very belated – action to restore a modicum of competition to the economy. There's a widely received narrative about what happened to antitrust law. 40+ years ago, fringe economists and other ideological entrepreneurs from the University of Chicago won…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[State of CSS 2022 now open!]]></title>
        <id>https://lea.verou.me/?p=3511</id>
        <link href="https://lea.verou.me/2022/10/state-of-css-2022-now-open/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-03T15:34:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Take State of CSS 2022 survey A while ago I posted a call for feedback to inform the design of the State of CSS 2022 survey. The response has been overwhelming and it was glorious. We got quite a lot of proposals, feedback, votes. But that also meant we had to make some tough decisions […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lea Verou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battery Life]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2680/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2680/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/battery_life.png" title="It's okay, I'm at 10%, so I'm good for another month or two." alt="It's okay, I'm at 10%, so I'm good for another month or two." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Oct 2022 How Palantir will steal the NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4177</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/10/01/the-palantir-will-see-you-now/"/>
        <updated>2022-10-01T17:18:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How Palantir will steal the NHS: Stealth privatisation was always the endgame for public-private-partnerships. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How Palantir will steal the NHS (permalink) Britons are divided on many matters, but one uniting force that cuts across regional, party and class lines is jealous pride for the NHS and fierce resistance to its privatisation and the importation of America's grisly omnishambolic health care "system." But while the British people oppose privatisation, the British investor class are slavering for it. Oligarchs love to loot public services, which is why the IMF is so adamant that th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of September Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42793</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/09/30/end-of-september-link-assortment-7/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-30T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events The SF Bay IF Meetup will convene again on October 1. This will be a hybrid event, so you can attend in person if you’re in the area, or online if you aren’t. IF Comp games are also scheduled to become available tomorrow, October 1. This annual competition has been running now for nearly … Continue reading "End of September Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantified Self]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2679/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2679/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/quantified_self.png" title="It's made me way more excited about ferris wheels, subways, car washes, waterslides, and store entrances that have double doors with a divider in the middle." alt="It's made me way more excited about ferris wheels, subways, car washes, waterslides, and store entrances that have double doors with a divider in the middle." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 29 Sep 2022 Porn on Tumblr is a complicated subject]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4172</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/09/29/go-nuts-show-nuts/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-29T16:48:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Porn on Tumblr is a complicated subject: Chokepoints, compliance, weakest links. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Porn on Tumblr is a complicated subject (permalink) In 2018, Tumblr announced a ban on "adult content." That call was made by Verizon, Tumblr's erstwhile owner, and to call the resulting mess "a shitshow" is an insult to good, hardworking shitshows all over the world. Verizon enforced this policy with an automated filter, which was charged with analyzing images and categorizing them as "sexual" or "nonsexual." This is risible enough, like asking a computer to sort videos into "virtuous" or "sinful" but that…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Console,…]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7354</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/09/29/dear-console/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-29T14:52:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The browser developer tools Console is so much more than a place to log your messages. It is a way for you to programatically access the currently shown document and window, read out values and change them. On top of that, it has a powerful API of helper methods to make that easier than with […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Sep 2022 Maintaining monopolies with the cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4161</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/09/28/other-peoples-computers/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-28T15:11:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Maintaining monopolies with the cloud: Microsoft, Oracle and other cloud giants use their terms of service to prevent competition. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Maintaining monopolies with the cloud (permalink) Correction: An earlier draft of this article incorrectly stated that John D Rockefeller owned the railroads that shipped product for the Standard Oil Company. In reality, Rockefeller controlled those railroads through bribery and coercion, not an equity stake. I regret the error. "There is no cloud, there is only other people's computers." It's funny because it's true, and the "other people" in this case are rapaci…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wing Lift]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2678/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2678/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/wing_lift.png" title="Once the air from the top passes below the plane of the wing and catches sight of the spooky skulls, it panics, which is the cause of turbulent vortices." alt="Once the air from the top passes below the plane of the wing and catches sight of the spooky skulls, it panics, which is the cause of turbulent vortices." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Sep 2022 Federalist Society v Corporate Personhood]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4156</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/09/27/freeze-peach/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-27T17:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Federalist Society v Corporate Personhood: Corporations don't have First Amendment rights except when they're making political donations, refusing to bake cakes, or blocking birth control. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Federalist Society v Corporate Personhood (permalink) There are lots of cleavage lines between "left" and "right" ("Conservatism consists of exactly one proposition: There must be in-groups whom the law protects but does not bind, alongside out-groups whom the law binds but does not protect" -F. Wilhoit), and here's a crucial one: the left knows its ideology arises from material reality, while the right cla…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developers as an audience is a hard sell – part one “developers are influencers”]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7343</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/09/26/developers-as-an-audience-is-a-hard-sell-part-one-developers-are-influencers/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-26T14:58:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I wrote the developer advocacy handbook and advertised my new role as “Developer Evangelist” to my company one of the main points I made was how developers are an incredibly important audience for any company to covet. Not only do they build your own products, they are also influencers for other people. Developers are […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Key System]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2677/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2677/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/two_key_system.png" title="Our company can be your one-stop shop for decentralization." alt="Our company can be your one-stop shop for decentralization." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[25 Sep 2022 McKinsey and Providence colluded to force poor patients into destitution]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4150</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/09/25/criminal-conspiracy/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-25T18:43:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links McKinsey and Providence colluded to force poor patients into destitution: "How would you like to pay that today?" Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading McKinsey and Providence colluded to force poor patients into destitution (permalink) Providence is a health giant whose anchor is a network of Catholic hospitals. They colluded with McKinsey to steal from their poorest patients, by deceiving them about their eligibility for free care, saddling poor, sick people with crushing debts: https://www.nytimes.com/2022/09/24/business/nonprofit-hospitals-poor-patients.html Though Providence is nominally a nonprofit, but it sits atop a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 24 Sep 2022 Billionare grifters hate her]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4145</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/09/24/shithole-billionaires/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T13:39:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Billionaire grifters hate her: Cometh the Hour, Cometh the Ida M Tarbell. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Billionaire grifters hate her (permalink) A billionaire's crime spree has come to an end: a federal judge held that Fleetcor was running a fraudulent, predatory business, and found that the company's billionaire owner, Ron Clarke, was personally responsible for the company's offenses. He woulda gotten away with it, but for the reporting of a former nurse turned self-trained muckraker: https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-08-11/payments-billionaire-found-to-have-knowingly-deceived-customers The Fleetcor sca…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh yeah... Return To Monkey Island is out]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/rtmi_is_out</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/rtmi_is_out"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Click here!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Historical Dates]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2676/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2676/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/historical_dates.png" title="Evidence suggests the 1899 transactions occurred as part of a global event centered around a deity associated with the lotus flower." alt="Evidence suggests the 1899 transactions occurred as part of a global event centered around a deity associated with the lotus flower." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick reminder: HTML5 required and pattern are not a security feature]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7341</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/09/22/quick-reminder-html5-required-and-pattern-are-not-a-security-feature/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T20:13:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using the required and/or pattern attribute on HTML input elements stops users from submitting forms with invalid values, but you can work around that using the Console tool. In HTML5, you can provide a `required` attribute to ensure a certain field has been filled out before a form can be sent off. I have read […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 22 Sep 2022 Twitch's Chokepoint Capitalism]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4135</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/09/22/amazon-vs-amazon/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Twitch does a chokepoint capitalism: "Amazon is charging Amazon so much money to run the business via Amazon that it has no choice but to take more money from streamers." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Twitch does a chokepoint capitalism (permalink) When Amazon bought Twitch, the story was that the new conglomerate would be more efficient and that would benefit everyone – streamers and audiences. That's the story we hear about every anticompetitive merger, and it's always a lie. One major efficiency that the Amazon-Twitch merger was supposed to produce? Lower bandwidth costs. That's one of the largest expenses associated …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pilot Priority List]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2675/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2675/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/pilot_priority_list.png" title="CELEBRATE: Serve passengers tiered cakes shaped like the airspace class diagram" alt="CELEBRATE: Serve passengers tiered cakes shaped like the airspace class diagram" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 20 Sep 2022 Book-banning wingnuts are a tiny, vocal minority]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4129</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/09/20/the-moral-majority/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-20T12:16:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Book-banning wingnuts are a tiny, vocal minority: The moral majority is neither. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Book-banning wingnuts are a tiny, vocal minority (permalink) "The Moral Majority" is a stupendous marketing gimmick: it allowed a small minority of vicious, paranoid, hateful creeps to brand themselves as a "silent majority" who were all around us, afraid to speak their minds. The impact of this wasn't merely in convincing politicians and the press that the views of these unhinged, fringe conspiratorialists should be taken seriously – just as important is the zap it put on the heads of their enemies, the people w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 19 Sep 2022 How to ditch Facebook without ditching your friends]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=4125</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/09/19/interoperable-facebook/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-19T17:43:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How to ditch Facebook without ditching your friends: A new interop design fiction from EFF. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How to ditch Facebook without ditching your friends (permalink) Facebook users claim to hate the service, but they keep using it, leading many to describe Facebook as "addictive." But there's a simpler explanation: people keep using Facebook though they hate it because they don't want to lose their connections to the people they love. Calling Facebook "addictive" plays into the company's own mythology, the sales-pitch they make to advertisers, in which they claim to be neuro-sorcerers whose mastery of …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyday Carry]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2674/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2674/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/everyday_carry.png" title="Someday I just know I'm going to encounter a problem that requires 500 flashlights and 700 knives with weird holes in them, and on that day I won't be caught unprepared." alt="Someday I just know I'm going to encounter a problem that requires 500 flashlights and 700 knives with weird holes in them, and on that day I won't be caught unprepared." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discussing two "holy war" topics at the same time]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-17T23:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cutting to the chase: text editors *and* tabs vs. spaces!  Ooooh!


I've had this thing called "e" for a while now.  It's a stupid little 
script which serves to do a couple of things.  It starts my 
editor
with a given file, and it kicks it with the right arguments to make it 
disable line wrapping and to make the [TAB] key actually put in two 
spaces.


So, my dumb script would use "-w -E -T 2" most of the time, except when it 
was running on a Makefile, at which point it would skip those args.  
Simple enough, right?


pico is back?  Yes indeed, on Macs, as of 12.3, pico is in fact back.  To 
make sure I wasn't imagining things, I tracked down a machine that hadn't 
been upgraded yet and checked there.  Sure enough, it was in fact nano and 
not pico.


macOS 12.3 has nano as a symlink... pointing to pico!


At some point, I switched from literal tab characters in my source code to 
blobs of spaces, probably due to using that style at work and not hating 
it.  So, somewhere along the line I actually started depending on nano 
behavior without realizing it.


As for the lack of a feature in pico itself, it's kind of strange, really.  
If you go digging into the source, they have this random.c with a function 
called tab which claims to "simulate tab stop" using spaces.  That said, I 
can't find any place where it would be called with the magic values which 
would make it behave that way.


It wouldn't surprise me if this switch is just more of Apple removing 
GPLed things from their OS - pico seems to use the Apache license.  They 
dumped bash for zsh (MIT license) at some point (Big Sur, I think), and 
now this?  Okay then.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dumb things you can sometimes do with hard links]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-16T01:51:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a very old and stupid trick you could do with some filesystems in 
some situations back in the day... and might still be able to do in a 
few places today.


The problem is that while version X might eventually have an exploit, 
it'll get removed and it'll be replaced by version Y without that
particular hole.  By the time you get your hands on a tool to break into 
X, it'll be gone.


What you'd do is create a hard link pointing at the file you wanted to 
preserve, storing it in a spot which was writable by your account.  
Then, say, /usr/bin/sudo (because that never has security 
issues...) gets replaced at some point with a new file and you get to 
keep the old version.  When you get the tool to pop it, off you go!


Of course, these days, it's not quite so easy on the more modern systems 
you find.  Debian 11 here won't let me do it - it's EPERM city.  Rocky 8 
(so CentOS 8 and RHEL 8 too) also won't do it.  They both have some gunk
in /usr/lib/sysctl.d to lock this down.  But, my old Slackware 14.2 
install of my workstation let me do it the last time I tried about 
a year ago.  How about that, huh?  I bet it'd still work if I dug out 
the old drives and booted them up.


Incidentally, this is the magic sauce: /proc/sys/fs/protected_hardlinks
Read the man page for proc(5) to learn more about it.

here it is,
the thread I read a long time ago.  It's interesting to note that as far 
as I can tell, nothing actually changed upstream.  This left paranoid 
admins like me with no option but to use the (most excellent) Openwall 
patches to lock down this kind of stuff.  I used that on my machines at 
work which had non-staff users... just in case.


This whole situation is scary.  
Read more about it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More stories about stacks of modems]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-14T23:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in January, you might have seen my
post
about a very large BBS which seemed to solve for the problem of "how do 
we host a bunch of users" by having one physical box per user.  It might 
have been one physical box per *two* users, maybe, but it's hard to say.


Now, keep in mind digital cameras weren't easy to come by, so I have 
very few actual pictures.  I'll have to do a lot of explaining to make 
up for the lack of detail and alternate angles.  Clearly, I had no 
notion of ever using these pictures to tell stories 25+ years later.


Some friends at a local company had some bandwidth to spare (a T1 to 
Alternet somewhere, as I recall), so they parked a Zoom modem on one of 
their boxes and plugged it into a phone line.  We got an identical model 
to avoid cross-brand issues (Zoom m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking away the berries]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-13T02:14:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I sometimes write the beginnings of posts but don't post them.  I still 
save them in case conditions change or other things happen and make me 
want to follow up on the topic.  In this case, I wrote something about 
offices before the whole COVID lockdown thing happened and people 
largely stopped going to offices every day.  With that in mind, let's 
proceed.


However, tech companies decided to go past this at some point and 
brought about this whole notion of "microkitchens".  This is where 
they'd put their branding on the coolers (instead of "Coca-Cola" or 
"Pepsi") and would load it up with every kind of fizzy sugary liquid 
they could get their hands on.  They'd have racks and racks of shelving 
packed with all sorts of interesting crunchy, sugary and carb-loaded 
snacks.  They'd a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at the outlying data points]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T07:04:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the fun things I used to do at a prior job was to dig through the 
raw data points which were collected from the *many* servers we had.  I 
could just pick an interesting-sounding metric and then would just ask 
the system to show me the top 10 or bottom 10 out of a population of 
thousands or more.


To get my feet wet with the whole "investigations" thing that we'd do, I 
started looking into this one day and chose one of the many temp sensors 
which were being logged by the servers.  I forget exactly which one it 
was, for there were many.  The CPUs logged it, the chassis logged it, 
the power supply logged it, and so on.  There were so many choices.


I went looking for a reason.  What could possibly explain this?  First 
off, it didn't line up with any obvious pattern in the host names.  The 
hosts were named for whichever team owned them, followed by a sequence 
number that was bumped any time a new one was provisioned.  There was no 
signal to be found in that.


There was more, though.  You could also see a "rack position" in this 
data, and now it started getting interesting.  It seems that all of the 
really hot machines had a rack position of something low, like 04 or 05, 
and never anything higher than that.  In fact, when looking at a whole 
rack, it was always the lowest number of all of the positions that were 
being used.  Now this was worth chasing!


It's good that I asked, since they told me something surprising: 
position 04 or 05 or whatever was the *bottom* of the rack.  Yes, 
somehow, the lowest machine in the rack was the hottest!  They found 
this interesting, too, and wound up digging into it.  Given that I was 
far away in a distant office, this was the best way for us to proceed.


The problem was that the bottommost server would have nothing below it 
but just open space until it got to the floor.  That space would not 
move air efficiently, and it obviously mattered.


This rolled out and my hot spots disappeared.  Fantastic!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Questions about construction trucks on train tracks]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T01:26:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another day, another bit of local flavor, but this time it's something I 
wish I didn't have to write about.

wrote
about seeing a maintenance truck rolling down the Caltrain line in 
Mountain View.  It had a special attachment to let it stay on the rails.  
At no point did the arms come down for the crossing.  It managed to 
approach, then the people inside looked around and went through, and the 
arms never budged.  There were no flashing lights or bells.




caught fire.  A bunch of people were hurt.  More were shaken 
up.


I'm assuming their construction trucks don't trigger the "short the 
rails together to signal various things" logic, either.  This would 
mean that crossing arms stay up... and I have to assume it also means 
the signals along the way stay green instead of going red.

We will presumably hear more about whatever the signals said, and 
whether the train went past a red signal or not.  I just have a bad 
feeling that they saw a green and kept on going.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toll signs on 101 report your transponder setting]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-10T03:50:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a little bit of Silicon Valley local flavor for a change.  We 
have this freeway that runs from San Jose to San Francisco called US 
101, or around here, just "101".  (Southern California has it too, but 
they call it "the" 101.  That's how we detect invaders.)  Anyway, this 
thing is usually eight or more lanes up and down the peninsula, and it's 
had a "diamond" or car pool lane on the #1 (innermost/"fast") lane for 
many years.  You had to have a certain number of people in the car (or 
some other conditions met) during certain hours (AM and PM rush, 
weekdays), or you'd be in for a hefty ticket.


How does the system know what to charge you?  Well, you either have an 
old-style toll transponder that always bills you as a solo driver, or 
you have a new-style transponder with a 1/2/3+ switch that tells the 
road how to handle you.


Think about what this does to enforcement.  Now, instead of just "is 
there a vehicle in the lane", "is it the right time during a weekday", 
and "how many people are in the car", now it's also a matter of "do they 
have their transponder set properly".


Check this out.



CHP
could roll up on them and give them a ticket.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A parasitic RPC service that broke core dumps]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T04:39:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I already told a
story
about how you can hose your machine by pointing the Linux kernel at a 
custom core dump handler and then have that handler fail to function.  
This'll clog up the pipe (really), and then everything else will just 
stack up behind it.  Pretty soon, every crashing process will be stuck 
just the same.


Once upon a time, in a big company environment, someone decided that 
they wanted to provide a service to other things running on the same 
Linux box.  But, instead of either writing Yet Another Service (tm) 
that would go through release processes and all of that good stuff, they 
went for a different design entirely.


There are so many problems with this.  You have the issue of a "server" 
that appears out of thin air depending on who or what starts first on 
the mac…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A sysadmin's rant about feed readers and crawlers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-08T17:49:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If a web site makes an RSS or Atom feed available, it's not a bad idea 
to poll it from time to time.  Actually doing that poll like a good 
netizen (remember that concept?) takes a little attention to detail.


Given the reality of the situation, does it make sense to poll every 10 
seconds?  Probably not, right?  Someone set up something like that and 
left it running for a couple of months until I finally noticed it and 
dealt with it myself.


Given this, you can keep track of the "Last-Modified" header when you 
get a copy of the feed.  Then, you can turn around and use that same 
value in an "If-Modified-Since" header the next time you come to look 
for an update.  If nothing's changed, the web server will notice it's 
the same as what it already has, and it'll send you a HTTP 304 co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editing stuff in prod]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-05T21:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a concept: "ssh to prod and edit directly on the machine" is 
generally bad news.


I should point out that I didn't know this person and had no idea how 
they would respond to such feedback - it might have been fine!  They 
might be a well-adjusted person who can take a request like that and not 
turn it around into a full-on nuclear attack.  But, I didn't know either 
way.


At some point, I actually had a meeting with this developer for some 
other reason, and what happened was kind of amazing.  First thing, he 
brought it up and asked me about it.  I said something like, "well, I 
didn't want to get into it, but since you asked", and proceeded into 
something along the lines of "obviously it would be best if you didn't 
do that - sshing in and twiddling Python files on the actual production 
AWS instance of the service".


"But... I suspect you are doing it for some reason?"


My response was... I hope... reasonable: "So as much as I would love to 
say 'don't do that!!!', I'm not going to stand in the way of you 
literally doing your job.  So please proceed with care, and keep an eye 
open for some day when (first dumb thing) and (second dumb thing) aren't 
problems any more and you need not do this any more."


It was either "edit in prod" or endure DAY LONG development cycles: make 
a change, wait 24 hours, come back tomorrow, and try it again.  That's 
how broken it was.


The best part about this was that we had a totally reasonable 
conversation about it.  It's the kind of thing which had become a rare 
commodity in those days at that place.


Would I expect someone else to go to that level of insanity every single 
time they just want to get their job done?  Absolutely not.

Editing files in prod to develop them?  That's bad news.  Deliberately 
rigging tunnels to spoof a connection from prod?  That's also bad news.  
Having to do them to get your job done?  You might be in the bad place.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's now your fault they don't know about it]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-04T00:14:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quite a while back, I wrote a post that basically went like this: if 
someone has a problem with someone else or something that person is 
doing, they're going to find a way to get to "no".  They will find some 
reason, some excuse, or some problem with it.  They'll bring up a point 
and you'll show that this is not in fact a thing.  They will then pivot 
again and again.


But, as I said, that was back then, and this time I'm talking about 
something else: when it happens in person with a coworker.  I had an 
experience like this a few years back, and figured I'd share how it goes 
for the sake of others who might not have encountered it yet, or who 
have and thought they were alone in this.


Coworker: There are no docs for [this thing you're doing].


Coworker: You could make a wiki pag…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universally unique identifier?  Sometimes...]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-02T03:44:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a short one since it's somewhere between a random bit of 
"grab some popcorn" amusement and a "huh, that might be a problem some 
day".  In short, it looks like every Raspberry Pi filesystem installed 
from any given release image probably ends up with the same
UUID.


For instance, if you downloaded the "lite" version of Raspbian between 
roughly November 8th and January 28th, you probably got a file called 
2021-10-30-raspios-bullseye-armhf-lite.zip.  Inside, there's an image, 
and the idea is that you dump that straight to your SD card, cram it in 
the Pi, and off you go.  The second partition on that image is an ext4 
filesystem which was created on some build machine somewhere.  The UUID 
on it never gets "evolved" to something else after the install.


You can see it inside the image itself here:


Or, if you actually installed a few of these things like I did over the 
past couple of months, you can just 'tune2fs -l /dev/mmcblk0p2' and see 
the same value in there.


Don't end up with a pile of SD cards on your desk and think "I know, 
I'll use the filesystem UUIDs to track which one goes where", in other 
words.


If it's not breaking anything for you, it's probably best to just let it 
be.  Untangling a boot mess on these weird little boxes is anything but 
fun.

Note: if you're actually on a recent Raspberry Pi, odds are good that 
your /etc/fstab will be using *partition* UUIDs (PARTUUID=...) and not 
those of the filesystem.  If in doubt, use blkid to see what's what.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Command-V (or CTRL-V) is your "copilot"]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-28T22:54:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A reader wrote in asking what I thought about the whole GitHub "copilot" 
thing.  If you haven't heard of it yet, it's apparently this thing that 
was trained on a whole mess of repositories and their code, and you can 
"prompt" it and it'll spit out code that may or may not do what you 
want.  It doesn't seem to know about licensing (BSD, GPL, MIT, that sort 
of thing), or plagiarism, or any of that other good stuff.


This is actually a story about somewhere I used to work, and someone who 
was on one of my teams back in the day.  One day, I heard that one of 
the people in a far-away office had created some kind of tool that would 
let you look at the status of different machines - that is, Linux boxes. 
I don't remember the finer points of it or why this person even 
bothered, but they…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[C++ header files and inter-class connections]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-27T11:35:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are some interesting implications to the way that you have to 
handle references to other bits of code when you write a C++ header 
file.  There are things you can do which turn out to be suboptimal, and 
until or unless you work someplace with a coding style document or get 
some mentor who's already been there, you're likely to make some
mistakes.


Anyway, a common way to do this is to set up the outer class such that 
it has a pointer to the inner one.  You *could* have it just own it 
directly, but then that introduces problems.



 private:
  Bar bar_;



Of course, bar.h probably has its own dependencies which get #included, 
and so now you end up with this evil web of slow compiles.  It sucks.


What used to happen next is that someone would say, okay, let's make it 
a pointe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Results without all of the brackets]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-22T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, I
put forth
a bunch of API possibilities for the problem of needing to return a 
value but also indicating the lack of a value and being able to comment 
on why.  In it, the notion of a "wrapper" around a string was presented, 
such that it might look like "Result<string>", and those brackets 
started looking like a pain.  There was also the possibility of having 
something like "ResultString", but didn't that open the door to having a 
bunch of code duplication?


After this had existed for a while, the general happy feeling of having 
this stuff in place became infectious.  I wanted it to cover other 
things with it, too.  I wanted it to handle something a bit more 
complicated than a mere string, and so decided to try my hand at the 
template-wrangling metaprogramming cruft t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Returning values and errors]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-20T21:33:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you agree with the notion that you need to be able to tell the 
difference between the absence of a value and a value itself, then this 
has some impacts on the code you write.  If you want to keep 'em 
separated (so they can come out and play), then it gets you looking at 
your API designs in certain ways.


Imagine we're talking about a helper function that is intended to be run 
inside a program that's handling the access to a web page.  It's 
probably a CGI program, but it could also be buried inside some much 
bigger thing, too.  This is all about C++ styles, but you can probably 
see slices of other languages in here, too.


string UserIP() -- No more lifetime worries here, but oops, uh, well, 
what if we don't know what it is and need to provide an error?  If it's 
a CGI situatio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My "daily drivers", and what happened to Slackware here]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T21:48:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In
yesterday's post,
I mentioned taking my old Mac Mini out of the OS X/macos ecosystem and 
bringing it into Debian, and then what kind of hilarity followed when I 
attempted to install a Javascript linter (and it tried to drag in 180+ 
node-related packages).


Readers are advised that this post will probably contain 
definitely contains a even higher than usual amount of 
navel-gazing as I dish out the details of my setup.  My usual 
disclaimer of "this works for me and probably won't work for you, so if 
you have different tastes, then great, go with that" definitely applies 
here.


First of all, the one that most people actually notice is the actual box 
which is serving rachelbythebay.com, which at the moment is a box called 
snowgoose.  I had installed it in early 2020 as CentOS 8 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A twisted maze of dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T03:07:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh sure, everyone laughs about things having a lot of dependencies, but 
do they ever really think about the implications of having hundreds of 
teeny little libraries, all moving independently?  This is how it 
manifests in the real world.


My relative inexperience with Debian systems means I'm constantly being 
delighted to discover that such and such has already been packaged up 
and is just an apt command away.  Things that I would have done by hand 
in the years up to this point now have someone else worrying about them.


This is what happened next:


... huh.  The story basically ends there.  I'm going to handle this some 
other way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add 4740180 to the list of silly magic numbers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T08:11:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh dear.  The software fungus where bits of code take the
literal characters "HTTP" as a number
has expanded.  Now it has a variant: 4740180.


Where does this one come from?  
Go and gRPC, apparently!


I found this while searching the web for "1213486160" to see how things 
have been going in the past few years.  Unfortunately, it's still biting 
people all over the place.  There are far too many posts asking people 
to upgrade their software, or restart things, or do any number of 
useless rubber-chicken-waving techniques which ultimately will 
accomplish nothing.

When you see a funny-looking number, figure out where it comes from.
That's the only way to have any chance of understanding what's actually 
going on.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feedback: environments, old BBSes, Honda's 2022 bug]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T23:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yep, it's time for another round of reader feedback.

"process infection" story:

https://lwn.net/Articles/883547/):


If you do privileged execution of specific operations via IPC you get 
the guarantee that whatever is done, is done from a well-defined, 
pristine execution environment, without leaking context implicitly. The 
IPC message is the *full* vulnerable surface, and that's as minimal as 
it can get. And that's great.




Oh wow, thank you for mentioning that, unnamed reader!  I definitely 
read that post on LWN at some point in the past couple of days when the 
pkexec thing started going around.  It must have really worked its way 
into my head, and then eventually stirred up the memory of everything 
getting "nicely infected" at $OLD_JOB.


Every time I talk about trying to par…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A nice story about Unix processes "infecting" each other]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T19:24:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I once worked at a place that had an interesting little problem stemming 
from the way they managed machines and some of the fun side-effects 
processes can have on each other.  This is back in the pre-systemd days 
of running services, such that things tended to be started or restarted 
by someone or something that itself ran as root.  That is, if you 
started something, it might inherit one or more things from your 
environment.  Likewise, if you ran something with an unusual 
environment, it might bestow those "gifts" onto anything it happened to 
touch.


After locking themselves out of machines too many times, people 
generally learned that after you mess with a glibc upgrade, you restart 
the sshd listener on port 22.  Of course, they also had to learn to not 
whack EVERY sshd at the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An old photo of a very large BBS]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 30 years ago, I was given this picture.  I wanted to present it 
in a post all by itself to give it a chance to "sink in" before I went 
and used it in an analogy.  First, I'll just show the image and explain 
what you're looking at here.




I do remember the description from the back: this is a picture of *part 
of* something that was called the Software Creations BBS.  It was a 
multi-line bulletin board system where you could dial up and send 
messages to people, upload and download files, and (presumably) play 
online games ("doors") and anything else they cared to offer.

64 machines in a little space.  I have to assume 
they are at least 
286s (ATs, more or 
less), but it's impossible to tell from just this picture.  They could 
have been 386s or even 486s by that point, but …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One machine can go pretty far if you build things properly]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, so yesterday I 
posted
a picture of an old multi-line bulletin board system which had 
apparently taken over an entire bedroom with dozens of computers.  I 
mentioned that I intended to come back to the topic to throw in my own 
two cents, and so here we go.


Or, were you someone who found it horrific and wished there was a 
simpler way?  Did you wonder if it would be possible to pack all of that 
into one or maybe two boxes, instead?  Did you want a way to negate all 
of that complexity while still providing the same level of service?


Now, things are different.  I look at that and just sigh at the lost 
opportunities.  The actual amount of work being done on behalf of any of 
the users who are connected is tiny.  If we ignore the fact that the 
actual BBS software and related acc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>