<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html</id>
    <title>Ajour / Spitlo.com</title>
    <updated>2022-06-05T00:39:01.334Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.14.4</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trevor Project’s Kevin Wong Shares What’s In His Corner of the Internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69069</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/pride-month/trevor-projects-kevin-wong-shares-whats-in-his-corner-of-the-internet/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T19:55:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Trevor Project’s Kevin Wong Shares What’s In His Corner of the Internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3714</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/03/gambling-home/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T17:54:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links House sales are cratering but inventory is soaring: You are the sucker at the table. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading House sales are cratering but inventory is soaring (permalink) When I moved to the UK in the early 2000s, nearly everyone I met fancied themselves a real-estate investment genius. Young people all had plans to "get on the housing ladder." Each of these schemes was more crackpot than the last – the most plausible involved buying minuscule flats, "doing them up," and flipping them. The weirder ones involved buying unbuilt holiday homes in Spain or Croatia – places these people couldn't afford to visit, es…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Motion Blur]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2628/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2628/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/motion_blur.png" title="I can't speak for your other subjects, but MY motion was as smooth and natural as the framerate allowed." alt="I can't speak for your other subjects, but MY motion was as smooth and natural as the framerate allowed." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Jun 2022 (supplemental)]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3720</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/02/residential-casino/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T18:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NB: This duplicate post exists solely to correct a broken Twitter link Today's links House sales are cratering but inventory is soaring: You are the sucker at the table. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading House sales are cratering but inventory is soaring (permalink) When I moved to the UK in the early 2000s, nearly everyone I met fancied themselves a real-estate investment genius. Young people all had plans to "get on the housing ladder." Each of these schemes was more crackpot than the last – the most plausible involved buying minuscule flats, "doing them up," and flipping them. The weirder ones involved buying unbuilt holiday homes…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social media’s ‘Doomscrolling Reminder Lady’ on her favorite corners of the internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69042</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/interviews/karen-ho-twitter-doomscrolling-reminder-lady/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T15:55:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post Social media’s ‘Doomscrolling Reminder Lady’ on her favorite corners of the internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla releases local machine translation tools as part of Project Bergamot]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69082</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/local-translation-add-on-project-bergamot/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T15:23:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In January of 2019, Mozilla joined the University of Edinburgh, Charles University, University of Sheffield and University of Tartu as part of a project funded by the European Union called Project Bergamot. The ultimate goal of this consortium was to build a set of neural machine translation tools that would enable Mozilla to develop a […]
The post Mozilla releases local machine translation tools as part of Project Bergamot appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Jun 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3702</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/06/01/factories-to-condos-pipeline/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T16:16:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Inflation is caused by too little capacity: Not too much money. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Inflation is caused by too little capacity (permalink) Inflation is here, and there are a lot of explanations for it. People who worry about the monetary supply – especially people in the deflation-loving cryptocurrency world – blame it on excessive money creation during the pandemic and uppity workers demanding higher wages: https://www.businessinsider.com/elon-musk-remote-work-makes-you-less-productive-wrong-2022-6 Anti-monopolists blame inflation on price-gouging. This is a persuasive argument. After all, CEOs of compani…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Abusing you was by the book” (documenting two years of abuse from Game Journalism, after sharing my #metoo… the whole painful story all in one place)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5386</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/abusing-you-was-by-the-book-documenting-two-years-of-abuse-from-game-journalism-after-sharing-my-metoo-the-whole-painful-story-all-in-one-place"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T08:09:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been about a full year since the Kotaku article that exploited my sexual assault, and exploited the other victims of my rapist, has been removed. A full year since I had to argue with journalists for my life, and trying to show them the extent of the harm this has caused. I am told that what I achieved was “unprecedented” (I hate that word). That articles don’t get removed without lawyers, this, that, or the other fancy thing only rich or powerful people have. Nevertheless, I don’t feel victorious. I feel burned out, abused, laughed at, and alienated....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for May]]></title>
        <id>log.html#may2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#may2022"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of May. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Combinatory Logic, wrote a guide to combinatory logic, using talking birds.
, released a linter, and optimized uxnasm.
Dexe, released an updated version.
100r.co, added batteries, and regulator.
News
From this month until next October, our updates may be delayed. We are sailing northward, towards Desolation Sound and the Broughtons, where cell towers are few. We will wander in and out of such regions all summer. So far, we sailed up to the Gulf Islands, and over to Nanaimo from Victoria, and then crossed the Strait of Georgia over to the Sunshine Coast(close-reaching in 20-knot winds). This was a good shakedown for Pino, a good way to re-awaken our little vessel. All went well, but we ought to have secured our produce better... some of our potatoes escaped their nest and went out for an afternoon roll around the cabin floor.
Start of May, we had some issues with our batteries. They've been acting out for some time, we think because of a dead cell. We have been operating at half battery capacity for a month, and realized that yet again we don't need that much power, especially in the summer when the days are long.
The combinatory logic guide is the first of many projects we plan to release this summer. We also released an sign language version of Uxntal.
In other news, a version of Collapse OS was ported to Uxn.
Pino book club
We're reading Watership Down by Richard Adams.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Types of Scopes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2627/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2627/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/types_of_scopes.png" title="An x-ray gyroscope is used to determine exactly which toppings they included in the pita." alt="An x-ray gyroscope is used to determine exactly which toppings they included in the pita." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of May Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42708</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/05/31/end-of-may-link-assortment-8/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T17:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events June 4 is the next meeting of the SF Bay IF Meetup. June 5 is the next meeting of the Seattle IF group, 2-4 PM PDT. Narrascope registrations are now open for July 30-31: the event is low-cost and remote, and features speakers on many aspects of interactive narrative. Releases Hannah Nicklin’s Writing for … Continue reading "End of May Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marketing our privacy products while preserving privacy]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=69067</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/mozilla-vpn/marketing-our-privacy-products-while-preserving-privacy/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T16:22:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When we launched Mozilla VPN, a fast and easy-to-use VPN, it was in a market crowded by companies making promises about privacy and security and we believed our reputation for building products that help you keep your information safe would make our product stand-out. To date, tens of thousands of people have signed up to […]
The post Marketing our privacy products while preserving privacy  appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenifer Boscacci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 31 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3697</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/31/dealers-choice/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T15:10:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How John Deere leverages repair-blocking into gag orders: A farmer's only local dealership refuses to fix his tractor because he advocates for Right to Repair. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How John Deere leverages repair-blocking into gag orders (permalink) John Deere is justifiably notorious for its campaign to block farmers from fixing their own agricultural equipment. The company is #RightToRepair's archnemesis, and no amount of misleading feel-good stories about how it keeps its heavy hand on farmers' tractors forever can change that. https://doctorow.medium.com/about-those-kill-switched-ukrainian-tractors-bc93f471b9c8 The…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do we have a lack of developers or a false assumption what the job is?]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7259</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/31/do-we-have-a-lack-of-developers-or-a-false-assumption-what-the-job-is/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T10:03:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week I was at build Europe and talked to a lot of people about the developer market. The general consensus was that there is a huge lack of developers to hire. That there is not enough talent. When I poked further and asked about how people assess talent, it boiled down to people having […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3692</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/30/80-lbs/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T19:18:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Apple's Cement Overshoes": Thinking different about right to repair. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Apple's Cement Overshoes" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my recent Medium column, "Apple's Cement Overshoes," about the incredible, cynical fuckery that Apple engages in to sabotage right to repair and ensure that its devices end up in overseas e-waste landfills rather than being fixed and kept in service. https://doctorow.medium.com/apples-cement-overshoes-329856288d13 For all the debate around Right to Repair, it's amazing how simple the actual issue is. On the anti- side, you have comp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[d65536]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2626/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2626/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/d65536.png" title="They're robust against quantum attacks because it's hard to make a quantum system that large." alt="They're robust against quantum attacks because it's hard to make a quantum system that large." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3684</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/27/voluntary-carbon-market/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T16:35:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Wework founder raises $70m for blockchain-based, "voluntary" carbon credits: It's a scam matrioshka. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: None Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Wework founder raises $70m for blockchain-based, "voluntary" carbon credits (permalink) Even crypto's biggest boosters admit that the industry has a scam problem. This is especially hard to deny now that hundred of billions of (real) dollars' worth of (fake) "stablecoins" have gone up in smoke. Crypto apologists will tell you that there are scams everywhere, and they're not wrong. The productive economy has been systematic dismantled and replaced with financialized grifts: private equity, REITs, SPACs, MLMs, ad…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What people think that web developers do vs. what we really do]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7256</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/27/what-people-think-that-web-developers-do-vs-what-we-really-do/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T09:09:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What people think web developers do: Code, deploy and use, with coding being the main task What web developers really do: Coding Require random 3rd party framework code Updating Node/NPM Try the last command again with `sudo` Checking on mobile Shaking fist towards Cupertino Looking things up on the web Pasting Stack Overflow solutions Resize […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Field Topology]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2625/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2625/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/field_topology.png" title="The combination croquet set/10-lane pool can also be used for some varieties of foosball and Skee-Ball." alt="The combination croquet set/10-lane pool can also be used for some varieties of foosball and Skee-Ball." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 26 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3680</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/26/initialization-bias/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T10:41:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Attacking machine learning training by re-ordering data: Boy it's hard to audit an AI. This day in history: 2012, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Attacking machine learning training by re-ordering data (permalink) We have increasingly outsourced our decision-making to machine learning models ("the algorithm"). The whole point of building recommendation, sorting, and "decision support" systems on ML is to undertake assessments at superhuman speed and scale, which means that the idea of a "human in the loop" who validates machine judgment is a mere figleaf, and it only gets worse from here. There are real consequences to this. I mean, for starters, if you get killed by a US military drone, chances are th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A teleprompter script for video recordings]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7253</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/25/a-teleprompter-script-for-video-recordings/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T21:03:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Currently I am recording a lot of videos and I found the fastest way to do them is to write the script and read it out to my camera and then record screencasts and edit them to fit the narration. In order to make sure I read from the top of the screen and reading […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 25 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3667</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/25/the-wild-places/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T11:56:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Talking with Kim Stanley Robinson about "The High Sierra": An interview for Fatherly Magazine. Kim Stanley Robinson's "The High Sierra": A love story. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Talking with Kim Stanley Robinson about "The High Sierra" (permalink) This month, the great Kim Stanley Robinson published "The High Sierra," an odd combination of memoir, natural history, mountaineering guidebook, and environmental manifesto. At one point, Robinson told me it would be his last book. Thankfully, he changed his mind, but I can see why he'd think of this as a career capstone. https://www.littlebrown.com/titles/kim-stanley-robinso…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Return to Monkey Island Dev Diary]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/dev_diary</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/dev_diary"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jul 17, 2020
First official day is Monday but I've started setting up Slack and other web services.
Jul 18, 2020
Ordered Linux machine. Talked to Dave about maybe controlling Elaine for a section of the game.  
Starting to worry about finding great people. It's going to be hard because we have to keep the project a secret.
Played MI1 again. Taking a lot of notes about what made MI MI.  After TWP and fast walk and other almost invisible improvements, it's painful to play a 35 year-old adventure game.
I was surprised at how many objects didn't have custom default responses. A large number of objects just said "That doesn't seem to work."
Jul 19, 2020
Played MI again.
Jul 20, 2020
Working with the lawyer to get contractor contracts done that conform to Disney's requirements. Taking longer than I thought.
Hope to get Dave's contract done by tomorrow.
Jul 23, 2020
First "real" design meeting with dave.  Laying down the backbone puzzles for Act 1.
Jul 24, 2020
Started the Puzzle Dependency Chart for Act 1.
Jul 27, 2020
Jenn started
Jul 28, 2020
Making good progress on design.  I know we'll slow down when we have to do all the details.  Looking forward to getting a concept artist.  Things come alive for me when concepts start to come in.
Nov 17, 2020
Starting up diary again... maybe I'll be able to keep it going this time.
Thinking about the ui. I hate the current status-quo.
Nov 18, 2020
Meeting with Disney.
May 25, 2022
Yep, this dev diary didn't last long.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voyager Wires]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2624/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2624/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/voyager_wires.png" title="Also, they're getting increasingly worried that someone will accidentally hit the 'retract' button, and that the end of the cable thrashing around as it winds up could devastate the Earth's surface." alt="Also, they're getting increasingly worried that someone will accidentally hit the 'retract' button, and that the end of the cable thrashing around as it winds up could devastate the Earth's surface." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 24 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3661</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/24/moral-money/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T14:24:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links HSBC: "Who cares if Miami is underwater?": Scenes from the "Moral Money Summit." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading HSBC: "Who cares if Miami is underwater?" (permalink) Before I tell you about how HSBC just announced it wants to literally render the planet Earth unfit for human habitation, I want to talk about HSBC's other crimes. Remember the LIBOR scandal? HSBC was neck-deep in it, costing the world's public coffers trillions through fraud? https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-05-23/banks-are-ordered-by-court-to-defend-libor-antitrust-lawsuit HSBC used laundered money from the world's most corrupt people to cash out on it…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 23 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3656</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/23/you-got-spacced/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T15:50:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links SPACs were hugely successful (for banks): But you lost your shirt. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading SPACs were hugely successful (for banks) (permalink) Remember SPACs? For a while, you couldn't turn around without hearing about a celeb who was backing a "blank check" IPO. It was confusing, because SPACs don't make any sense: you buy into a company at $10/share. The company has no business, no products, nothing. But it plans on going public, and then buying another company. In theory, you're betting that some celebrity-endorsed randos will take all the $10 share buy-ins and use the money to buy another company – a comp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goofs]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2623/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2623/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/goofs.png" title="The film is set in 2018, but when Commander Bremberly chases the hologram through Times Square, there's a billboard for Avengers: Age of Ultron. Depending on the date, that billboard would have been advertising either Infinity War or this movie." alt="The film is set in 2018, but when Commander Bremberly chases the hologram through Times Square, there's a billboard for Avengers: Age of Ultron. Depending on the date, that billboard would have been advertising either Infinity War or this movie." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 20 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3652</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/20/self-destruct-button/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T17:05:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "About Those Killswitched Ukrainian Tractors": Good spaceships don't have self-destruct buttons. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "About Those Killswitched Ukrainian Tractors" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my Medium column, "About Those Killswitched Ukrainian Tractors," in which I am a bit of a buzzkill about that feel-good story of a Ukrainian John Deere dealership bricking $5m worth of tractors stolen by Russian looters: https://doctorow.medium.com/about-those-kill-switched-ukrainian-tractors-bc93f471b9c8 In case you missed the underlying story, here's a quick recap. Russian looters, abetted by the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Presents: A YouTube creator blending femininity and engineering]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68990</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/xyla-foxlin-youtube-engineering/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T15:44:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being feminine and having technical skills are not mutually exclusive. This should be obvious, but Xyla Foxlin has had to work hard to prove femininity and engineering can go hand in hand. While in college, she started a YouTube channel called Beauty and the Bolt, where she co-produced tutorials on STEM topics like electronics, math […]
The post Firefox Presents: A YouTube creator blending femininity and engineering appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angular Diameter Turnaround]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2622/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2622/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/angular_diameter_turnaround.png" title="Thank you to Katie Mack for teaching me about this effect, and to Janelle Shane for describing redshifts as 'like galaxies sinking into a pool of dilute blood,' which is how I'll see them from now on." alt="Thank you to Katie Mack for teaching me about this effect, and to Janelle Shane for describing redshifts as 'like galaxies sinking into a pool of dilute blood,' which is how I'll see them from now on." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global Accessbility Awareness Day – Does your web product support the needs of the many?]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7249</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/19/global-accessbility-awareness-day-does-your-web-product-support-the-needs-of-the-many/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T17:07:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You never create one product on the web – you create a product that people can change to their needs. At least you should. I’ve been working on the web since 1997 and one thing I realised early on is a big basic idea of the web: You do not control how your web product […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 19 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3641</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/19/the-weakest-link/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T16:13:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Your mom is a tech ninja: Your boss? Not so much. The impossible scam of US drug plans: Even the guy who invented them can't figure them out. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Your mom is a tech ninja (permalink) What makes someone "good at technology?" In part, it's an understanding of the underlying technical principles and industry conventions – what a "power on" icon looks like, say. I have a lot of that. But there's another component, one that's often invisible to people like me: the extent to which your technology was designed to suit your needs. I have a lot of that, too. I'm a 50 year old, middle-class, tech-ind…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 18 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3635</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/18/turfed/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T07:01:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A(nother) way in which Facebook is the 21st Century's tobacco industry: Millions for front groups who insist that only Mark Zuckerberg can save us from Xi Jinping. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A(nother) way in which Facebook is the 21st Century's tobacco industry (permalink) Have you noticed some extremely normal ads from extremely normal "grassroots activists" who are really, really worried that if we break up Facebook, China will destroy America and that is why Congress must absolutely stop trying to regulate America's tech giants, the bristling colossi that stand guard to defend us from the menace across the ocean? https://www.djournal.com/opinion/columnists…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mainly Known For]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2621/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2621/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/mainly_known_for.png" title="Oh sure, I know Keira Knightly, from the first movie in that series by The Land Before Time producer. You know, the franchise with the guy from Jurassic Park and Ghostwriter, and script work by Billie Lourd's mom?" alt="Oh sure, I know Keira Knightly, from the first movie in that series by The Land Before Time producer. You know, the franchise with the guy from Jurassic Park and Ghostwriter, and script work by Billie Lourd's mom?" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3621</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/17/dollars-for-docs/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T15:45:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How Big Pharma bribed docs to overprescribe opioids: Analysis from UCSF's "Opioid Industry Documents" repository. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How Big Pharma bribed docs to overprescribe opioids (permalink) I have complex chronic pain, and I've seen a lot of specialists. One of them prescribed long-term opioids for me. I dodged a bullet there, I think. Here's a little story about how hard it is to know whether to trust your doctor when you have a pain condition. One day, I was in a neurologist's office here in Burbank, waiting for a nerve timing study. I picked up the neurology journal on the waiting-room table and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing the accessibility of Inspection overlays]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7246</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/17/fixing-the-accessibility-of-inspection-overlays/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T14:56:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Inspect tool is a great way to get information about different page elements before selecting then. Once it is enabled, it shows an information overlay as you move from element to element. The main problem with the tool is that sometimes it is tough to get the information about the right element, as they […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Surprising Truth About Pixels and Accessibility]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/surprising-truth-about-pixels-and-accessibility/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/surprising-truth-about-pixels-and-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-17T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Should I use pixels or rems?”. In this comprehensive blog post, we'll answer this question once and for all. You'll learn about the accessibility implications, and how to determine the best unit to use in any scenario.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3617</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/16/through-the-meat-grinder/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T16:50:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Amy's Kitchen, a case-study in the problems with consumerism: You are not an ambulatory wallet. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Amy's Kitchen, a case-study in the problems with consumerism (permalink) As theories of change go, consumerism has a lot going for it. "Voting with your dollars" cuts out the middleman: rather than voting for a politician and hoping that they do the right thing, you can just reward good companies directly by buying their products (and punish bad companies by not buying their products). But voting with your dollars has some obvious deficits. The first one is that you can't shop your way out of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health Data]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2620/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2620/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/health_data.png" title="Donate now to help us find a cure for causality. No one should have to suffer through events because of other events." alt="Donate now to help us find a cure for causality. No one should have to suffer through events because of other events." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-May Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42646</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/05/15/mid-may-link-assortment-5/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-15T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events June 4 is the next meeting of the SF Bay IF Meetup.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liminal Fever Dreams & Rejecting the Player (the surrealist, strange, upsetting otherworlds of video games)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5363</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/liminalfeverdreams"/>
        <updated>2022-05-13T01:34:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been meaning to write this post for some time, but held off to wait for The Lovely Estate to release a patch that would fix the walking issue. It’s fixed. This game is tremendous and you must give it a chance! Talking about this game here was important to me because it captures everything that I love about atmospheric games. It has a MOOD. – The Lovely Estate “You’re here to get someone. They’re here to breathe until they can’t anymore. Mind the fumes. Explore the secrets within these stained walls and find something before it finds you.” The...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crêpe]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2619/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2619/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/crepe.png" title="A medicine that makes you put two dots over your letters more often is a diäretic." alt="A medicine that makes you put two dots over your letters more often is a diäretic." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A “Quick Edit” bookmarklet to make changes to any web site]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7244</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/12/a-quick-edit-bookmarklet-to-make-changes-to-any-web-site/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T19:29:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using the Quick edit bookmarklet you can make any web site editable. Drag it to your favourites toolbar, click it and you get into edit mode. You can edit, copy and paste, delete and anything else. Hitting `ESC` will end edit mode. You can use this to quickly edit web sites before taking a screenshot, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 12 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3607</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/12/crypto-means-cryptography/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T17:28:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A useful, critical taxonomy of decentralization, beyond blockchains: Not all who decentralize are bros. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A useful, critical taxonomy of decentralization, beyond blockchains (permalink) I keep getting sucked into discussions of web3, decentralization and cryptocurrency. It's only natural: much of the rhetoric and stated goals of the people behind these technologies intersect with my longstanding causes, like access to cryptography and decentralized communities (what we used to call P2P). The reason I say I get "sucked into" these discussions is that, despite the rhetorical overlap, I've sensed a sig…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designers, (Re)define Success First]]></title>
        <id>https://alistapart.com/article/redefine-success-first/</id>
        <link href="https://alistapart.com/article/redefine-success-first/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[About two and a half years ago, I introduced the idea of daily ethical design. It was born out of my frustration with the many obstacles to achieving design that’s usable and equitable; protects people’s privacy, agency, and focus; benefits society; and restores nature. I argued that we need to overcome the inconveniences that prevent us from acting ethically and that we need to elevate design ethics to a more practical level by structurally integrating it into our daily work, processes, and tools.
Unfortunately, we’re still very far from this ideal. 
At the time, I didn’t know yet how to structurally integrate ethics. Yes, I had found some tools that had worked for me in previous projects, such as using checklists, assumption tracking, and “dark reality” sessions, but I didn’t manage to a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>by</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[sqlite-utils: a nice way to import data into SQLite for analysis]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/05/12/sqlite-utils--a-nice-way-to-import-data-into-sqlite/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/05/12/sqlite-utils--a-nice-way-to-import-data-into-sqlite/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T09:35:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! This is a quick post about a nice tool I found recently called sqlite-utils, from the tools category.
Recently I wanted to do some basic data analysis using data from my Shopify
store. So I figured I’d query the Shopify API and import my data into SQLite,
and then I could make queries to get the graphs I want.
But this seemed like a lot of boring work, like I’d have to write a
schema and write a Python program. So I hunted around for a solution, and I
found sqlite-utils, a tool designed to make it easy to import arbitrary data
into SQLite to do data analysis on the data.
sqlite-utils automatically generates a schema
The Shopify data has about a billion fields and I really did not want to type
out a schema for it. sqlite-utils solves this problem: if I have an array of
JSON orders, I…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 11 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3602</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/11/a-dent-in-the-universe/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T15:14:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The (billionaires') case against billionaires: Turns out, we live in a society. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The (billionaires') case against billionaires (permalink) The downsides of a world with billionaires in it are well-rehearsed: billionaires can convert their vast wealth to power, and use that power to turn their whims and pet theories into policy failures that affect millions – or even billions – of people. Take Bill Gates. Forget all the conspiracy theories about Gates and vaccines – it's bizarre that people bother to make up those fairy-tales when the truth is so much worse. Gates has an absolute ideologi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Selection Bias]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2618/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2618/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/selection_bias.png" title="We carefully sampled the general population and found that most people are familiar with acquiescence bias." alt="We carefully sampled the general population and found that most people are familiar with acquiescence bias." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pages that didn't make it into "How DNS Works"]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/05/10/pages-that-didn-t-make-it-into--how-dns-works-/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/05/10/pages-that-didn-t-make-it-into--how-dns-works-/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-10T14:44:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! A couple weeks ago I released a new zine called How DNS Works.
When I started writing that zine (in, uh, January 2021), I originally had in
mind a broader zine on “everything you need to know to own a domain”. So it had
a bunch of pages on domain registration, TLS, and email.
At the time I thought “I can just explain DNS in like 5 pages, it’s not
that complicated, there will be lots of space for other topics about domains”.
I was extremely wrong about that and it turned out I needed all 28 pages to
explain DNS. So I ended up deciding to just focus the zine on DNS and all those
other topics didn’t make it into the final zine.
This morning it occurred to me that instead of letting all of the old draft
pages languish in purgatory on my hard drive, I could post those extra pages
here all together on my blog. So here they are!
disclaimer: not super cohesive
I will say (as a disclaimer) that these pages aren’t as cohesive as I usually
like my zines to be and they definitely do not tell you everything you need to
need to know to own a domain.
domain registration






email


I should say that these 2 pages don’t really do email justice – email security
is a HUGE topic that honestly I don’t know a lot about.
TLS


These two pages also don’t remotely cover TLS, it’s possible I’ll write more in
depth about TLS at some point. Who knows!
that’s all!
though I will say: if you liked these, you might be interested in buying How DNS Works :)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Everything is going to be OK” is in THE collection in MoMA (also Tetrageddon won the Webby)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5357</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/everything-is-going-to-be-ok-is-in-the-collection-in-moma-also-tetrageddon-won-the-webby"/>
        <updated>2022-05-10T02:24:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m finally able to share some incredible news that deserves a blog post all on its own… “Everything is going to be OK” was accepted into the permanent collection in MoMA (New York)!!! I am honored to be able to announce that. It will be part of the Never Alone exhibit this September… Never Alone Video Games and Other Interactive Design Sep 10, 2022–summer 2023 “Everything is going to be OK” is a work that I’m probably most proud of. It has everything from me, poetry, animation, meaning… I’m honored that it has meant so much to so many people,...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone should build X for the web” – why not you? All you need is a GitHub account]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7237</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/09/someone-should-build-x-for-the-web-why-not-you-all-you-need-is-a-github-account/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T20:16:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, Šime Vidas complained on Twitter that it is hard to paste a block of text on a mobile device. I proposed to use pastebin.com but that needs a lot of taps before you paste. Šime then proceeded to joke that we should create pastebinzero.com and all it needs is a full-screen. So I […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 09 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3595</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/09/rest-in-piss-robert-bork/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T10:28:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links At the FTC, a quiet, profound shift on antitrust: Listening to "those who have experienced firsthand the effects of mergers and acquisitions beyond antitrust experts." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading At the FTC, a quiet, profound shift on antitrust (permalink) Sometimes, a tiny change in the political process comes along that makes you realize just how far things have come – a change that's both substantive and symbolic. Something like this terse, six-paragraph memo from the FTC, a deceptively anodyne wrapper for an explosive moment: https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/events/2022/05/ftc-justice-department-listening-forum…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maps]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2617/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2617/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/maps.png" title="OpenStreetMap was always pretty good but is also now *really* good? And Apple Maps's new zoomed-in design in certain cities like NYC and London is just gorgeous. It's cool how there are all these good maps now!" alt="OpenStreetMap was always pretty good but is also now *really* good? And Apple Maps's new zoomed-in design in certain cities like NYC and London is just gorgeous. It's cool how there are all these good maps now!" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3590</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/07/safegraph-spies-and-lies/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-07T11:53:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Safegraph follows people into abortion clinics and then sells the data: And then they lie about it. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Safegraph follows people into abortion clinics and then sells the data (permalink) As theocrats in robes, appointed by presidents who lost their elections, make ready to impose forced birth on half of America, it's right to worry that police in thrall to "the party of small government" will spy on, hunt down, and punish people who get abortions (or miscarry). It's not all despair. This era of forced birth offers many possibilities that were denied in the pre-Roe era. The advent of abortio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep End]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2616/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2616/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/deep_end.png" title="Hey! No running in the back-arc basin!" alt="Hey! No running in the back-arc basin!" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3583</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/05/mego/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T14:38:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A New York law to end to Wall Street's pension ripoff: The ex-suckers flip the card table. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A New York law to end to Wall Street's pension ripoff (permalink) The "Shield of Boringness" – c.f. Dana Claire – is a scammer's weapon. Layering scams in complexity lets villains get away with all kinds of nastiness. Some things are hard to understand because they're complex, but some things are complex so they'll be hard to understand. In finance, this is sometimes called MEGO: "my eyes glaze over" – complex scams designed to bore their victims into submission. All of us are vulnerable to MEGO, becaus…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edge DevTools for Visual Studio Code V2 – new browser preview with emulation and sourcemap support]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7229</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/05/05/edge-devtools-for-visual-studio-code-v2-new-browser-preview-with-emulation-and-sourcemap-support/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-05T12:51:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The V2 version of the Microsoft Edge DevTools for Visual Studio Code extension is now live. We’ve worked hard to make the current feature set more stable and introduced new ones. Console integration Console Integration – makes it easier to use `console.log()` or interact with the document right from the developer tools. We found the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 04 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3576</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/04/house-always-wins/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T14:52:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The eye-glazing scam of Medicare drug plans: Six tiers and none of them mean a fucking thing. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The eye-glazing scam of Medicare drug plans (permalink) CORRECTION: An earlier version of this article erroneously claimed Simon Lovell had passed away; I misremembered my contribution to a 2015 medical fundraiser for Mr Lovell as a contribution to a funeral expenses fundraiser. My sincere apologies to Mr Lovell (and I'm delighted to learn I was wrong!). Indie bookstores can change your life. In 2007, I wandered into NYC's St Marks' Bookstore (RIP) and picked up a book from the recommended table: "How to C…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome Back]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2615/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2615/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/welcome_back.png" title="'We're shocked by the Notre Dame fire. Click for our tribute to--' [okay] 'Now that we're all staying at home these past few weeks thanks to this new coronavirus, we--' [okay]" alt="'We're shocked by the Notre Dame fire. Click for our tribute to--' [okay] 'Now that we're all staying at home these past few weeks thanks to this new coronavirus, we--' [okay]" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3567</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/03/utopia-of-rules/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T16:36:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Democrats' self-immolating fetish for means-testing: How to lose an election…and a nation. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Democrats' self-immolating fetish for means-testing (permalink) Biden campaigned on universal student debt reduction, but now wants to add a means-test; a layer of bureaucratic formalities to identify the "deserving poor." The neoliberal fetish for red-tape is on the march, and the consequences will be the 2022 mid-terms, and maybe the future of the nation. Means-testing is the kind of technocratic make-work beloved of the McKinsey set, thus it was no surprise that Buttigieg campaigned aga…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Credit card autofill now enabled in the United Kingdom, France and Germany]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68934</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/firefox-credit-card-autofill-uk-france-germany/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T15:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the rapid growth of e-commerce in the last few years, more people are expecting their browser to help them out when shopping online. Firefox has supported credit card autofill in the United States and Canada since 2018. Starting today Firefox can remember and fill credit card details additionally in the United Kingdom, France and […]
The post Credit card autofill now enabled in the United Kingdom, France and Germany appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>admin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating Firefox: How we got to 100]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68902</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/celebrating-firefox-100/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T13:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether it’s celebrating the first 100 days of school or turning 100 years old, reaching a 100th milestone is a big deal worthy of confetti, streamers and cake, and of course, reflection. Today, Firefox is releasing its 100th version to our users and we wanted to take a moment to pause and look back on […]
The post Celebrating Firefox: How we got to 100 appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox’s Picture-in-Picture rolls out subtitles – a Mozilla Connect community requested feature]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68888</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/firefox-picture-in-picture-rolls-out-subtitles/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T12:43:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are so many different ways that Firefox users count on Picture-in-Picture for their best browsing and content viewing experiences: Toddler duty? Don’t sweat it! Stream your child’s favorite movie to watch on your desktop while you hold down your job and the title of “favorite parent!” Can’t miss the big game? Firefox’s Multiple Picture-in-Picture […]
The post Firefox’s Picture-in-Picture rolls out subtitles – a Mozilla Connect community requested feature appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Vasquez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Don’t Need a UI Framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2022/05/you-dont-need-ui-framework/</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2022/05/you-dont-need-ui-framework/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-03T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As developers, it can be tempting to grab a pre-styled UI framework like Material UI or Bootstrap. Seems like a great way to outsource design and save a bunch of time, right? In my experience, this is an unrealistic expectation, and things don’t quite work out that way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photogammetry, Meshroom, and Blender (some learning resources that helped me)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5346</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/photogammetry-meshroom-and-blender-some-learning-resources-that-helped-me"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T21:50:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Photogrammetry is the science of making measurements from photographs. It infers the geometry of a scene from a set of unordered photographs or videos. Photography is the projection of a 3D scene onto a 2D plane, losing depth information. The goal of photogrammetry is to reverse this process.” – Meshroom github I’ve been doing a lot of 3D modeling lately and, because I’m new to it, I have also been experimenting with finding workflows that I might be comfortable in. For example a friend of mine models a lot in VR. She swears by it. Anyone I have asked has...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 02 May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3563</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/05/02/reverse-centaurs/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T15:59:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Revenge Of the Chickenized Reverse Centaurs": The relationship between algorithms, interoperability and worker power. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Revenge Of the Chickenized Reverse Centaurs" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my Medium column, "Revenge Of the Chickenized Reverse Centaurs," proposing a theory of the relationship between algorithms, interoperability and worker power (happy May Day!). https://onezero.medium.com/revenge-of-the-chickenized-reverse-centaurs-b2e8d5cda826 Let's break it down. Start with "chickenization": this is a labor economics term referring to industries that foll…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2614/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2614/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/2.png" title="It's like sigma summation notation, except instead of summing the argument over all values of i, you 2 the argument over all values of 2." alt="It's like sigma summation notation, except instead of summing the argument over all values of i, you 2 the argument over all values of 2." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When I Made Another Monkey Island]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/when_i_made_another_monkeyisland</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/when_i_made_another_monkeyisland"/>
        <updated>2022-05-01T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nine years ago I wrote a blog post titled "If I made another Monkey Island" and it feels like there are some things I need to say.
I can't remember the exact incident, but the day I wrote that I was feeling down about never being able to make another Monkey Island.  I wrote it in a single afternoon, and it was not much more than a stream of thoughts. In the movie version, tears would have been pouring down my cheeks, but it wasn't the movie version so I was probably sipping coffee and eating a chocolate chip cookie.
My point is these were not commandments handed down and etched in stone on a giant tablet. They were just random thoughts about a (then very unlikely) new Monkey Island game. 
None of these are promises or anything I owe anybody.
People talk a lot about Monkey Island 3a as if i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for April]]></title>
        <id>log.html#apr2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#apr2022"/>
        <updated>2022-05-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of April. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Bicycle, released an Uxntal playground. See Varvara riding a Sinclair bike.
Uxn, wrote a linux native implementation of Varvara, as well as an HTML5 implementation of the virtual machine.
Turquoise, released a little line plotting system.
100r.co, added sewing, Shimoda, Cathedral Grove, and mini dodger.
Nebu, working on a spreadsheet editor in Uxn.
News
The month of April was a time of boat projects. We built a mini dodger to cover the companionway, and installed a large spindle for floating rope on Pino's stern (marine stores give those spindles away for free, usually). In these waters, it is often necessary to stern tie to shore when anchoring and the spindle will make it easier to uncoil the line.
We also took some time off to visit some ancient trees in Cathedral Grove on Vancouver Island.
Devine found some slide rules and wrote a guide on how to use them.
If you want to play Catpot, the little Hypercard game we made for Merveilles Hyperjam 2020, you can play it with this Hypercard Simulator (thank you Dan).
Pino book club
We're reading The Stranger by Albert Camus.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of April Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42644</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/04/30/end-of-april-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-30T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events May 1 (tomorrow!) the London IF Meetup plays Spring Thing games together, 2 PM-5 PM British time. May 4, the Unnamed IF Book Club meets, also discussing Spring Thing games – though very possibly a different set of them. There are lots of entries this year. LudoNarraCon, May 5-9, is an event running on Steam … Continue reading "End of April Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3541</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/30/disney-still-must-pay/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-30T15:41:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Disney's writer wage theft, a year on: Still work to do. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Disney's writer wage theft, a year on (permalink) In November 2020, SFWA came forward with a stunning accusation: Disney had told the beloved writer Alan Dean Foster (author of the original, bestselling Star Wars novelization) that they would not ever pay him the royalties he was owed. https://pluralistic.net/2020/11/19/disneymustpay/#disneymustpay Disney argued that Foster's contract – where he was guaranteed wages for his creative labor on the Star Wars book, which was written before the film was complete and formed the basis for many…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 29 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3537</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/29/taken-in-context/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-29T13:40:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Killing online surveillance with contextual ads: For chrissakes, can we stop talking about who the product is? Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Killing online surveillance with contextual ads (permalink) The internet has ushered in an era of unprecedented invasive surveillance. Commercial operators large and small spy on us in every way and sell and give away and leak our data to criminals, cops, spies, advertisers and stalkers. This isn't because you're not paying for "the product," which makes you the product. Companies that can abuse you do. John Deere will sell you a $800,000 tractor and then lock you out of getting it f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bad Map Projection: Madagascator]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2613/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2613/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/bad_map_projection_madagascator.png" title="The projection's north pole is in a small lake on the island of Mahé in the Seychelles, which is off the top of the map and larger than the rest of the Earth's land area combined." alt="The projection's north pole is in a small lake on the island of Mahé in the Seychelles, which is off the top of the map and larger than the rest of the Earth's land area combined." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3532</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/28/shut-yer-pi-hole/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-28T13:29:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Renegotiate the web "bargain" by blocking all ads: The Adafruit ESPHole lets you say "How about 'Nah?'" Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Renegotiate the web "bargain" by blocking all ads (permalink) Back in 2019, I wrote a case-study on ad- and tracker-blocking as part of EFF's series on adversarial interoperability (AKA "competitive compatibility" or comcom). My point was that the ad-tech industry says that it tracks you as part of a bargain: you trade away your privacy and get media in exchange, but that this was a bizarre kind of take-it-or-leave-it form of bargaining. https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/07/adblockin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3525</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/27/im-a-backdoor-man/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-27T14:28:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How police backdoors for online services let sextortionists target children: There is no such thing as a back-door that only lets the good guys through. Laura Jean McKay's "The Animals in That Country": A brilliant debut novel of too much understanding. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How police backdoors for online services let sextortionists target children (permalink) An "Emergency Data Request" (EDR) is a warrantless demand by a police officer to a tech company, designed for white-hot emergencies when a cop needs an online service to cough up some of its user data to save a life or prevent a tragedy. Criminals love EDRs…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lightsabers]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2612/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2612/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/lightsabers.png" title="A lot of Jedi romances start with this turning into a Lady and the Tramp spaghetti situation." alt="A lot of Jedi romances start with this turning into a Lady and the Tramp spaghetti situation." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 26 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3516</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/26/plastic-fatalistic/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T14:38:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Bottled water monopolist admits recycling is bullshit: "Personal responsibility" and "caveat emptor." This day in history: 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Bottled water monopolist admits recycling is bullshit (permalink) "Puffery" is a funny word! It's the word that lawyers use when their clients are accused of unlawful speech acts, such as fraud or libel. In that context, "puffery" (or, even better, "mere puffery") is a synonym for bullshit. Recycling is puffery. Which is to say, recyling is bullshit. Plastics recycling has its origins in a "puffery" campaign. In 1973, Exxon researchers told the company that there was no feasible way to recycle plastics, and that there likely never would be. htt…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New zine: How DNS Works!]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/04/26/new-zine--how-dns-works-/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/04/26/new-zine--how-dns-works-/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T07:28:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! On Thursday we released a new zine about one of my favourite computer systems: DNS!
You can get it for $12 here:
https://wizardzines.com/zines/dns, or get
an 11-pack of all my zines here.
Here’s the cover and table of contents:




why DNS?
I wanted to write about DNS for three reasons:
DNS is everywhere! You basically can’t use the internet without using
DNS — nobody is going to memorize all the IP addresses for every domain they
use. You need to look them up with DNS!
DNS has a really cool decentralized design! I love that it gives you
control of your own little corner of the internet (it just costs ~$12/year to
own a domain!), I love that the basic design is relatively straightforward,
and I love that it’s worked basically the same way for 40 years and scaled
relatively well over…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MS update [blog]]]></title>
        <id>ms-update</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/04/26/ms-update"/>
        <updated>2022-04-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What seems like only a few months ago, I wrote about being diagnosed with MS, and yet that was over 2 years ago (and the diagnosis was actually December 2019).
As it's MS Awareness Week 2022 and MS was on my mind (literally and figuratively!) I thought an update blog post would seem fit.
My post in 2020 started stating this, which, as it turns out, wasn't right at all:

I was diagnosed with "very mild benign relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis".]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 25 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3510</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/25/mj-locke-rides-again/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-25T14:49:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Up Against It, an "essential," action-adventure sf tale of bureaucrats and colonizers: Laura J Mixon's fast-paced space-opera. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Up Against It, an "essential," action-adventure sf tale of bureaucrats and colonizers (permalink) I first discovered Laura Mixon's fiction in 1992. I was working at Toronto's Bakka Books and I was the "cyberpunk guy," so when I unpacked a new box from Tor Books and found her eco-thriller/cyberpunk debut Glass Houses at the top, I grabbed a copy and read it on my lunch-break: https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/327799.Glass_Houses I ended up hand-selling cases of copies of Glass Houses, talking up this …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cutest-Sounding Scientific Effects]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2611/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2611/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/cutest_sounding_scientific_effects.png" title="The Stroop-YORP number of a scientific paper is how many of the 16 finalist names (sans 'effect') it manages to casually sneak into the text." alt="The Stroop-YORP number of a scientific paper is how many of the 16 finalist names (sans 'effect') it manages to casually sneak into the text." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 22 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3504</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/22/mesmer-2-point-oh/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T19:40:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Don't believe Obama's Big Tech criti-hype: They're not evil geniuses (they're not geniuses, period). Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Don't believe Obama's Big Tech criti-hype (permalink) Obama's Stanford University speech this Thursday (correctly) raised the alarm about conspiratorial thinking, and (correctly) identified that Big Tech was at the center of that rise – and then (wildly incorrectly) blamed "the algorithm" for it. https://thehill.com/policy/technology/3382803-obama-points-finger-at-tech-companies-for-disinformation-in-major-speech/ Obama was committing the sin of criti-hype, Lee Vinsel's incredibly useful…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internet spring cleaning: How to delete Instagram, Facebook and other accounts]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68841</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-instagram-facebook-online-accounts/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So you’ve washed your sheets and vacuumed under the couch in the name of spring cleaning. But what about your online clutter? Apps that delight, inform and keep you connected deserve room in your digital space. But if you haven’t used your Facebook account in years, or you’re looking to permanently take back some time […]
The post Internet spring cleaning: How to delete Instagram, Facebook and other accounts appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete your Spotify account]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68840</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-spotify/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether you want to follow in Neil Young’s footsteps or are already streaming music and podcasts through another service, deleting your stagnant Spotify account is a good idea. If you have a subscription, you’ll need to cancel that first. Once you’re ready, here’s how to delete your Spotify account. In your web browser, go to […]
The post How to delete your Spotify account appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete your Facebook account]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68872</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-facebook/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Firefox, you can limit the social media giant tracking your online activities through the Facebook Container extension without deleting your Facebook account. Though, *wildly gestures at news headlines over the past couple of years*, we don’t blame you if you want to stop using the app for good. You may have even deactivated your […]
The post How to delete your Facebook account appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete your Instagram account]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68873</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-instagram/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So you’ve decided to shut down your Instagram account. Maybe you want to cleanse your digital space from its parent company, Meta. Perhaps you’re tired of deleting the app only to reinstall it later. Whatever your reason, here’s how to delete your Instagram: Visit https://instagram.com/accounts/remove/request/permanent and log in, if you aren’t already logged in. You’ll […]
The post How to delete your Instagram account appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete your Snapchat account]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68874</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-snapchat/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether you’ve migrated to another similar social media platform, or have simply outgrown it, you may be tempted to just delete the Snapchat app from your phone and get on with it. But you’ll want to scrub your data, too. Here’s how to delete your Snapchat account from an iOS app: Click on the profile […]
The post How to delete your Snapchat account appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete your Twitter account]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68875</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-twitter/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter can be a trove of information. It can also enable endless doomscrolling. If you’d rather get your news and and debate people on the latest hot take elsewhere, here’s how to delete your Twitter account from a browser: Once you’re logged in, click on more on the left-hand side of your Twitter homepage. Click […]
The post How to delete your Twitter account appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete your Google account]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68876</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-google/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s share of the global search market stands at about 85%. While the tech giant will likely continue to loom large over our lives, from search to email to our calendars, we can delete inactive or unnecessary Google accounts. Here’s how to do that: Go to https://myaccount.google.com/data-and-privacy and scroll down to your data & privacy […]
The post How to delete your Google account appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete your Amazon account]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68877</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-amazon/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon has had its fair share of controversies, particularly about data collection and how the retail giant treats its workers. If you’ve decided that easy access and quick deliveries aren’t worth the price anymore, here’s how to delete your Amazon account: Go to https://www.amazon.com/privacy/data-deletion. Make sure to read which Amazon services you won’t have access […]
The post How to delete your Amazon account appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete your TikTok account]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68878</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-tiktok/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TikTok has exploded in popularity, surpassing Twitter and Snapchat’s combined ad revenue in February. If you’ve tried the app and decided it’s not for you, here’s how to delete your TikTok account: In the app, click the profile icon on the bottom right. Click the three-line icon on the top right. Click on settings and […]
The post How to delete your TikTok account appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete your Venmo account]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68879</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/how-to-delete-your-venmo-account/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T17:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Payment app Venmo has made it easier to split bills and pay for things without cash. But if you’ve decided to use other ways to do that, you’ll want to delete your account along with your bank information with it. You’ll first have to transfer any funds in your Venmo account to your bank account. […]
The post How to delete your Venmo account appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assigning Numbers]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2610/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2610/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/assigning_numbers.png" title="Gödel should do an article on which branches of math have the lowest average theorem number." alt="Gödel should do an article on which branches of math have the lowest average theorem number." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 20 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3496</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/20/ceci-nest-pas-un-helicopter/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-20T14:23:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Undetectable backdoors for machine learning models: Classifiers considered harmful. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Undetectable backdoors for machine learning models (permalink) We're in the middle of a giant machine learning surge, with ML-based "classifiers" being used to make all kinds of decisions at speeds that humans could never match: ML decides everything from whether you get a bank loan to what your phone's camera judges to be a human face. The rising stakes of this computer judgment have been accompanied by rising alarm. The main critique, of course, is that machine learning models can serve to "empiricism-…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entwives]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2609/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2609/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/entwives.png" title="No, we actually do have a woman who's basically part of our fellowship. She lives in Rivendell, you wouldn't know her." alt="No, we actually do have a woman who's basically part of our fellowship. She lives in Rivendell, you wouldn't know her." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Front-End Developer's Guide to the Terminal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/javascript/terminal-for-js-devs/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/javascript/terminal-for-js-devs/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you want to learn a modern JavaScript framework like React or Angular, you better be familiar with the terminal! So many frameworks and tools assume that you're proficient with it, without ever explaining it. This blog post is your missing manual, covering all of the most important fundamentals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 18 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3488</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/18/news-isnt-secret/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-18T14:43:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Big Tech Isn’t Stealing News Publishers’ Content": "…It's stealing their money." Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Big Tech Isn’t Stealing News Publishers’ Content" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my Medium column, "Big Tech Isn’t Stealing News Publishers’ Content," on how the news industry's focus on charging tech firms to link to them is totally misguided, and misses the real issue: the rigging of the ad market. https://doctorow.medium.com/big-tech-isnt-stealing-news-publishers-content-a97306884a6b Countries all over the world – France, Australia, Brazil and now Canada (Bill C-11)- have f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family Reunion]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2608/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2608/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/family_reunion.png" title="Grandma says that because of differences in primate and feline lifespans, the cat is actually my 17,000,000th cousin 14,000,000 times removed." alt="Grandma says that because of differences in primate and feline lifespans, the cat is actually my 17,000,000th cousin 14,000,000 times removed." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3471</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/16/they-laughed-at-me-in-vienna/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-16T20:54:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Ryan North's 'How to Take Over the World': Popular science as a series of supervillainous thought-experiments. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Ryan North's 'How to Take Over the World' (permalink) There's a certain kind of Internet Person who makes the world a better place every day, just by showing up. People like Ryan North, whose many accomplishments include his daily, long-running, brilliant Dinosaur Comics: https://www.qwantz.com/ The secret to Dinosaur Comics is the simplicity of the bit, coupled with the lengths that North takes it to: it's the same six stock-art panels of a T-Rex, a Utahraptor and a, Dromiceiomimus, discoursing on some funny, bizarre…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-April Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42641</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/04/15/mid-april-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-15T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events ParserComp 2022 is soliciting games that use keyboard input: ParserComp defines a parser game as one where the primary input method is the keyboard, commands are typed in, the computer uses a parser engine to understand commands and then outputs text to screen describing the results. Games for ParserComp may be submitted from May … Continue reading "Mid-April Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Presents: A makeup artist with alopecia redefining beauty online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68661</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/abby-wren-makeup-artist-alopecia-advocate/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-15T16:49:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abby Wren wants you to look.   With her face and bald head as her canvas, she creates wildly elaborate and colorful makeup designs that have gained her more than 177,000 followers on TikTok. She’s transformed herself into an Easter bunny, the Cheshire cat and Homer Simpson. Once, she turned herself into Bernie Sanders from that […]
The post Firefox Presents: A makeup artist with alopecia redefining beauty online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla celebrates groundbreaking creators in new docuseries “Firefox Presents”]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68743</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/new-mozilla-docuseries-firefox-presents-launch/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-15T16:43:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Different is dope. Firefox has always stood by this. It’s also the mantra of Abby Wren, the woman featured in the pilot episode of our new docuseries, “Firefox Presents.” Launching Friday, April 15, “Firefox Presents” is a documentary series featuring colorful and inspiring creators who each have a unique journey of finding themselves or their […]
The post Mozilla celebrates groundbreaking creators in new docuseries “Firefox Presents” appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geiger Counter]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2607/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2607/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/geiger_counter.png" title="At first I didn't get why they were warning me about all those birds sitting on the wire, but then I understood." alt="At first I didn't get why they were warning me about all those birds sitting on the wire, but then I understood." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 13 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3460</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/13/taxes-are-for-the-little-people/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-13T16:34:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links America's 400 top earners pay less tax than you: Propublica continues to mine the IRS Files. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading America's 400 top earners pay less tax than you (permalink) Last June, Propublica announced that it was in possession of leaked IRS files detailing the tax affairs of America's richest people, and that the IRS Files showed that taxes are – as Leona Helmsley famously quipped – for the little people: https://pluralistic.net/2021/06/15/guillotines-and-taxes/#carried-interest The initial reporting described how, for example, private equity raiders were able to debt-finance acquisitions of productive busin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weird Unicode Math Symbols]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2606/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2606/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/weird_unicode_math_symbols.png" title="U+2A0B ⨋ Mathematicians need to calm down" alt="U+2A0B ⨋ Mathematicians need to calm down" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A list of new(ish) command line tools]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/04/12/a-list-of-new-ish--command-line-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/04/12/a-list-of-new-ish--command-line-tools/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-12T15:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Today I asked on twitter about newer
command line tools, like ripgrep and fd and fzf and exa and bat.
I got a bunch of replies with tools I hadn’t heard of, so I thought I’d make a
list here. A lot of people also pointed at the modern-unix list.
replacements for standard tools
ripgrep, ag, ack (grep)
exa, lsd (ls)
mosh (ssh)
bat (cat)
delta (a pager for git)
fd (find)
drill, dog (dig)
duf (df)
dust, ncdu (du)
pgcli (psql)
btm, btop, glances, gtop, zenith (top)
tldr (man, sort of)
sd (sed)
difftastic (diff)
mtr (traceroute)
plocate (locate)
new inventions
Here are some tools that are not exactly replacements for standard tools:
z, fasd, autojump, zoxide (tools to make it easier to find files / change directories)
broot (a file manager)
direnv (load environment variables depending on the current directory)
fzf, peco (“fuzzy finder”)
croc and magic-wormhole (send files from one computer to another)
hyperfine (benchmarking)
httpie, curlie, xh (for making HTTP requests)
entr (run arbitrary commands when files change)
asdf (version manager for multiple languages)
tig, lazygit (interactive interfaces for git)
lazydocker (interactive interface for docker)
choose (the basics of awk/cut)
ctop (top for containers)
fuck (autocorrect command line errors)
pbcopy/pbpaste (for clipboard <> stdin/stdout) maybe aren’t “new” but were mentioned a lot. You can use xclip to do the same thing on Linux.
JSON/YAML/CSV things:
jq (a great JSON-wrangling tool)
jc (convert various tools’ output into JSON)
yq  (like jq, but for YAML). there’s also another yq
fq (like jq, but for binary)
fx (interactive json tool)
jless (json pager)
xsv (a command line tool for csv files, from burntsushi)
visidata (“an interactive multitool for tabular data”)
grep things:
pdfgrep (grep for PDF)
gron (make JSON greppable)
ripgrep-all (ripgrep, but also PDF, zip, ebooks, etc)
some of my favourites
My favourites of these that I use already are entr, ripgrep, git-delta,
httpie, plocate, and jq. I’m interested in trying out btm,
z, xsv, and duf.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 12 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3454</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/12/klong-you-are-a-pickle/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-12T14:13:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Daniel Pinkwater's "Crazy in Poughkeepsie": Another Pinkwater masterpiece, in which we sojourn to whale heaven. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Daniel Pinkwater's "Crazy in Poughkeepsie" (permalink) "Crazy in Poughkeepsie" is Daniel Pinkwater's standalone, demi-sequel to 2020's "Adventures of Dwergish Girl," a YA novel about a sort-of Catskills leprechaun girl whose coming of age involves moving to human civilization, learning the art of pizza-making, getting involved with community radio, venturing to New York City to drink papaya juice and learn mystic secrets from a junk-store owner, and, ultimately, resolving an existential t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use, participation, visibility, and anti-artificial scarcity… How small independent tools help us construct a reality that empowers us (something of a manifesto)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5330</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/use-participation-visibility-and-anti-artificial-scarcity-how-small-independent-tools-help-us-construct-a-reality-that-empowers-us-something-of-a-manifesto"/>
        <updated>2022-04-12T00:11:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tool development, as an umbrella term that is used to describe software that is both utilitarian and a toy, has become deeply important to me. I think there is something interesting to observe from that space, especially when it is centered around making interesting visual experiments functional to artists. It invites abundance and generocity. For example, J.Kirchartz’s Glitchy3bitDither has become invalualbe to me. It’s a browser based glitching tool that lets you import an image, and then choose from a series of glitch effects. Yes, I can make my own. Yes, there are so many of these. No, for me,...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One million broken web sites – and a way to prevent that]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7208</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/04/12/one-million-broken-web-sites-and-a-way-to-prevent-that/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-11T23:37:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Webaim.org releases an annual report called the WebAIM Million. This is a deep analysis of the one million most visited web sites how accessible they are. And every year the result is pretty grim. Across the one million home pages, 50,829,406 distinct accessibility errors were detected—an average of 50.8 errors per page. This is 1.1% […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 11 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3448</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/11/coercion-v-cooperation/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-11T16:29:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "When Automation Becomes Enforcement": Are disappearing messages part of end-to-end encryption, or are they just DRM? The "algospeak" dialect: An emerging vocabulary designed to evade machine censorship. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2022 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "When Automation Becomes Enforcement" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my recent Medium column, "When Automation Becomes Enforcement," about the debate of interoperability and end-to-end encryption in the EU's Digital Markets Act, and how that relates to the long-running battle over who's in charge: you, or your computer? https://onezero.medium.com/when-…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taylor Series]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2605/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2605/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/taylor_series.png" title="The Taylor series should have been canceled after the first term." alt="The Taylor series should have been canceled after the first term." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 09 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3441</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/09/john-m-ford/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-09T19:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links John M Ford's "Aspects": An unfinished masterpiece by a legend of science fiction and fantasy. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading John M Ford's "Aspects" (permalink) John M Ford's sudden death in 2006 – a heart attack – left his legion of friends and fans bereft and reeling. Ford – "Mike" to his friends – was brilliant, witty, and multitalented, an accomplished RPG designer, poet, and half-a-dozen kinds of novelist. He published an eerily prescient cyberpunk novel about "the Web" four years before Neuromancer, and eight years before Tim Berners-Lee created the World Wide Web. His expansion to Paranoia is one of the wittiest RPG sour…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does your narrative system need to do?]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42671</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/04/09/what-does-your-narrative-system-need-to-do/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-09T18:07:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a question that comes up very frequently in the narrative design conversations. This post is a tour of some possible answers. Select or Generate Content Content selection systems choose what piece of content to show the player next. They often function on the level of scenes or individual lines or barks in a … Continue reading "What does your narrative system need to do?"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3437</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/08/oh-why/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-08T19:15:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Ed Sheeran problem, or, how the record industry got what it asked for: A dog that caught the bus wheel. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Ed Sheeran problem, or, how the record industry got what it asked for (permalink) You might have seen Ed Sheeran's triumphant statement about his victory in a copyright lawsuit that alleged he'd copied elements of Sami Switch's "Oh Why" in his song "Shape Of You": https://twitter.com/edsheeran/status/1511631955238047751 Sheeran's statement makes two critical points: first, that there are only so many ways of arranging English words and musical phrases, and 60,000 new songs being rel…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Mirror Editing with Sourcemapped files (Sass, React…) – we need you to make it better]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7201</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/04/08/css-mirror-editing-with-sourcemapped-files-sass-react-we-need-you-to-make-it-better/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-08T12:14:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using the Edge Developer Tools for VS Code extension, you can live edit files in the browser developer tools and all the changes are also happen in your source files. That way you never lose a change you did to your web projects in the developer tools. It makes tweaking a layout much more convenient […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frankenstein Captcha]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2604/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2604/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/frankenstein_captcha.png" title="The distinction between a ship and a boat is a line drawn in water." alt="The distinction between a ship and a boat is a line drawn in water." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3431</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/07/moral-hazard-of-filternets/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-07T19:33:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The antitrust case against gig companies: Either they're violating employment law, or they're violating antitrust. Cops prove how stupid the SMART Act is: Blasting Disney tunes as a way to foil accountability. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The antitrust case against gig companies (permalink) Gig work companies like Uber and Doordash are committed to misclassifying their workers as contractors, which lets them escape employer obligations like a minimum wage, health care or worker's comp (driving for Uber/Lyft is one of the most dangerous jobs in America). These companies spent $225m to pass California's Proposition 2…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A glossary of terms about cyberattacks, from ransomware to DDoS]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68641</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/cyberattacks-glossary-of-terms-ransomware-ddos/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-06T14:58:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you read news about technology, you’re bound to run into some jargon. Here at Mozilla, we believe that information should be as accessible as possible regardless of your level of expertise. We want to help you approach stories about technology with more curiosity and with a little less head-scratching involved. We’ll break down headline-making […]
The post A glossary of terms about cyberattacks, from ransomware to DDoS appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is a cyberattack and what can we do to protect ourselves online?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68630</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/mozilla-explains/cyberattack-meaning-russia-ukraine/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-06T14:57:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberattacks are nothing new. According to the FBI, the first major “attack on the internet” predated even the web — a self-replicating malicious program created by a grad student who shortly apologized with instructions to remove it. While the software didn’t damage or destroy any files, it spread, within 24 hours, to about 6,000 of […]
The post What is a cyberattack and what can we do to protect ourselves online? appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 06 Apr 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3426</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/04/06/foia-be-damned/"/>
        <updated>2022-04-06T13:56:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How trade secrets swallowed your right to know: A corporate veto over your environment, health, and civic duty. The Mormon Church owns the most valuable property portfolio in America: At least $15,700,000,000 in holdings. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How trade secrets swallowed your right to know (permalink) If you've never had a fight over the phrase "intellectual property," count yourself lucky, you normie, you. In the land of Free Software and Free Culture, "IP" is fightin' words. Not unreasonably, mind you. "IP" was a deliberately ploy, undertaken by the world's largest, most aggressive corporations, who hated the existing terms of art, like "creators…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discussing two "holy war" topics at the same time]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-17T23:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cutting to the chase: text editors *and* tabs vs. spaces!  Ooooh!


I've had this thing called "e" for a while now.  It's a stupid little 
script which serves to do a couple of things.  It starts my 
editor
with a given file, and it kicks it with the right arguments to make it 
disable line wrapping and to make the [TAB] key actually put in two 
spaces.


So, my dumb script would use "-w -E -T 2" most of the time, except when it 
was running on a Makefile, at which point it would skip those args.  
Simple enough, right?


pico is back?  Yes indeed, on Macs, as of 12.3, pico is in fact back.  To 
make sure I wasn't imagining things, I tracked down a machine that hadn't 
been upgraded yet and checked there.  Sure enough, it was in fact nano and 
not pico.


macOS 12.3 has nano as a symlink... pointing to pico!


At some point, I switched from literal tab characters in my source code to 
blobs of spaces, probably due to using that style at work and not hating 
it.  So, somewhere along the line I actually started depending on nano 
behavior without realizing it.


As for the lack of a feature in pico itself, it's kind of strange, really.  
If you go digging into the source, they have this random.c with a function 
called tab which claims to "simulate tab stop" using spaces.  That said, I 
can't find any place where it would be called with the magic values which 
would make it behave that way.


It wouldn't surprise me if this switch is just more of Apple removing 
GPLed things from their OS - pico seems to use the Apache license.  They 
dumped bash for zsh (MIT license) at some point (Big Sur, I think), and 
now this?  Okay then.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dumb things you can sometimes do with hard links]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-16T01:51:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a very old and stupid trick you could do with some filesystems in 
some situations back in the day... and might still be able to do in a 
few places today.


The problem is that while version X might eventually have an exploit, 
it'll get removed and it'll be replaced by version Y without that
particular hole.  By the time you get your hands on a tool to break into 
X, it'll be gone.


What you'd do is create a hard link pointing at the file you wanted to 
preserve, storing it in a spot which was writable by your account.  
Then, say, /usr/bin/sudo (because that never has security 
issues...) gets replaced at some point with a new file and you get to 
keep the old version.  When you get the tool to pop it, off you go!


Of course, these days, it's not quite so easy on the more modern systems 
you find.  Debian 11 here won't let me do it - it's EPERM city.  Rocky 8 
(so CentOS 8 and RHEL 8 too) also won't do it.  They both have some gunk
in /usr/lib/sysctl.d to lock this down.  But, my old Slackware 14.2 
install of my workstation let me do it the last time I tried about 
a year ago.  How about that, huh?  I bet it'd still work if I dug out 
the old drives and booted them up.


Incidentally, this is the magic sauce: /proc/sys/fs/protected_hardlinks
Read the man page for proc(5) to learn more about it.

here it is,
the thread I read a long time ago.  It's interesting to note that as far 
as I can tell, nothing actually changed upstream.  This left paranoid 
admins like me with no option but to use the (most excellent) Openwall 
patches to lock down this kind of stuff.  I used that on my machines at 
work which had non-staff users... just in case.


This whole situation is scary.  
Read more about it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More stories about stacks of modems]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-14T23:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in January, you might have seen my
post
about a very large BBS which seemed to solve for the problem of "how do 
we host a bunch of users" by having one physical box per user.  It might 
have been one physical box per *two* users, maybe, but it's hard to say.


Now, keep in mind digital cameras weren't easy to come by, so I have 
very few actual pictures.  I'll have to do a lot of explaining to make 
up for the lack of detail and alternate angles.  Clearly, I had no 
notion of ever using these pictures to tell stories 25+ years later.


Some friends at a local company had some bandwidth to spare (a T1 to 
Alternet somewhere, as I recall), so they parked a Zoom modem on one of 
their boxes and plugged it into a phone line.  We got an identical model 
to avoid cross-brand issues (Zoom m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking away the berries]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-13T02:14:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I sometimes write the beginnings of posts but don't post them.  I still 
save them in case conditions change or other things happen and make me 
want to follow up on the topic.  In this case, I wrote something about 
offices before the whole COVID lockdown thing happened and people 
largely stopped going to offices every day.  With that in mind, let's 
proceed.


However, tech companies decided to go past this at some point and 
brought about this whole notion of "microkitchens".  This is where 
they'd put their branding on the coolers (instead of "Coca-Cola" or 
"Pepsi") and would load it up with every kind of fizzy sugary liquid 
they could get their hands on.  They'd have racks and racks of shelving 
packed with all sorts of interesting crunchy, sugary and carb-loaded 
snacks.  They'd a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at the outlying data points]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T07:04:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the fun things I used to do at a prior job was to dig through the 
raw data points which were collected from the *many* servers we had.  I 
could just pick an interesting-sounding metric and then would just ask 
the system to show me the top 10 or bottom 10 out of a population of 
thousands or more.


To get my feet wet with the whole "investigations" thing that we'd do, I 
started looking into this one day and chose one of the many temp sensors 
which were being logged by the servers.  I forget exactly which one it 
was, for there were many.  The CPUs logged it, the chassis logged it, 
the power supply logged it, and so on.  There were so many choices.


I went looking for a reason.  What could possibly explain this?  First 
off, it didn't line up with any obvious pattern in the host names.  The 
hosts were named for whichever team owned them, followed by a sequence 
number that was bumped any time a new one was provisioned.  There was no 
signal to be found in that.


There was more, though.  You could also see a "rack position" in this 
data, and now it started getting interesting.  It seems that all of the 
really hot machines had a rack position of something low, like 04 or 05, 
and never anything higher than that.  In fact, when looking at a whole 
rack, it was always the lowest number of all of the positions that were 
being used.  Now this was worth chasing!


It's good that I asked, since they told me something surprising: 
position 04 or 05 or whatever was the *bottom* of the rack.  Yes, 
somehow, the lowest machine in the rack was the hottest!  They found 
this interesting, too, and wound up digging into it.  Given that I was 
far away in a distant office, this was the best way for us to proceed.


The problem was that the bottommost server would have nothing below it 
but just open space until it got to the floor.  That space would not 
move air efficiently, and it obviously mattered.


This rolled out and my hot spots disappeared.  Fantastic!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Questions about construction trucks on train tracks]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T01:26:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another day, another bit of local flavor, but this time it's something I 
wish I didn't have to write about.

wrote
about seeing a maintenance truck rolling down the Caltrain line in 
Mountain View.  It had a special attachment to let it stay on the rails.  
At no point did the arms come down for the crossing.  It managed to 
approach, then the people inside looked around and went through, and the 
arms never budged.  There were no flashing lights or bells.




caught fire.  A bunch of people were hurt.  More were shaken 
up.


I'm assuming their construction trucks don't trigger the "short the 
rails together to signal various things" logic, either.  This would 
mean that crossing arms stay up... and I have to assume it also means 
the signals along the way stay green instead of going red.

We will presumably hear more about whatever the signals said, and 
whether the train went past a red signal or not.  I just have a bad 
feeling that they saw a green and kept on going.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toll signs on 101 report your transponder setting]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-10T03:50:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a little bit of Silicon Valley local flavor for a change.  We 
have this freeway that runs from San Jose to San Francisco called US 
101, or around here, just "101".  (Southern California has it too, but 
they call it "the" 101.  That's how we detect invaders.)  Anyway, this 
thing is usually eight or more lanes up and down the peninsula, and it's 
had a "diamond" or car pool lane on the #1 (innermost/"fast") lane for 
many years.  You had to have a certain number of people in the car (or 
some other conditions met) during certain hours (AM and PM rush, 
weekdays), or you'd be in for a hefty ticket.


How does the system know what to charge you?  Well, you either have an 
old-style toll transponder that always bills you as a solo driver, or 
you have a new-style transponder with a 1/2/3+ switch that tells the 
road how to handle you.


Think about what this does to enforcement.  Now, instead of just "is 
there a vehicle in the lane", "is it the right time during a weekday", 
and "how many people are in the car", now it's also a matter of "do they 
have their transponder set properly".


Check this out.



CHP
could roll up on them and give them a ticket.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A parasitic RPC service that broke core dumps]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T04:39:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I already told a
story
about how you can hose your machine by pointing the Linux kernel at a 
custom core dump handler and then have that handler fail to function.  
This'll clog up the pipe (really), and then everything else will just 
stack up behind it.  Pretty soon, every crashing process will be stuck 
just the same.


Once upon a time, in a big company environment, someone decided that 
they wanted to provide a service to other things running on the same 
Linux box.  But, instead of either writing Yet Another Service (tm) 
that would go through release processes and all of that good stuff, they 
went for a different design entirely.


There are so many problems with this.  You have the issue of a "server" 
that appears out of thin air depending on who or what starts first on 
the mac…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A sysadmin's rant about feed readers and crawlers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-08T17:49:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If a web site makes an RSS or Atom feed available, it's not a bad idea 
to poll it from time to time.  Actually doing that poll like a good 
netizen (remember that concept?) takes a little attention to detail.


Given the reality of the situation, does it make sense to poll every 10 
seconds?  Probably not, right?  Someone set up something like that and 
left it running for a couple of months until I finally noticed it and 
dealt with it myself.


Given this, you can keep track of the "Last-Modified" header when you 
get a copy of the feed.  Then, you can turn around and use that same 
value in an "If-Modified-Since" header the next time you come to look 
for an update.  If nothing's changed, the web server will notice it's 
the same as what it already has, and it'll send you a HTTP 304 co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editing stuff in prod]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-05T21:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a concept: "ssh to prod and edit directly on the machine" is 
generally bad news.


I should point out that I didn't know this person and had no idea how 
they would respond to such feedback - it might have been fine!  They 
might be a well-adjusted person who can take a request like that and not 
turn it around into a full-on nuclear attack.  But, I didn't know either 
way.


At some point, I actually had a meeting with this developer for some 
other reason, and what happened was kind of amazing.  First thing, he 
brought it up and asked me about it.  I said something like, "well, I 
didn't want to get into it, but since you asked", and proceeded into 
something along the lines of "obviously it would be best if you didn't 
do that - sshing in and twiddling Python files on the actual production 
AWS instance of the service".


"But... I suspect you are doing it for some reason?"


My response was... I hope... reasonable: "So as much as I would love to 
say 'don't do that!!!', I'm not going to stand in the way of you 
literally doing your job.  So please proceed with care, and keep an eye 
open for some day when (first dumb thing) and (second dumb thing) aren't 
problems any more and you need not do this any more."


It was either "edit in prod" or endure DAY LONG development cycles: make 
a change, wait 24 hours, come back tomorrow, and try it again.  That's 
how broken it was.


The best part about this was that we had a totally reasonable 
conversation about it.  It's the kind of thing which had become a rare 
commodity in those days at that place.


Would I expect someone else to go to that level of insanity every single 
time they just want to get their job done?  Absolutely not.

Editing files in prod to develop them?  That's bad news.  Deliberately 
rigging tunnels to spoof a connection from prod?  That's also bad news.  
Having to do them to get your job done?  You might be in the bad place.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's now your fault they don't know about it]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-04T00:14:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quite a while back, I wrote a post that basically went like this: if 
someone has a problem with someone else or something that person is 
doing, they're going to find a way to get to "no".  They will find some 
reason, some excuse, or some problem with it.  They'll bring up a point 
and you'll show that this is not in fact a thing.  They will then pivot 
again and again.


But, as I said, that was back then, and this time I'm talking about 
something else: when it happens in person with a coworker.  I had an 
experience like this a few years back, and figured I'd share how it goes 
for the sake of others who might not have encountered it yet, or who 
have and thought they were alone in this.


Coworker: There are no docs for [this thing you're doing].


Coworker: You could make a wiki pag…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universally unique identifier?  Sometimes...]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-02T03:44:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a short one since it's somewhere between a random bit of 
"grab some popcorn" amusement and a "huh, that might be a problem some 
day".  In short, it looks like every Raspberry Pi filesystem installed 
from any given release image probably ends up with the same
UUID.


For instance, if you downloaded the "lite" version of Raspbian between 
roughly November 8th and January 28th, you probably got a file called 
2021-10-30-raspios-bullseye-armhf-lite.zip.  Inside, there's an image, 
and the idea is that you dump that straight to your SD card, cram it in 
the Pi, and off you go.  The second partition on that image is an ext4 
filesystem which was created on some build machine somewhere.  The UUID 
on it never gets "evolved" to something else after the install.


You can see it inside the image itself here:


Or, if you actually installed a few of these things like I did over the 
past couple of months, you can just 'tune2fs -l /dev/mmcblk0p2' and see 
the same value in there.


Don't end up with a pile of SD cards on your desk and think "I know, 
I'll use the filesystem UUIDs to track which one goes where", in other 
words.


If it's not breaking anything for you, it's probably best to just let it 
be.  Untangling a boot mess on these weird little boxes is anything but 
fun.

Note: if you're actually on a recent Raspberry Pi, odds are good that 
your /etc/fstab will be using *partition* UUIDs (PARTUUID=...) and not 
those of the filesystem.  If in doubt, use blkid to see what's what.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Command-V (or CTRL-V) is your "copilot"]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-28T22:54:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A reader wrote in asking what I thought about the whole GitHub "copilot" 
thing.  If you haven't heard of it yet, it's apparently this thing that 
was trained on a whole mess of repositories and their code, and you can 
"prompt" it and it'll spit out code that may or may not do what you 
want.  It doesn't seem to know about licensing (BSD, GPL, MIT, that sort 
of thing), or plagiarism, or any of that other good stuff.


This is actually a story about somewhere I used to work, and someone who 
was on one of my teams back in the day.  One day, I heard that one of 
the people in a far-away office had created some kind of tool that would 
let you look at the status of different machines - that is, Linux boxes. 
I don't remember the finer points of it or why this person even 
bothered, but they…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[C++ header files and inter-class connections]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-27T11:35:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are some interesting implications to the way that you have to 
handle references to other bits of code when you write a C++ header 
file.  There are things you can do which turn out to be suboptimal, and 
until or unless you work someplace with a coding style document or get 
some mentor who's already been there, you're likely to make some
mistakes.


Anyway, a common way to do this is to set up the outer class such that 
it has a pointer to the inner one.  You *could* have it just own it 
directly, but then that introduces problems.



 private:
  Bar bar_;



Of course, bar.h probably has its own dependencies which get #included, 
and so now you end up with this evil web of slow compiles.  It sucks.


What used to happen next is that someone would say, okay, let's make it 
a pointe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Results without all of the brackets]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-22T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, I
put forth
a bunch of API possibilities for the problem of needing to return a 
value but also indicating the lack of a value and being able to comment 
on why.  In it, the notion of a "wrapper" around a string was presented, 
such that it might look like "Result<string>", and those brackets 
started looking like a pain.  There was also the possibility of having 
something like "ResultString", but didn't that open the door to having a 
bunch of code duplication?


After this had existed for a while, the general happy feeling of having 
this stuff in place became infectious.  I wanted it to cover other 
things with it, too.  I wanted it to handle something a bit more 
complicated than a mere string, and so decided to try my hand at the 
template-wrangling metaprogramming cruft t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Returning values and errors]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-20T21:33:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you agree with the notion that you need to be able to tell the 
difference between the absence of a value and a value itself, then this 
has some impacts on the code you write.  If you want to keep 'em 
separated (so they can come out and play), then it gets you looking at 
your API designs in certain ways.


Imagine we're talking about a helper function that is intended to be run 
inside a program that's handling the access to a web page.  It's 
probably a CGI program, but it could also be buried inside some much 
bigger thing, too.  This is all about C++ styles, but you can probably 
see slices of other languages in here, too.


string UserIP() -- No more lifetime worries here, but oops, uh, well, 
what if we don't know what it is and need to provide an error?  If it's 
a CGI situatio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My "daily drivers", and what happened to Slackware here]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T21:48:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In
yesterday's post,
I mentioned taking my old Mac Mini out of the OS X/macos ecosystem and 
bringing it into Debian, and then what kind of hilarity followed when I 
attempted to install a Javascript linter (and it tried to drag in 180+ 
node-related packages).


Readers are advised that this post will probably contain 
definitely contains a even higher than usual amount of 
navel-gazing as I dish out the details of my setup.  My usual 
disclaimer of "this works for me and probably won't work for you, so if 
you have different tastes, then great, go with that" definitely applies 
here.


First of all, the one that most people actually notice is the actual box 
which is serving rachelbythebay.com, which at the moment is a box called 
snowgoose.  I had installed it in early 2020 as CentOS 8 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A twisted maze of dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T03:07:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh sure, everyone laughs about things having a lot of dependencies, but 
do they ever really think about the implications of having hundreds of 
teeny little libraries, all moving independently?  This is how it 
manifests in the real world.


My relative inexperience with Debian systems means I'm constantly being 
delighted to discover that such and such has already been packaged up 
and is just an apt command away.  Things that I would have done by hand 
in the years up to this point now have someone else worrying about them.


This is what happened next:


... huh.  The story basically ends there.  I'm going to handle this some 
other way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add 4740180 to the list of silly magic numbers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T08:11:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh dear.  The software fungus where bits of code take the
literal characters "HTTP" as a number
has expanded.  Now it has a variant: 4740180.


Where does this one come from?  
Go and gRPC, apparently!


I found this while searching the web for "1213486160" to see how things 
have been going in the past few years.  Unfortunately, it's still biting 
people all over the place.  There are far too many posts asking people 
to upgrade their software, or restart things, or do any number of 
useless rubber-chicken-waving techniques which ultimately will 
accomplish nothing.

When you see a funny-looking number, figure out where it comes from.
That's the only way to have any chance of understanding what's actually 
going on.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feedback: environments, old BBSes, Honda's 2022 bug]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T23:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yep, it's time for another round of reader feedback.

"process infection" story:

https://lwn.net/Articles/883547/):


If you do privileged execution of specific operations via IPC you get 
the guarantee that whatever is done, is done from a well-defined, 
pristine execution environment, without leaking context implicitly. The 
IPC message is the *full* vulnerable surface, and that's as minimal as 
it can get. And that's great.




Oh wow, thank you for mentioning that, unnamed reader!  I definitely 
read that post on LWN at some point in the past couple of days when the 
pkexec thing started going around.  It must have really worked its way 
into my head, and then eventually stirred up the memory of everything 
getting "nicely infected" at $OLD_JOB.


Every time I talk about trying to par…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A nice story about Unix processes "infecting" each other]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T19:24:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I once worked at a place that had an interesting little problem stemming 
from the way they managed machines and some of the fun side-effects 
processes can have on each other.  This is back in the pre-systemd days 
of running services, such that things tended to be started or restarted 
by someone or something that itself ran as root.  That is, if you 
started something, it might inherit one or more things from your 
environment.  Likewise, if you ran something with an unusual 
environment, it might bestow those "gifts" onto anything it happened to 
touch.


After locking themselves out of machines too many times, people 
generally learned that after you mess with a glibc upgrade, you restart 
the sshd listener on port 22.  Of course, they also had to learn to not 
whack EVERY sshd at the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An old photo of a very large BBS]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 30 years ago, I was given this picture.  I wanted to present it 
in a post all by itself to give it a chance to "sink in" before I went 
and used it in an analogy.  First, I'll just show the image and explain 
what you're looking at here.




I do remember the description from the back: this is a picture of *part 
of* something that was called the Software Creations BBS.  It was a 
multi-line bulletin board system where you could dial up and send 
messages to people, upload and download files, and (presumably) play 
online games ("doors") and anything else they cared to offer.

64 machines in a little space.  I have to assume 
they are at least 
286s (ATs, more or 
less), but it's impossible to tell from just this picture.  They could 
have been 386s or even 486s by that point, but …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One machine can go pretty far if you build things properly]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, so yesterday I 
posted
a picture of an old multi-line bulletin board system which had 
apparently taken over an entire bedroom with dozens of computers.  I 
mentioned that I intended to come back to the topic to throw in my own 
two cents, and so here we go.


Or, were you someone who found it horrific and wished there was a 
simpler way?  Did you wonder if it would be possible to pack all of that 
into one or maybe two boxes, instead?  Did you want a way to negate all 
of that complexity while still providing the same level of service?


Now, things are different.  I look at that and just sigh at the lost 
opportunities.  The actual amount of work being done on behalf of any of 
the users who are connected is tiny.  If we ignore the fact that the 
actual BBS software and related acc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>