<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html</id>
    <title>Ajour / Spitlo.com</title>
    <updated>2022-03-31T00:28:09.327Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.14.4</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3383</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/30/lawful-interception/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-30T08:23:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Hackers' code-free exploit: pretend to be cops: The predictable outcome of the Emergency Data Request system. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Hackers' code-free exploit: pretend to be cops (permalink) Back in 1994, Bill Clinton signed CALEA into law, mandating that all switches capable of carrying voice-traffic include a "lawful interception" backdoor that would let cops listen in on phone calls without having to actually physically access the switch itself. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communications_Assistance_for_Law_Enforcement_Act CALEA came with three promises: I. The backdoor would only be used by cops; II. Th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rejected Question Categories]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2600/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2600/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/rejected_question_categories.png" title="You can click to preorder to get a copy of What If? 2 when it comes out 9/13, assuming we all make it past the spider situation(?) on Tuesday(?)." alt="You can click to preorder to get a copy of What If? 2 when it comes out 9/13, assuming we all make it past the spider situation(?) on Tuesday(?)." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3378</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/28/dumb-money/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-28T16:26:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "The Byzantine Premium": The contradiction at the heart of Bitcoin advocacy. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "The Byzantine Premium" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my Medium column, "The Byzantine Premium," which examines the contradiction at the heart of cryptocurrency advocates' stated desire to have cryptos serve as money. https://onezero.medium.com/the-byzantine-premium-8411521db843 The article draws on Alex Pickard's article "Cryptocurrencies: The Power of Memes," for Research Affiliates, which breaks down the valuation of cryptos into four factors: https://www.researchaffiliates.com/…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Layout Algorithms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/understanding-layout-algorithms/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/understanding-layout-algorithms/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As front-end developers, we often learn CSS by focusing on individual properties. Instead, we should focus on how the language uses those properties to calculate layouts. In this blog post, we'll pop the hood on CSS and see how the language is structured, and how to learn it effectively.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spacecraft Debris Odds Ratio]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2599/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2599/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/spacecraft_debris_odds_ratio.png" title="You say this daily walk will reduce my risk of death from cardiovascular disease by 30%, but also increase my risk of death by bear attack by 300%? That's a 280% increased! I'm not a sucker; I'm staying inside." alt="You say this daily walk will reduce my risk of death from cardiovascular disease by 30%, but also increase my risk of death by bear attack by 300%? That's a 280% increased! I'm not a sucker; I'm staying inside." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3372</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/27/beware-of-the-leopard/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-27T16:39:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Amazon's relentless personal data foot-dragging: A system's purpose is what it does. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Amazon's relentless personal data foot-dragging (permalink) Sometimes, the best way to understand a failure is to contrast it with a success. Take Amazon, whose avowed "relentlessness" created next-day Prime delivery and AWS, with its power to instantaneously, continuously emit "buckets" of data. Amazon boasts endlessly about its efficiency, ease of use and speed – which means that whenever you find Amazon being inefficient, hard to use and slow, it's reasonable to assume that this is a deliberate choic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick survey: help improve the simulation options of browser developer tools]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7180</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/03/25/quick-survey-help-improve-the-simulation-options-of-browser-developer-tools/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-25T08:20:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Please help us to improve the emulation features of browser developer tools by filling out a two questions survey. Background We’re currently working on improving the findability of emulation features in the Microsoft Edge developer tools. Did you know that you can emulate different vision deficiences, dark and light schemes, forced colours and print layout […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Itch.io creators you need to follow & some of their beautiful work]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5310</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/itch-io-creators-you-need-to-follow-some-of-their-beautiful-work"/>
        <updated>2022-03-25T00:21:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Featured image from “space for black hair zine” by starybri A while ago I noticed that my itch following grew quite a bit (now over 5k followers!), but I don’t nearly follow enough people there. I think it goes without saying that itch.io is a wonderful platform. The way they let you follow creators there, and handle notifying you, has been invaluable to me in terms of finding those hidden gems. I have an unsorted growing curation-monstrosity called “the good stuff” that I mention any chance I get. So… I put out a call for people to share their projects...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graphic Designers]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2598/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2598/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/graphic_designers.png" title="They might make it past that first line of defense. For the second, you'll need some picture frames, a level, and a protractor that can do increments of less than a degree." alt="They might make it past that first line of defense. For the second, you'll need some picture frames, a level, and a protractor that can do increments of less than a degree." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New in 1.4.6: Using the DevTools Console inside Visual Studio Code and offline functionality]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7172</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/03/24/new-in-1-4-6-using-the-devtools-console-inside-visual-studio-code-and-offline-functionality/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-24T15:31:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We just released version 1.4.6 of the Edge DevTools for VS Code extension and the main change is that the Console tool is now available in the extension. 0:05 Console.log messages in VS Code 0:08 Test out some JavaScript 0:10 window object access 0:12 DOM convenience API support 0:15 Style changes 0:17 Console.table 0:20 Live […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The web is for everyone: Our vision for the evolution of the web]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68612</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/mozilla-webvision-future-of-web/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-23T15:58:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last two decades, the web has woven itself into the fabric of our lives. What began as a research project has become the world’s most important communication platform and an essential tool for billions of people.  But despite its success — and sometimes because of it — the web has real problems. People […]
The post The web is for everyone: Our vision for the evolution of the web appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bobby Holley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing a toy version of TLS 1.3]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/03/23/a-toy-version-of-tls/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/03/23/a-toy-version-of-tls/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-23T12:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Recently I’ve been thinking about how I find it fun to learn computer
networking by implementing working versions of real network protocols.
And it made me wonder – I’ve implemented toy versions of
traceroute, TCP and DNS.
What about TLS? Could I implement a toy version of that to learn more about how it works?
I asked on Twitter if this would be hard, got some encouragement and pointers for where to start, so I decided to go for it.
This was really fun and I learned a little more about how involved real
cryptography is – thanks to cryptopals, I already 100% believed that I should not invent my own
crypto implementations, and seeing how the crypto in TLS 1.3 works gave me even more of
an appreciation for why I shouldn’t :)
As a warning: I am really not a cryptography person, I will …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 23 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3361</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/23/false-genocide-negative/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-23T11:49:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Facebook's genocide filters are really, really bad: An AI that can't recognize its own training data is a very, very bad AI. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Facebook's genocide filters are really, really bad (permalink) In the fall of 2020, Facebook went to war against Ad Observatory, a NYU-hosted crowdsourcing project that lets FB users capture the paid political ads they see through a browser plugin that santizes them of personal information and then uploads them to a portal that disinformation researchers can analyze. https://pluralistic.net/2020/10/25/musical-chairs/#son-of-power-ventures Facebook's attacks were truly s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salary Negotiation]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2597/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2597/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/salary_negotiation.png" title="&quot;We can do 0.33 or 0.34, but our payroll software doesn't allow us to--&quot; &quot;NO DEAL.&quot;" alt="&quot;We can do 0.33 or 0.34, but our payroll software doesn't allow us to--&quot; &quot;NO DEAL.&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 22 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3356</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/22/myob/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-22T15:12:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Ban surveillance advertising: EFF's technological and legal proposal for a surveillance-free internet. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Ban surveillance advertising (permalink) I've been working with EFF for 20 years (!) now, and that association continues to pay dividends. EFF basically invented the idea of promoting tech policy positions that were informed by deep expertise in technology, law and human rights principles. This three-legged stool produces some remarkably sturdy proposals and policies – proposals that are legally sound, technologically achievable, and that advance important human rights causes in the digital …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 21 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3347</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/21/jeffersonian-v-hamiltonian/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-21T17:35:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "What Is Peak Indifference?": A theory of change. To make Big Tech better, make it smaller: Decreasing the salience of tech's errors is as important as reducing their prevalence. Brazil's "Remuneration Right" will strengthen Big Tech and Big Media: Fix ads, not snippets. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "What Is Peak Indifference?" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my recent Medium column, "What Is Peak Indifference?" in which I try to unpack my 2016 theory of change about the role that "self-radicalization" plays in addressing thorny problems. https://craphound.com/news/2022/03/21/what-…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Extension Helps Bring Movie Magic To Theaters Near You]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68599</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/extensions-addons/firefox-extension-helps-bring-movie-magic-to-theaters-near-you/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-21T16:06:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox is about to let you in on a little known industry secret…did you know some of the leading visual effects studios including Industrial Light & Magic (ILM), utilize Firefox to help make movie magic?  Color calibration — the process of adjusting colors in order to display images consistently in color and brightness across monitors […]
The post Firefox Extension Helps Bring Movie Magic To Theaters Near You appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Vasquez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Galaxies]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2596/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2596/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/galaxies.png" title="I know it seems overwhelming, but don't worry; I'm sure most of them have only a few stars, and probably no planets." alt="I know it seems overwhelming, but don't worry; I'm sure most of them have only a few stars, and probably no planets." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 20 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3342</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/20/a-walk-in-the-park/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-20T12:54:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Kathe Koja's Dark Factory: Taking Bohemia seriously. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Kathe Koja's Dark Factory (permalink) In "Dark Factory," Kathe Koja – an incredible, versatile writer who has pioneered multiple genres of fiction – presents an "immersive novel," about a high-stakes Bohemian party scene of mixed-reality artists, wealthy dilettantes, weird theorists and the very serious business of fun. http://darkfactory.club/ The titular Dark Factory is a hot mixed-reality club, where dancers, DJs, bartenders and artists combine music, neural interface signals, intoxicants and physical movement to create transformat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 18 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3334</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/18/greshams-carbon-law/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-18T15:44:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The market for carbon credit lemons: Bad money drives out good. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The market for carbon credit lemons (permalink) The idea of selling indulgences – the right to sin, for a price – has been controversial for the past 500+ years, since Jan Hus's condemnation of the practice. And yet here we are, in the age of carbon offsets, where forgiveneess for torching the planet is for sale. The fundamental premise of carbon offsets is that capitalism – that machine for socializing costs and privatizing gains – isn't the problem, it's the solution. Rather than having the state intervene to ban certain conduct, practices or products, we just need to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced Techniques]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2595/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2595/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/advanced_techniques.png" title="A blow from Emmy's Cutlass of Variations will transport the dragon to a corresponding symmetric position in the Noetherworld." alt="A blow from Emmy's Cutlass of Variations will transport the dragon to a corresponding symmetric position in the Noetherworld." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discussing two "holy war" topics at the same time]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/17/macedit/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-17T23:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cutting to the chase: text editors *and* tabs vs. spaces!  Ooooh!


I've had this thing called "e" for a while now.  It's a stupid little 
script which serves to do a couple of things.  It starts my 
editor
with a given file, and it kicks it with the right arguments to make it 
disable line wrapping and to make the [TAB] key actually put in two 
spaces.


So, my dumb script would use "-w -E -T 2" most of the time, except when it 
was running on a Makefile, at which point it would skip those args.  
Simple enough, right?


pico is back?  Yes indeed, on Macs, as of 12.3, pico is in fact back.  To 
make sure I wasn't imagining things, I tracked down a machine that hadn't 
been upgraded yet and checked there.  Sure enough, it was in fact nano and 
not pico.


macOS 12.3 has nano as a symlink... pointing to pico!


At some point, I switched from literal tab characters in my source code to 
blobs of spaces, probably due to using that style at work and not hating 
it.  So, somewhere along the line I actually started depending on nano 
behavior without realizing it.


As for the lack of a feature in pico itself, it's kind of strange, really.  
If you go digging into the source, they have this random.c with a function 
called tab which claims to "simulate tab stop" using spaces.  That said, I 
can't find any place where it would be called with the magic values which 
would make it behave that way.


It wouldn't surprise me if this switch is just more of Apple removing 
GPLed things from their OS - pico seems to use the Apache license.  They 
dumped bash for zsh (MIT license) at some point (Big Sur, I think), and 
now this?  Okay then.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3317</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/17/shareholder-socialism/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-17T18:12:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Late stage capitalism is weird capitalism: A planned economy run by Blackrock, Vanguard and State Street. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Late stage capitalism is weird capitalism (permalink) We are living in an era of extremely weird capitalism. American capitalism is usually described as a system in which top managers are rewarded with stock options, which incentivizes them to maximize returns to shareholders, who are so dispersed that they struggle to control companies by voting their stock. The potted history of this system goes like this: Gilded Age robber barons were horizontal tyrants, monopolizing single industries.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automatically starting a server when starting a debug session in VS Code]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7164</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/03/17/automatically-starting-a-server-when-starting-a-debug-session-in-vs-code/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-17T11:06:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in January, I posted about a launch.json file to turn VS code into an end-to-end web debugging environment. One of the features people told me was missing was to start and stop a server with the debugging session. So here is how to do this. We add two more lines to the existing `launch.json`, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3312</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/16/mightier-than-the-sword/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-16T14:40:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The role of prose quality in scholarship: Better-edited papers fare better in peer-reviewed journals. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The role of prose quality in scholarship (permalink) The dominant language of science and scholarship is English, and yet native English speakers do not have a monopoly on scientific and scholarly insights. Some non-native English speakers believe this puts them at a disadvantage when it comes to acceptance in peer-reviewed journals and citations, and pay language editors to improve their prose. But is it worth it? Does improving the quality of prose improve the perceived quality of scholarship, an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dumb things you can sometimes do with hard links]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/15/link/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-16T01:51:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a very old and stupid trick you could do with some filesystems in 
some situations back in the day... and might still be able to do in a 
few places today.


The problem is that while version X might eventually have an exploit, 
it'll get removed and it'll be replaced by version Y without that
particular hole.  By the time you get your hands on a tool to break into 
X, it'll be gone.


What you'd do is create a hard link pointing at the file you wanted to 
preserve, storing it in a spot which was writable by your account.  
Then, say, /usr/bin/sudo (because that never has security 
issues...) gets replaced at some point with a new file and you get to 
keep the old version.  When you get the tool to pop it, off you go!


Of course, these days, it's not quite so easy on the more modern systems 
you find.  Debian 11 here won't let me do it - it's EPERM city.  Rocky 8 
(so CentOS 8 and RHEL 8 too) also won't do it.  They both have some gunk
in /usr/lib/sysctl.d to lock this down.  But, my old Slackware 14.2 
install of my workstation let me do it the last time I tried about 
a year ago.  How about that, huh?  I bet it'd still work if I dug out 
the old drives and booted them up.


Incidentally, this is the magic sauce: /proc/sys/fs/protected_hardlinks
Read the man page for proc(5) to learn more about it.

here it is,
the thread I read a long time ago.  It's interesting to note that as far 
as I can tell, nothing actually changed upstream.  This left paranoid 
admins like me with no option but to use the (most excellent) Openwall 
patches to lock down this kind of stuff.  I used that on my machines at 
work which had non-staff users... just in case.


This whole situation is scary.  
Read more about it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consensus Time]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2594/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2594/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/consensus_time.png" title="Now, you may argue that the varying hour lengths and feedback effects would cause chaos. To which I say, yeah, and I'm also curious to see how the weekday cycle interacts with it! So, you in?" alt="Now, you may argue that the varying hour lengths and feedback effects would cause chaos. To which I say, yeah, and I'm also curious to see how the weekday cycle interacts with it! So, you in?" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-March Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42635</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/03/15/mid-march-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-15T15:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events March 21, I’m speaking at the GDC AI summit (at a fairly silly hour of my morning, but a relatively normal time for US-based people) about the work underlying Mask of the Rose, and especially the way NPC decision-making is exposed as part of the story. The Foundations of Digital Games conference will be … Continue reading "Mid-March Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 15 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3301</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/15/sanctions-financing/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-15T15:25:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Fight inflation with a windfall profits tax: Step one: tar. Step two: ??? Russian "ESG" investments were always about financing invasions and murder: Enjoy your rouble-denominated coupons, assholes. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Fight inflation with a windfall profits tax (permalink) Does your lifestyle involve consuming energy? If so, you may have noticed a tingly little sticker shock, especially at the gas pumps (but also everywhere else, from electric cars to home heating and beyond). Inflation, amirite? To hear corporate Democrats and snake-eyed Republican sociopaths tell it, the problem is that we just can't have nic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delightful React File/Directory Structure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/file-structure/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/file-structure/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-15T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How should we structure components and other files in our React apps? I've iterated my way to a solution I'm really happy with. In this blog post, I'll share how it works, what the tradeoffs are, and how I mitigate them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More stories about stacks of modems]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/14/modems/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-14T23:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in January, you might have seen my
post
about a very large BBS which seemed to solve for the problem of "how do 
we host a bunch of users" by having one physical box per user.  It might 
have been one physical box per *two* users, maybe, but it's hard to say.


Now, keep in mind digital cameras weren't easy to come by, so I have 
very few actual pictures.  I'll have to do a lot of explaining to make 
up for the lack of detail and alternate angles.  Clearly, I had no 
notion of ever using these pictures to tell stories 25+ years later.


Some friends at a local company had some bandwidth to spare (a T1 to 
Alternet somewhere, as I recall), so they parked a Zoom modem on one of 
their boxes and plugged it into a phone line.  We got an identical model 
to avoid cross-brand issues (Zoom m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noise cancellation for development]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7136</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/03/14/noise-cancellation-for-development/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-14T20:53:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like noise cancelling headphones. Using them, I can sleep better on planes and find much more detail in music I enjoy. In the office, they are a visual clue that I am currently unavailable for feedback as I want to concentrate on a task at hand. We live in times of a constant information […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 14 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3295</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/14/unhealthy-finances/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-14T16:44:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Surprise billing's death-spiral may suck in untold patients: The best time to kill Envision Healthcare was before it started (the second best time is now). Podcasting "Vertically Challenged": We need to investigate the companies Big Tech DOESN'T buy. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Surprise billing's death-spiral may suck in untold patients (permalink) The most remarkable thing about the surprise billing crisis is that its architects thought they could get away with it. Back in 2018, KKR (slogan: "Integrity. Trust. Partnership") bought Envision Health with a plan to make billions through Emergency Room fraud. https://plural…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deviled Eggs]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2593/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2593/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/deviled_eggs.png" title="The foil on the toothpick represents the blue flash." alt="The foil on the toothpick represents the blue flash." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrate tiny learning milestones]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/03/13/celebrate-tiny-learning-milestones/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/03/13/celebrate-tiny-learning-milestones/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-13T09:27:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Today I want to talk about – how do you know you’re getting better at programming?
One obvious approach is:
make goals
periodically check if you achieved those goals
if you did, celebrate
I kind of hate goals
Goals can be useful, but a lot of the time I actually find them stressful and
not that helpful. For example, here are a few goals I wrote down for myself 9
years ago:
write a nontrivial amount of C code that works and is used by actual people
contribute to an open source project in C
learn C++
9 years later, I have done 0 of those things. With the “goal” framing, it’s to
think of this as a bad thing! Like, I wanted to learn C++ and I didn’t! I still
can’t write C comfortably! Oh no! I guess I failed!
I find this framing depressing and unhelpful. In reality, I didn’t have any re…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking away the berries]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/12/chow/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-13T02:14:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I sometimes write the beginnings of posts but don't post them.  I still 
save them in case conditions change or other things happen and make me 
want to follow up on the topic.  In this case, I wrote something about 
offices before the whole COVID lockdown thing happened and people 
largely stopped going to offices every day.  With that in mind, let's 
proceed.


However, tech companies decided to go past this at some point and 
brought about this whole notion of "microkitchens".  This is where 
they'd put their branding on the coolers (instead of "Coca-Cola" or 
"Pepsi") and would load it up with every kind of fizzy sugary liquid 
they could get their hands on.  They'd have racks and racks of shelving 
packed with all sorts of interesting crunchy, sugary and carb-loaded 
snacks.  They'd a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 12 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3287</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/12/move-slow-and-fix-things/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-12T19:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A systemic (not individual) approach to content moderation: All the good stuff happens BEFORE the moderator gets involved. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2012 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A systemic (not individual) approach to content moderation (permalink) As Mike Masnick is fond of saying, "Content moderation at scale is impossible." The evidence for that statement is all around us, in the form of innumerable moderation gaffes, howlers and travesties: Blocking mask-making volunteers to enforce a mask-ad ban; Removing history videos while trying to purge Holocaust denial; Deplatforming antiracist skinheads when trying to block racist skinheads; Removing an image of Captai…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 11 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3282</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/11/a-market-for-flaming-lemons/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T16:58:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The SEC must not legitimize fake "carbon offsets": Net zero is not zero. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The SEC must not legitimize fake "carbon offsets" (permalink) Later this month, the SEC will release its "climate disclosure rule," which could be a turning point for the carbon offset "market," which is a presently a dumpster fire of accounting fraud, lies, and moral hazard: https://news.bloomberglaw.com/esg/green-groups-want-offsets-included-as-part-of-secs-climate-rule It's not clear whether the Commission will actually tackle offsets, and if they do, it's not clear whether they'll do so well. Certainly, the business …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at the outlying data points]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T07:04:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the fun things I used to do at a prior job was to dig through the 
raw data points which were collected from the *many* servers we had.  I 
could just pick an interesting-sounding metric and then would just ask 
the system to show me the top 10 or bottom 10 out of a population of 
thousands or more.


To get my feet wet with the whole "investigations" thing that we'd do, I 
started looking into this one day and chose one of the many temp sensors 
which were being logged by the servers.  I forget exactly which one it 
was, for there were many.  The CPUs logged it, the chassis logged it, 
the power supply logged it, and so on.  There were so many choices.


I went looking for a reason.  What could possibly explain this?  First 
off, it didn't line up with any obvious pattern in the host names.  The 
hosts were named for whichever team owned them, followed by a sequence 
number that was bumped any time a new one was provisioned.  There was no 
signal to be found in that.


There was more, though.  You could also see a "rack position" in this 
data, and now it started getting interesting.  It seems that all of the 
really hot machines had a rack position of something low, like 04 or 05, 
and never anything higher than that.  In fact, when looking at a whole 
rack, it was always the lowest number of all of the positions that were 
being used.  Now this was worth chasing!


It's good that I asked, since they told me something surprising: 
position 04 or 05 or whatever was the *bottom* of the rack.  Yes, 
somehow, the lowest machine in the rack was the hottest!  They found 
this interesting, too, and wound up digging into it.  Given that I was 
far away in a distant office, this was the best way for us to proceed.


The problem was that the bottommost server would have nothing below it 
but just open space until it got to the floor.  That space would not 
move air efficiently, and it obviously mattered.


This rolled out and my hot spots disappeared.  Fantastic!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Questions about construction trucks on train tracks]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/10/caltrain/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T01:26:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another day, another bit of local flavor, but this time it's something I 
wish I didn't have to write about.

wrote
about seeing a maintenance truck rolling down the Caltrain line in 
Mountain View.  It had a special attachment to let it stay on the rails.  
At no point did the arms come down for the crossing.  It managed to 
approach, then the people inside looked around and went through, and the 
arms never budged.  There were no flashing lights or bells.




caught fire.  A bunch of people were hurt.  More were shaken 
up.


I'm assuming their construction trucks don't trigger the "short the 
rails together to signal various things" logic, either.  This would 
mean that crossing arms stay up... and I have to assume it also means 
the signals along the way stay green instead of going red.

We will presumably hear more about whatever the signals said, and 
whether the train went past a red signal or not.  I just have a bad 
feeling that they saw a green and kept on going.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[False Dichotomy]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2592/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2592/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/false_dichotomy.png" title="There are two types of dichotomy: False dichotomies, true dichotomies, and surprise trichotomies." alt="There are two types of dichotomy: False dichotomies, true dichotomies, and surprise trichotomies." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic changed everything — even the way we use browser extensions]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68590</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/uncategorized/the-pandemic-changed-everything-even-the-way-we-use-browser-extensions/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-10T23:05:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On March 11, 2020 the World Health Organization declared COVID-19 a global pandemic. Within days, practically the entire planet was on lockdown. We went indoors and online.  So how did the sudden mass migration online impact browser extension usage? Pretty dramatically, it turns out. On this two-year mark of the start of the pandemic we […]
The post The pandemic changed everything — even the way we use browser extensions appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scott DeVaney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Latest Firefox Relay includes bigger attachment size and filters for promotional emails]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68542</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/latest-firefox-relay-includes-bigger-attachment-size-and-filters-for-promotional-emails/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-10T17:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since the public launch of Firefox Relay, thousands of users have signed up for our smart, easy solution that hides your real email address to help protect your identity. Thank you all for your tremendous support for our Firefox Relay product. This signals a demand for people who want to preserve their privacy by limiting […]
The post Latest Firefox Relay includes bigger attachment size and filters for promotional emails appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use undocumented web APIs]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/03/10/how-to-use-undocumented-web-apis/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/03/10/how-to-use-undocumented-web-apis/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-10T09:03:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! A couple of days I wrote about tiny personal programs, and I mentioned that
it can be fun to use “secret” undocumented APIs where you need to copy your
cookies out of the browser to get access to them.
A couple of people asked how to do this, so I wanted to explain how because
it’s pretty straightforward. We’ll also talk a tiny bit about what can go
wrong, ethical issues, and how this applies to your undocumented APIs.
As an example, let’s use Google Hangouts. I’m picking this not because it’s the
most useful example (I think there’s an official API which would be much more
practical to use), but because many sites where this is actually useful are
smaller sites that are more vulnerable to abuse. So we’re just going to use
Google Hangouts because I’m 100% sure that the Google Hangou…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toll signs on 101 report your transponder setting]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/09/toll/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-10T03:50:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a little bit of Silicon Valley local flavor for a change.  We 
have this freeway that runs from San Jose to San Francisco called US 
101, or around here, just "101".  (Southern California has it too, but 
they call it "the" 101.  That's how we detect invaders.)  Anyway, this 
thing is usually eight or more lanes up and down the peninsula, and it's 
had a "diamond" or car pool lane on the #1 (innermost/"fast") lane for 
many years.  You had to have a certain number of people in the car (or 
some other conditions met) during certain hours (AM and PM rush, 
weekdays), or you'd be in for a hefty ticket.


How does the system know what to charge you?  Well, you either have an 
old-style toll transponder that always bills you as a solo driver, or 
you have a new-style transponder with a 1/2/3+ switch that tells the 
road how to handle you.


Think about what this does to enforcement.  Now, instead of just "is 
there a vehicle in the lane", "is it the right time during a weekday", 
and "how many people are in the car", now it's also a matter of "do they 
have their transponder set properly".


Check this out.



CHP
could roll up on them and give them a ticket.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Want to improve Developer Tools in Microsoft Edge? File an issue on Github]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7131</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/03/09/want-to-improve-developer-tools-in-microsoft-edge-file-an-issue-on-github/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T19:31:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we released a new GitHub repository for the Developer Tools in Microsoft Edge where you can file issues about problems, bugs and feattures you would like to see. You can also view the list of existing issues and add your comments. There’s an official blog post on the Microsoft Edge blog but here’s why […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 09 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3272</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/09/turkeys-voting-for-christmas/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T15:42:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The cruelty isn't the point: The point is power. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The cruelty isn't the point (permalink) When confronted with Texas's cruel, vicious trans bill – which allows the state to take children away from their parents if they allow their kids to get life-saving, gender-affirming medical treatments – it's easy to think that "the cruelty is the point." But as Jamie Gardner writes in Jacobin, "they're just assholes" doesn't have much explanatory power. Neither assholes nor trans people are modern innovations, so why is it that this law was introduced now? https://jacobinmag.com/2022/03/gop-republicans-texas-…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A parasitic RPC service that broke core dumps]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/08/core/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T04:39:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I already told a
story
about how you can hose your machine by pointing the Linux kernel at a 
custom core dump handler and then have that handler fail to function.  
This'll clog up the pipe (really), and then everything else will just 
stack up behind it.  Pretty soon, every crashing process will be stuck 
just the same.


Once upon a time, in a big company environment, someone decided that 
they wanted to provide a service to other things running on the same 
Linux box.  But, instead of either writing Yet Another Service (tm) 
that would go through release processes and all of that good stuff, they 
went for a different design entirely.


There are so many problems with this.  You have the issue of a "server" 
that appears out of thin air depending on who or what starts first on 
the mac…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qua]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2591/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2591/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/qua.png" title="Qua qua qua is the sine qua non of sine qua non qua sine qua non." alt="Qua qua qua is the sine qua non of sine qua non qua sine qua non." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recommended Reading Roundup #2]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5299</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/recommended-reading-roundup-2"/>
        <updated>2022-03-08T22:31:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is my second roundup of recommended reading, in which I share articles (or threads, or youtube videos…) that bring awareness to issues that I feel are desperately underrepresented. Like I said in my first roundup… “I’m also going to try to focus on sharing things relating to marginalized groups in Europe, as they relate to my own family’s history or (complicated) identity (Eastern Europe and the Balkans).” Doing this will continue to be especially important to me as I work on BlueSuburbia. You can read about my plans for the project in my announcement post here. If you find...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3267</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/08/three-freedoms/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-08T19:59:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How and why to break up Big Tech: My new Locus column, "Vertically Challenged." The Dawn of Everything: An essential reminder that we are in charge of our own destiny. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How and why to break up Big Tech (permalink) My latest Locus Magazine column is "Vertically Challenged," an analysis of why and how to break up Big Tech, and the changing narratives of tech leaders that make these breakups likely. https://locusmag.com/2022/03/cory-doctorow-vertically-challenged/ Science fiction has always trafficked in tales of supergenius business tycoons – sometimes as heroes whose singular vision shines through ou…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A sysadmin's rant about feed readers and crawlers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/07/get/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-08T17:49:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If a web site makes an RSS or Atom feed available, it's not a bad idea 
to poll it from time to time.  Actually doing that poll like a good 
netizen (remember that concept?) takes a little attention to detail.


Given the reality of the situation, does it make sense to poll every 10 
seconds?  Probably not, right?  Someone set up something like that and 
left it running for a couple of months until I finally noticed it and 
dealt with it myself.


Given this, you can keep track of the "Last-Modified" header when you 
get a copy of the feed.  Then, you can turn around and use that same 
value in an "If-Modified-Since" header the next time you come to look 
for an update.  If nothing's changed, the web server will notice it's 
the same as what it already has, and it'll send you a HTTP 304 co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disney and Pixar’s “Turning Red” movie Browser Wallpapers only available on Firefox for Android and iOS]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68516</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/disney-and-pixars-turning-red-movie-browser-mobile-wallpapers/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-08T14:04:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month we created new Firefox desktop colorways celebrating Disney and Pixar’s “Turning Red” streaming only on Disney+ March 11 (subscription required. 18+ to subscribe). It’s a fun way to show your personality by changing the way your Firefox browser looks, with colors and moods inspired by some of the main characters in the film. […]
The post Disney and Pixar’s “Turning Red” movie Browser Wallpapers only available on Firefox for Android and iOS appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some tiny personal programs I've written]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/03/08/tiny-programs/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/03/08/tiny-programs/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-08T08:35:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was talking to a friend last summer about what resources might be helpful for
folks learning to program. My friend said they thought some people might
benefit from a list of small and fun programming projects – the kind of thing
you can do in an evening or weekend.
So let’s talk about that! I like to write small programs that have some
marginal utility in my life. Kind of like this:
ah! A minor problem in my life!
I know, I bet I can solve this problem with CODE. YAY.
4 hours of happy programming ensues
This isn’t always the most practical (many of the problems I’ve
solved with programming could have been solved in less time in other ways), but
as long as your goal is actually to have fun programming and your programs
don’t hurt anyone else, I think this is a great approach :)
So here ar…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3261</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/07/infrastructure-bill/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-07T16:55:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "All (Broadband) Politics Are Local": A chance for individuals to make a difference. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "All (Broadband) Politics Are Local" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read "All (Broadband) Politics Are Local," my https://gameraboy2.tumblr.com/post/678083489397145600/hellion-was-her-brand-lariat-story-magazineMedium column about the horrific state of US broadband, the pandemic's heightening of the contradictions, and the near-miraculous shift in US policy and political will for rolling out universal fiber: https://doctorow.medium.com/all-broadband-politics-are-local-e103967a0f0…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Bike Generator with Control Panel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2022/03/how-to-build-bike-generator.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2022/03/how-to-build-bike-generator.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-07T01:20:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We built a pedal-powered generator and controller, which is practical to use as an energy source and exercise machine in a household — and which you can integrate into a solar PV system. We provide detailed plans to build your own, using basic skills and common hand tools. Image: The bicycle generator in the living room. CONTENTS ARTICLE Introduction The bike generator Why a vintage exercise bike with flywheel? How much power does it produce? The art of pedal power: what are the challenges? Matching the voltage Matching the current Charging batteries The dashboard: how to address these challenges? Matching the voltage: buck and boost converters Matching the current: switchable circuits and dimmers How to use the bike: experiments Corded...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>LOW-TECH MAGAZINE</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Shouldn't Complain]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2590/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2590/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/i_shouldnt_complain.png" title="Bald-faced hornets are only a 2 on the Schmidt pain index, so I shouldn't complain. The tennis ball ejected from the dryer exhaust vent could have ricocheted off the nest of a much higher-scoring insect before knocking me off the ladder. Really, I'm lucky." alt="Bald-faced hornets are only a 2 on the Schmidt pain index, so I shouldn't complain. The tennis ball ejected from the dryer exhaust vent could have ricocheted off the nest of a much higher-scoring insect before knocking me off the ladder. Really, I'm lucky." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 06 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3252</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/06/i-want-to-do-it-now-make-me-do-it/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-06T17:13:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Epistasix (1920)/Medical Society of the University of TorontoToday's links Student debt strike called for May 1: If Biden won't fulfill his campaign promise, we'll do it for him. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Student debt strike called for May 1 (permalink) One of Biden's most conspicuously broken campaign promises is student debt cancellation. This isn't a nightmare from the Machin Synematic Universe, either: Biden can cancel student debt on his own, at the stroke of a pen, in the form of an Executive Order. https://debtcollective.org/flick-of-a-pen/ Biden has the legal power to erase 100% of outstanding federal student debt. It's…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editing stuff in prod]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/05/prod/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-05T21:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a concept: "ssh to prod and edit directly on the machine" is 
generally bad news.


I should point out that I didn't know this person and had no idea how 
they would respond to such feedback - it might have been fine!  They 
might be a well-adjusted person who can take a request like that and not 
turn it around into a full-on nuclear attack.  But, I didn't know either 
way.


At some point, I actually had a meeting with this developer for some 
other reason, and what happened was kind of amazing.  First thing, he 
brought it up and asked me about it.  I said something like, "well, I 
didn't want to get into it, but since you asked", and proceeded into 
something along the lines of "obviously it would be best if you didn't 
do that - sshing in and twiddling Python files on the actual production 
AWS instance of the service".


"But... I suspect you are doing it for some reason?"


My response was... I hope... reasonable: "So as much as I would love to 
say 'don't do that!!!', I'm not going to stand in the way of you 
literally doing your job.  So please proceed with care, and keep an eye 
open for some day when (first dumb thing) and (second dumb thing) aren't 
problems any more and you need not do this any more."


It was either "edit in prod" or endure DAY LONG development cycles: make 
a change, wait 24 hours, come back tomorrow, and try it again.  That's 
how broken it was.


The best part about this was that we had a totally reasonable 
conversation about it.  It's the kind of thing which had become a rare 
commodity in those days at that place.


Would I expect someone else to go to that level of insanity every single 
time they just want to get their job done?  Absolutely not.

Editing files in prod to develop them?  That's bad news.  Deliberately 
rigging tunnels to spoof a connection from prod?  That's also bad news.  
Having to do them to get your job done?  You might be in the bad place.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3248</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/05/this-telegrams-a-rush/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-05T15:37:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How to be safer while using Telegram in Russia and Ukraine: A guide from EFF's Eva Galperin. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2007, 2012 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How to be safer while using Telegram in Russia and Ukraine (permalink) Those of us with roots in Ukraine and Russia have a somewhat different picture of events as they unfold. In addition to viral videos, OSINT, pundits, and even sensible commentary, we're also part of heartbreaking conversations with our families. My own roots are in Russia, Ukraine, Poland, Belarus and Romania. The messages I've received from my cousins aren't for public consumption, but suffice to say they've been haunting and frightening. I'm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 04 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3242</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/04/londongrad/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-04T15:46:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How English libel law enables Russian kleptocrats: Tories and Putin's cronies are both impedance-matched and comorbid. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How English libel law enables Russian kleptocrats (permalink) Given the Current Circumstances, now is a good time to revisit the special relationship between UK elites – lawyers, estate agents, legislators – and Russian oligarchs, which was brilliantly documented in a Dec 2021 report from Chatham House: https://www.chathamhouse.org/2021/12/uks-kleptocracy-problem/01-introduction I wrote about this in early January, drawing a comparison between the manifest compatibility betwe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's now your fault they don't know about it]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/02/wrong/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-04T00:14:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quite a while back, I wrote a post that basically went like this: if 
someone has a problem with someone else or something that person is 
doing, they're going to find a way to get to "no".  They will find some 
reason, some excuse, or some problem with it.  They'll bring up a point 
and you'll show that this is not in fact a thing.  They will then pivot 
again and again.


But, as I said, that was back then, and this time I'm talking about 
something else: when it happens in person with a coworker.  I had an 
experience like this a few years back, and figured I'd share how it goes 
for the sake of others who might not have encountered it yet, or who 
have and thought they were alone in this.


Coworker: There are no docs for [this thing you're doing].


Coworker: You could make a wiki pag…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Outlet Denier]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2589/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2589/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/outlet_denier.png" title="There are regularly placed bumps on the underside just the right size to press the rocker switch on the power strip." alt="There are regularly placed bumps on the underside just the right size to press the rocker switch on the power strip." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The website security ecosystem protects individuals against fraud and state-sponsored surveillance. Let’s not break it.]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68528</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/security/mozilla-eff-cybersecurity-experts-publish-letter-on-dangers-of-article-452-eidas-regulation/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-03T21:44:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Principle four of the Mozilla Manifesto states that “Individuals’ security and privacy on the internet are fundamental and must not be treated as optional.” We’ve made real progress on improving security on the Internet, but unfortunately, a draft law under discussion in the EU – the eIDAS Regulation – threatens to reverse that progress. Mozilla […]
The post The website security ecosystem protects individuals against fraud and state-sponsored surveillance. Let’s not break it. appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Rescorla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 02 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3230</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/02/shadow-banking-2-point-oh/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-02T14:53:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Defi and Shadow Banking 2.0: Leverage, rigidity and bank runs. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Defi and Shadow Banking 2.0 (permalink) 14 year ago, the world's financial system came to the brink of collapse. Central banks scrambled to react. Businesses shuttered. People lost their homes. Many governments fell. Faith in our institutions shattered. The Occupy movement was launched. So was Bitcoin. What brought on the Great Financial Crisis? The "shadow banking system" – a system of unregulated financial activities that are just like their regulated cousins, except that they're, well, unregulated. The GFC was precipitated by "financial innovation": new tricks that allowed …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universally unique identifier?  Sometimes...]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/03/01/uuid/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-02T03:44:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a short one since it's somewhere between a random bit of 
"grab some popcorn" amusement and a "huh, that might be a problem some 
day".  In short, it looks like every Raspberry Pi filesystem installed 
from any given release image probably ends up with the same
UUID.


For instance, if you downloaded the "lite" version of Raspbian between 
roughly November 8th and January 28th, you probably got a file called 
2021-10-30-raspios-bullseye-armhf-lite.zip.  Inside, there's an image, 
and the idea is that you dump that straight to your SD card, cram it in 
the Pi, and off you go.  The second partition on that image is an ext4 
filesystem which was created on some build machine somewhere.  The UUID 
on it never gets "evolved" to something else after the install.


You can see it inside the image itself here:


Or, if you actually installed a few of these things like I did over the 
past couple of months, you can just 'tune2fs -l /dev/mmcblk0p2' and see 
the same value in there.


Don't end up with a pile of SD cards on your desk and think "I know, 
I'll use the filesystem UUIDs to track which one goes where", in other 
words.


If it's not breaking anything for you, it's probably best to just let it 
be.  Untangling a boot mess on these weird little boxes is anything but 
fun.

Note: if you're actually on a recent Raspberry Pi, odds are good that 
your /etc/fstab will be using *partition* UUIDs (PARTUUID=...) and not 
those of the filesystem.  If in doubt, use blkid to see what's what.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Party Quadrants]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2588/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2588/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/party_quadrants.png" title="Single-elimination might provide more drama, but I think we can all agree that a comprehensive numerical scoring system will let us better judge the party's winner." alt="Single-elimination might provide more drama, but I think we can all agree that a comprehensive numerical scoring system will let us better judge the party's winner." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to make sure you aren’t spreading misinformation online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68508</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/spotting-misinformation-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-01T17:55:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Facts can be empowering during uncertain times, and perhaps there’s no fact-finding tool more accessible than the internet. But as past years have taught us, the internet can also mislead — to dangerous lengths. We know when world events are scary, the internet gets loud and overwhelming. So here are three best practices to spot […]
The post How to make sure you aren’t spreading misinformation online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Mar 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3220</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/03/01/reit-modernization-act/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-01T17:28:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How "hollowed" hotels are destroying worker rights: REITs aren't just for money laundering. Hey look at this: Delights to delectate. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How "hollowed" hotels are destroying worker rights (permalink) The Real Estate Investment Trust is (REIT) a sixties-era tax shelter designed to allow mom-and-pop investors to buy into income properties. REITs are exempt from corporate tax, but they're also prohibited from managing the buildings they own. Banning REITs from management roles was supposed to scare off rich people looking for a tax break and keep REITs firmly in the realm of the "little guy." But as with any tax-shelter, the super-rich used REIT…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“RPG In A Box” is a cool tool! (an alternative game development curation)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5286</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/rpg-in-a-box-is-a-cool-tool-an-alternative-game-development-curation"/>
        <updated>2022-03-01T02:25:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[– RPG in a Box by Zeromatrix I know I probably say this in every one of my Tool posts, but I’m constantly amazed by the breadth of work that’s out there from developers who are making independent tools. Just when you think you’ve seen it all a new take on “how to be creative on your computer” surfaces, and you fall in love with it all over again. I’ve written these tool roundups so much that I started a “Tools” category, and my Cool Tools itch curation keeps growing. I didn’t think this is something you could keep up...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Me & Tinnitus: entry 5 [blog]]]></title>
        <id>me-and-tinnitus-entry-5</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/03/01/me-and-tinnitus-entry-5"/>
        <updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a few months since I last wrote about my tinnitus and since there's been some change (sadly not positive) but also I've had a few people contact me asking for advice, and though I'm terrible on email, perhaps I can offer some here.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Command-V (or CTRL-V) is your "copilot"]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/28/copilot/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-28T22:54:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A reader wrote in asking what I thought about the whole GitHub "copilot" 
thing.  If you haven't heard of it yet, it's apparently this thing that 
was trained on a whole mess of repositories and their code, and you can 
"prompt" it and it'll spit out code that may or may not do what you 
want.  It doesn't seem to know about licensing (BSD, GPL, MIT, that sort 
of thing), or plagiarism, or any of that other good stuff.


This is actually a story about somewhere I used to work, and someone who 
was on one of my teams back in the day.  One day, I heard that one of 
the people in a far-away office had created some kind of tool that would 
let you look at the status of different machines - that is, Linux boxes. 
I don't remember the finer points of it or why this person even 
bothered, but they…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of February Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42629</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/02/28/end-of-february-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-28T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events March 5 is the next meeting of the SF Bay Area IF Meetup. March 21, I’m speaking at the GDC AI summit (at a fairly silly hour of my morning, but a relatively normal time for US-based people) about the work underlying Mask of the Rose, and especially the way NPC decision-making is exposed … Continue reading "End of February Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3215</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/28/roll-over-john-sherman/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-28T17:17:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "We Should Not Endure a King": Antitrust is a leftist cause. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "We Should Not Endure a King" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read my Medium column "We Should Not Endure a King: Antitrust is a political cause, not an economic one," an essay addressed to my fellow leftists who are skeptical of antitrust as a "market" solution. https://marker.medium.com/we-should-not-endure-a-king-dfef34628153 It's a perfectly reasonable fear. For the past four decades, the entire antitrust discourse has been about economics – about when a company's anticompetitive conduct is "inefficient," based on some complex mathematical …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for February]]></title>
        <id>log.html#feb2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#feb2022"/>
        <updated>2022-02-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of February. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Adelie, released a program to create slideshows.
GrimGrains, added a new recipe: Bean chili.
Thousand Rooms, released Catalan version, a translation by Dani Sevilla.
100r.co, added a new project: Gravity water filter.
Uxn, Cancel(Andrew R.) released a new version of uxn32 with complete step debugging tools. Added new art for the Varvara docs..
Orca, implemented injections(YouTube), and J and Y wiring(YouTube).
Toys, released Uxn versions of Minesweeper(Mastodon), and Wireworld.
News
This month it was announced that we joined LibrePlanet 2022 as keynote speakers. The annual technology and social justice conference will be held virtually on March 19 and 20, 2022, with the theme Living Liberation. Our talk is named Software Doldrums.
Rekka is putting the finishing touches to Wiktopher, and Devine designed a game that the people of Irideri could be playing. The result was a dice game combining the capture mechanism of Go and the randomness of the Domino. Learn to play Hako. Each player has a Sonozai, a set of 4 dice on a rope. Merveillans have been making their own sets:
recycled construction wood set
3d-printed bracelet set
3d-printable concept
Rostiger has been making illustrated notes for Uxn, and they are fabulous.
Pino book club
We're reading Underland by Robert Macfarlane.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[For the Sake of Simplicity]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2587/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2587/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/for_the_sake_of_simplicity.png" title="For the sake of simplicity, gardeners are assumed to move through Euclidean space--neglecting the distortion from general relativity--unless they are in the vicinity of a Schwarzschild Orchid." alt="For the sake of simplicity, gardeners are assumed to move through Euclidean space--neglecting the distortion from general relativity--unless they are in the vicinity of a Schwarzschild Orchid." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3211</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/27/not-an-ad/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-27T17:22:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Amazon's $31b "ad business" isn't: They getcha coming and going. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Amazon's $31b "ad business" isn't (permalink) Looking at Amazon's quarterly financials, it would be easy to mistake the company's $31b ad division as a serious shift in the online advertising industry, but that would be a huge mistake. You see, Amazon's not really selling ads. Nearly all of that $31b is for an "ad" on Amazon itself: that is it's Amazon collecting billions from the sellers who rely on the company as their main retail channel, who are locked in a bidding war to buy the top spots in search and product pages. This is a huge shift for Amazon in every way. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[C++ header files and inter-class connections]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/26/include/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-27T11:35:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are some interesting implications to the way that you have to 
handle references to other bits of code when you write a C++ header 
file.  There are things you can do which turn out to be suboptimal, and 
until or unless you work someplace with a coding style document or get 
some mentor who's already been there, you're likely to make some
mistakes.


Anyway, a common way to do this is to set up the outer class such that 
it has a pointer to the inner one.  You *could* have it just own it 
directly, but then that introduces problems.



 private:
  Bar bar_;



Of course, bar.h probably has its own dependencies which get #included, 
and so now you end up with this evil web of slow compiles.  It sucks.


What used to happen next is that someone would say, okay, let's make it 
a pointe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greek Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2586/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2586/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/greek_letters.png" title="If you ever see someone using a capital xi in an equation, just observe them quietly to learn as much as you can before they return to their home planet." alt="If you ever see someone using a capital xi in an equation, just observe them quietly to learn as much as you can before they return to their home planet." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 24 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3200</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/24/uber-for-arbitration/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-24T14:21:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Mass arbitration attack could bring Intuit to its knees: Justice for the millions ripped off by Turbotax's "Free File" fraud. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Mass arbitration attack could bring Intuit to its knees (permalink) Ever hear of "binding arbitration?" That's a clause in a contract that says that you aren't allowed to sue the company you're doing business with, even if they cheat, maim or kill you. It was invented to let giant companies of equal size and power agree in advance not to spend billions and decades in court to resolve contractual disputes. Then, Federalist Society judges led by Antonin Scalia set about clearing the way for arbitration to be cr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some things about getaddrinfo that surprised me]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/23/getaddrinfo-is-kind-of-weird/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/23/getaddrinfo-is-kind-of-weird/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-23T08:33:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Here are some things you may or may not have noticed about DNS:
when you resolve a DNS name in a Python program, it checks /etc/hosts, but when you use dig, it doesn’t.
switching Linux distributions can sometimes change how your DNS works, for example if you use Alpine Linux instead of Ubuntu it can cause problems.
Mac OS has DNS caching, but Linux doesn’t necessarily unless you use systemd-resolved or something
To understand all of these, we need to learn about a function called
getaddrinfo which is responsible for doing DNS lookups.
There are a bunch of surprising-to-me things about getaddrinfo, and once I
learned about them, it explained a bunch of the confusing DNS behaviour I’d
seen in the past.
where does getaddrinfo come from?
getaddrinfo is part of a library called libc whic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rounding]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2585/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2585/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/rounding.png" title="I've developed a novel propulsion system powered by loss of precision in unit conversion." alt="I've developed a novel propulsion system powered by loss of precision in unit conversion." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 22 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3191</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/22/national-champions/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-22T16:07:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting Part III of "The Internet Heist": In which the cartel gives itself a veto over your family life. China hamstrings its Big Tech: "National champions" are neither. This day in history: 2007, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting Part III of "The Internet Heist" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read the final part of "The Internet Heist," my Medium series on the copyright wars' early days, when the entertainment and tech giants tried to leverage the digital TV transition into a veto over every part of our lives. https://onezero.medium.com/the-internet-heist-part-iii-8561f6d5a4dc In Part I, I described the bizarre Broadcast Flag project, where Hollywood studios and Intel collude…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Results without all of the brackets]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-22T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, I
put forth
a bunch of API possibilities for the problem of needing to return a 
value but also indicating the lack of a value and being able to comment 
on why.  In it, the notion of a "wrapper" around a string was presented, 
such that it might look like "Result<string>", and those brackets 
started looking like a pain.  There was also the possibility of having 
something like "ResultString", but didn't that open the door to having a 
bunch of code duplication?


After this had existed for a while, the general happy feeling of having 
this stuff in place became infectious.  I wanted it to cover other 
things with it, too.  I wanted it to handle something a bit more 
complicated than a mere string, and so decided to try my hand at the 
template-wrangling metaprogramming cruft t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 21 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3185</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/21/contra-nihilismum/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:05:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A(nother) massive Swiss banking leak: Sunshine won't disinfect anything on its own. The people's disruption: Tech rights are workers' rights. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A(nother) massive Swiss banking leak (permalink) Look, there's been another massive banking leak, this one from Credit Suisse, showing complicity in laundering money for the world's greatest monsters: human traffickers, despots, criminals. They're calling it Suisse Secrets. https://www.theguardian.com/news/2022/feb/20/credit-suisse-secrets-leak-unmasks-criminals-fraudsters-corrupt-politicians They had to call it that, because Swiss Leaks was already taken, for the 2015 UBS leaks that rev…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Headline Words]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2584/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2584/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/headline_words.png" title="Roundly-condemned headlinese initiative shuttered indefinitely." alt="Roundly-condemned headlinese initiative shuttered indefinitely." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Returning values and errors]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-20T21:33:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you agree with the notion that you need to be able to tell the 
difference between the absence of a value and a value itself, then this 
has some impacts on the code you write.  If you want to keep 'em 
separated (so they can come out and play), then it gets you looking at 
your API designs in certain ways.


Imagine we're talking about a helper function that is intended to be run 
inside a program that's handling the access to a web page.  It's 
probably a CGI program, but it could also be buried inside some much 
bigger thing, too.  This is all about C++ styles, but you can probably 
see slices of other languages in here, too.


string UserIP() -- No more lifetime worries here, but oops, uh, well, 
what if we don't know what it is and need to provide an error?  If it's 
a CGI situatio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things that used to be hard and are now easy]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/20/things-that-used-to-be-hard-and-are-now-easy/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/20/things-that-used-to-be-hard-and-are-now-easy/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-20T09:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I was talking to some friends the other day about the types of
conference talks we enjoyed.
One category we came up with was “you know this thing that used to be super
hard? Turns out now it’s WAY EASIER and maybe you can do it now!“.
So I asked on Twitter about programming things that used to be hard and are now easy
Here are some of the answers I got. Not all of them are equally “easy”, but I
found reading the list really fun and it gave me some ideas for things to
learn. Maybe it’ll give you some ideas too.
SSL certificates, with Let’s Encrypt
Concurrency, with async/await (in several languages)
Centering in CSS, with flexbox/grid
Building fast programs, with Go
Image recognition, with transfer learning (someone pointed out that the joke in this XKCD doesn’t make sense anymore)
B…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 19 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3180</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/19/now-we-are-two/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-19T15:35:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Pluralistic is two: Still at it! This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Pluralistic is two (permalink) Today is the second anniversary of the founding of Pluralistic, my multiplatform, non-metrics-driven, solo blog, founded in some haste after my unplanned (but overdue and amicable) departure from Boing Boing. For two years, I've been putting out a new edition nearly every day (550 posts, or 75%). Each edition has one or more posts, and many of the editions have consisted of one or two long essays. In some ways, Pluralistic's long form essays are the dividends for the 20+ years I've been a daily blogger. All those short pieces I've written over the preceding decades are …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-February Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42614</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/02/19/mid-february-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-19T13:27:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mask demo! This month’s link assortment is a few days later than usual; that’s because I was focused in the first half of February on launching the demo for Mask of the Rose, the new game I’ve been working on at Failbetter. Mask of the Rose is set in the Fallen London universe, but decades … Continue reading "Mid-February Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 18 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3174</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/18/broken-records/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-18T15:17:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Tech platforms' playbook inevitably produces dumpster-fires: Anil Dash's amazing "broken tech/content culture cycle." This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Tech platforms' playbook inevitably produces dumpster-fires (permalink) Very rarely, I find an article that I want to share, but whose every line so so perfect that I can hardly bear to summarize it because I just want to repost the whole thing, peppered with "HELL YEAH"s. That's how I feel about Anil Dash's "That broken tech/content culture cycle." https://anildash.com/2022/02/09/the-stupid-tech-content-culture-cycle/ Dash lays out a playbook for firms that claim to be "tech companies" but rely on cultural production to g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chorded Keyboard]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2583/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2583/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/chorded_keyboard.png" title="And even though it all went wrong / I'll stand before the lord of song / with nothing on my tongue but 'I don't understand, I swear I backed up my keyboard config before messing with it'" alt="And even though it all went wrong / I'll stand before the lord of song / with nothing on my tongue but 'I don't understand, I swear I backed up my keyboard config before messing with it'" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My "daily drivers", and what happened to Slackware here]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T21:48:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In
yesterday's post,
I mentioned taking my old Mac Mini out of the OS X/macos ecosystem and 
bringing it into Debian, and then what kind of hilarity followed when I 
attempted to install a Javascript linter (and it tried to drag in 180+ 
node-related packages).


Readers are advised that this post will probably contain 
definitely contains a even higher than usual amount of 
navel-gazing as I dish out the details of my setup.  My usual 
disclaimer of "this works for me and probably won't work for you, so if 
you have different tastes, then great, go with that" definitely applies 
here.


First of all, the one that most people actually notice is the actual box 
which is serving rachelbythebay.com, which at the moment is a box called 
snowgoose.  I had installed it in early 2020 as CentOS 8 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3158</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/17/live-by-the-swordlive-by-the-sword/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T17:32:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The last days of Myspace: Facebook is following the steep decline playbook. The child labor story hidden by the Great Resignation: Bosses want to turn kids into scabs. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The last days of Myspace (permalink) I hated Facebook from the start and couldn't wait for it to die. That was a pretty reasonable thing to expect. After all, I'd watched social networks from Sixdegrees on crash and burn as the network effects that drove their growth also drove their precipitous collapse. A system enjoys "network effects" if it increases in value as it adds users. Social networks are all about these effects: you join Facebook because your friends are there,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A twisted maze of dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T03:07:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh sure, everyone laughs about things having a lot of dependencies, but 
do they ever really think about the implications of having hundreds of 
teeny little libraries, all moving independently?  This is how it 
manifests in the real world.


My relative inexperience with Debian systems means I'm constantly being 
delighted to discover that such and such has already been packaged up 
and is just an apt command away.  Things that I would have done by hand 
in the years up to this point now have someone else worrying about them.


This is what happened next:


... huh.  The story basically ends there.  I'm going to handle this some 
other way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Americans deserve federal privacy protections and greater transparency into hidden harms online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68502</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/americans-deserve-federal-privacy-protections-and-greater-transparency-into-hidden-harms-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-16T21:45:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Privacy is fundamental and cannot be treated as optional. Companies and regulators need to work hand in hand to provide stronger privacy protections to people. Technical privacy protections by companies are complementary to privacy regulation and neither alone is sufficient.” Marshall Erwin Marshall Erwin, Mozilla’s Chief Security Officer, testified today before the Committee on House […]
The post Americans deserve federal privacy protections and greater transparency into hidden harms online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to secure your data in less than 10 minutes]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68476</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/privacy-security/how-to-secure-data-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-16T18:15:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data Privacy Day has come and gone. But here at Mozilla, helping educate people around online privacy is so important to us that we want to be your guide to protecting your data over the next four weeks. Save this page on Pocket, come back every Wednesday and find a couple of quick things you […]
The post How to secure your data in less than 10 minutes appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3155</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/16/unauthorized-paper/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-16T16:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The extremely shady "educational integrity" industry: From Proctorio to Honorlock. Oh great, there's DRM in printer PAPER now: Dymo was so preoccupied with whether or not they could, they didn't stop to think if they should. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The extremely shady "educational integrity" industry (permalink) The pandemic presented an opportunity to reconsider our seemingly immutable assumptions about life – for adults, anyway. We got the Great Resignation and "hybrid" work-from-home. Our kids got remote learning. Ugh. Don't get me wrong: remote learning has its advantages, especially for kids coping with physical and mental health issues, kids with pas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Trap]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2582/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2582/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/data_trap.png" title="It's important to make sure your analysis destroys as much information as it produces." alt="It's important to make sure your analysis destroys as much information as it produces." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 15 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3150</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/15/management-jesuits/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T17:18:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links McKinsey For Kids (no, really): Give us a child when they are seven and they are ours for life. Outing German spy agencies by mailing them Airtags: A threat-model parable. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading McKinsey For Kids (no, really) (permalink) McKinsey for Kids is a new website from the scandal-haunted consulting giants who proposed that Oxycontin-producers Purdue Pharma pay a bounty to pharma distributors based on the number of lethal overdoses in their territories. Its purpose is to teach kids to think like McKinsey Consultants. https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/mckinsey-for-kids/hungry-fish-baffled-farmers-and-what-happened-next "Chapter 1" of the p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox And Pixar Animation Studios team up to help you show your true colors]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68380</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/true-colors-with-firefox-pixar-animation-studios-turning-red/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“But maybe I like this new me.” The trailer for Disney and Pixar’s new film, “Turning Red,” streaming on Disney+ March 11, ends with Mei, its 13-year-old protagonist, considering a wild idea: acceptance. Maybe I like this new me. Yes, in her case the “new me” is becoming a giant red panda when she feels […]
The post Firefox And Pixar Animation Studios team up to help you show your true colors appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add 4740180 to the list of silly magic numbers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T08:11:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh dear.  The software fungus where bits of code take the
literal characters "HTTP" as a number
has expanded.  Now it has a variant: 4740180.


Where does this one come from?  
Go and gRPC, apparently!


I found this while searching the web for "1213486160" to see how things 
have been going in the past few years.  Unfortunately, it's still biting 
people all over the place.  There are far too many posts asking people 
to upgrade their software, or restart things, or do any number of 
useless rubber-chicken-waving techniques which ultimately will 
accomplish nothing.

When you see a funny-looking number, figure out where it comes from.
That's the only way to have any chance of understanding what's actually 
going on.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feedback: environments, old BBSes, Honda's 2022 bug]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T23:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yep, it's time for another round of reader feedback.

"process infection" story:

https://lwn.net/Articles/883547/):


If you do privileged execution of specific operations via IPC you get 
the guarantee that whatever is done, is done from a well-defined, 
pristine execution environment, without leaking context implicitly. The 
IPC message is the *full* vulnerable surface, and that's as minimal as 
it can get. And that's great.




Oh wow, thank you for mentioning that, unnamed reader!  I definitely 
read that post on LWN at some point in the past couple of days when the 
pkexec thing started going around.  It must have really worked its way 
into my head, and then eventually stirred up the memory of everything 
getting "nicely infected" at $OLD_JOB.


Every time I talk about trying to par…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 13 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3143</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/14/externalities/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T18:49:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting Part II of "The Internet Heist": Big Content wants to plug your A-Hole! Comprehensive synthesis of the technological, ecological and political critique of blockchainism: It's all about the externalities. Eating invasive species: How to structure an invasivorism that doesn't hunger for more invaders. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting Part II of "The Internet Heist" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read the second part of "The Internet Heist," a series of three articles about the weirdest, most far-reaching, most bonkers battle of the copyright wars of the early 2000s. https://onezero.medium.com/the-internet-heist-part-ii-cb2add31a4fb…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pop Quiz: What are 5 questions to ask yourself before taking that online quiz?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68461</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/online-quizzes-data-collection-privacy-tips/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T16:56:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Who hasn’t taken a quiz online to figure out what TV character you are most like, what city should you live in or what 90s song most represents you? These quizzes seem innocent enough. You put in the name of your high school best friend, you select the kind of pet you had growing up […]
The post Pop Quiz: What are 5 questions to ask yourself before taking that online quiz? appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The multiple meanings of "nameserver" and "DNS resolver"]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/14/some-dns-terminology/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/14/some-dns-terminology/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T12:31:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m working on a zine about DNS right now, so I’ve been thinking about DNS
terminology a lot more than a normal person. Here’s something slightly
confusing I’ve noticed about DNS terminology!
Two of the most common DNS server terms (“nameserver” and “DNS resolver”)
have different meanings depending on the situation.
Now this isn’t a problem if you already understand how DNS works – I can
easily figure out what type of “nameserver” is being discussed based on
context.
But it can be a problem if you’re trying to learn how DNS works and you don’t
realize that those words might refer to different things depending on the
context – it’s confusing! So I’m going to explain the different possible
meanings and how to figure out which meaning is intended.
the 2 meanings of “nameserver”
There are 2 ty…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health Stats]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2581/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2581/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/health_stats.png" title="You will live on forever in our hearts, pushing a little extra blood toward our left hands now and then to give them a squeeze." alt="You will live on forever in our hearts, pushing a little extra blood toward our left hands now and then to give them a squeeze." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 11 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3134</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/11/bezzlers-gonna-bezzle/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-11T19:02:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Big Lie that keeps the Uber bezzle alive: A credulous press continues to report massive losses as profitability. This day in history: 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Big Lie that keeps the Uber bezzle alive (permalink) Uber is (still) a bezzle ("the magic interval when a confidence trickster knows he has the money he has appropriated but the victim does not yet understand that he has lost it"). And every bezzle – every bezzle – ends. Uber entered the market with an absurd proposition, which they papered over with an idiotic narrative…which the world ate up with a spoon. The absurd proposition: Uber could use apps to reinvent taxis, and turn a low-margin business into a high-margin busines…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rest and Fluids]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2580/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2580/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/rest_and_fluids.png" title="Remember not to take it easy. Put a hot washcloth on your forehead, remain standing, and breathe dry air while taking lots of histamines. You need to give your body a chance to get sick again." alt="Remember not to take it easy. Put a hot washcloth on your forehead, remain standing, and breathe dry air while taking lots of histamines. You need to give your body a chance to get sick again." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 10 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3130</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/10/monopoly-begets-monopoly/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T20:53:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Welcome to the Palmerverse: Ada Palmer's Renaissance-informed science fictional futurism. SEC vs private equity ripoffs: Personnel really are policy. Neuromancer today: Eileen Gunn on the enduring significance and wonder of William Gibson. Gators and Amazon tag-team small sellers: Amazon's bad conduct is good for (a certain kind of) business. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Welcome to the Palmerverse (permalink) Today in Wired, Gregory Barber profiles my friend, colleague and collaborator Ada Palmer, an extraordinary writer, librettist, historian, scholar, activist and performer: https://www.wired.com/story/ada-palmer-sci-fi-future-weird-hand-progress/ Palmer has just w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A nice story about Unix processes "infecting" each other]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T19:24:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I once worked at a place that had an interesting little problem stemming 
from the way they managed machines and some of the fun side-effects 
processes can have on each other.  This is back in the pre-systemd days 
of running services, such that things tended to be started or restarted 
by someone or something that itself ran as root.  That is, if you 
started something, it might inherit one or more things from your 
environment.  Likewise, if you ran something with an unusual 
environment, it might bestow those "gifts" onto anything it happened to 
touch.


After locking themselves out of machines too many times, people 
generally learned that after you mess with a glibc upgrade, you restart 
the sshd listener on port 22.  Of course, they also had to learn to not 
whack EVERY sshd at the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Showing different titles depending if the tab is active or not]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7124</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/02/10/showing-different-titles-depending-if-the-tab-is-active-or-not/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T18:49:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just encountered a sneaky thing I had not seen, although it probably worked in 1999 already. A web site was showing a different title on the tab, depending on it being active or not. The whole trick is to use the blur and focus event handlers on the window to change the title. window.onblur […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 09 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3126</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/09/grievance-factory/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T19:17:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Litigation finance pits greed against greed: There was a late-stage captialism that swallowed a fly… Occupy the SEC on bank mergers: The Herfindahl-Hirschman Index considered harmful. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Litigation finance pits greed against greed (permalink) Early in the 19th century, political philosophers like Jeremy Bentham began to rail against champerty, whereby "unscrupulous nobles and royal officials would lend their names to bolster the credibility of doubtful and fraudulent claims in return for a share of the property recovered." https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Champerty_and_maintenance#History On its face, the practice of inviting investors to back …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tractor Beam]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2579/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2579/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/tractor_beam.png" title="Did you base the saucer shape on pop culture depictions of aliens, or was that stuff based on your ships? Does the rotational symmetry help with ... hey, where are you going?" alt="Did you base the saucer shape on pop culture depictions of aliens, or was that stuff based on your ships? Does the rotational symmetry help with ... hey, where are you going?" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3120</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/08/wall-street-landlords/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T17:26:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Pixels of You: A illustrated tale of love and photos. Wall Street's landlord business is turning every rental into a slum: And they're using public money to do it. UK Tories want a national database of porn-viewing habits: Oh fuck not this bullshit again. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Pixels of You (permalink) Pixels of You is a new young adult sf graphic novel, written by Ananth Hirsh and Yuko Ota and illustrated by Jenn Doyle, published today by Abrams. It's a sweet, smart tale of art, bitterness, enmity and camaraderie. https://www.abramsbooks.com/product/pixels-of-you_9781419749575/ Pixels' two protagonists are a pair of young women who have both won a covet…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy Preserving Attribution for Advertising]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68457</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/privacy-preserving-attribution-for-advertising/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advertising provides critical support for the Web. We’ve been looking to apply privacy preserving advertising technology to the attribution problem, so that advertisers can get answers to important questions without harming privacy. Attribution is how advertisers know if their advertising campaigns are working. Attribution generates metrics that allow advertisers to understand how their advertising campaigns […]
The post Privacy Preserving Attribution for Advertising appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Thomson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3115</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/07/broadcast-flag/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T16:41:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting part one of "The Internet Heist": My origin story, fighting the Broadcast Flag. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting part one of "The Internet Heist" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read the first part of "The Internet Heist," a three-part series I wrote for Medium on the "Broadcast Flag," which was invented 20 years ago, on my first day on the job at EFF. It's basically my origin-story. https://onezero.medium.com/the-internet-heist-part-i-3395769891b0 The Broadcast Flag was an incredibly gnarly, high-stakes digital technology issue. It combined no fewer than three esoteric fields – spectrum allocation, computer science, and copyright – and threa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recommended Reading Roundup #1]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5275</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/recommended-reading-roundup-1"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T00:15:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m going to try something new for this blog and that will be roundups of recommended reading. Here is the first! There’s a lot that I usually don’t get to share on my social media because that space is heavily game’s focused… so I thought of saving informative things I read, or quality resource, and then regularly sharing them on my blog. I’m also going to try to focus on sharing things relating to marginalized groups in Europe, as they relate to my own family’s history or (complicated) identity (Eastern Europe and the Balkans). I don’t get to talk about...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sword Pull]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2578/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2578/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sword_pull.png" title="Merlin really shouldn't leave his dirt bike lying around." alt="Merlin really shouldn't leave his dirt bike lying around." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 06 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3111</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/06/this-land-is-your-land/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-06T15:28:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Explaining UK Fair Dealing with Simpsons clips: An update to the classic "Fair(y) Use." Woody Guthrie, Songs and Art * Words and Wisdom: 332 pages of inspiration, joy and fascinating tales of a true American hero. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Explaining UK Fair Dealing with Simpsons clips (permalink) It's been 15 years since Bucknell U film prof Eric Faden made "A Fair(y) Tale," a short film that explains fair use by stringing together short, fair-use-qualifying clips from Disney movies. It remains an amazing accomplishment! https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BeKFAM892k4 Fair(y) Tale took 9 months to piece together as Faden painstakingly searched the corpus …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3104</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/05/time-for-some-game-theory/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-05T18:47:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How to design an anti-monopoly interop system: On the colossal bad faith of Subaru and Kia. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How to design an anti-monopoly interop system (permalink) A historical accident made Massachusetts a lab for studying how tech can serve monopolies, and the moves, countermoves and counter-countermoves show how businesses, tinkerers, governments and the public can liberate themselves from seemingly all-powerful monopolists. It all starts with Right to Repair. Companies love to monopolize the repair of their products. If the only place to get your broken stuff fixed is at its manufacturer's authorized depots, the manufacturer can move all kinds of v…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My hardware adventure with a Gameboy Pocket [blog]]]></title>
        <id>my-hardware-adventure-with-a-gameboy-pocket</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/02/05/my-hardware-adventure-with-a-gameboy-pocket"/>
        <updated>2022-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I bought this Gameboy Pocket off eBay in the hope that I could bring it back to life...

I'd seen this before and suspected that the game couldn't be loaded due to corruption during boot (on the GB side). I was wrong, but I definitely enjoyed the challenge!

Opening up the Gameboy up and took a peek, and yep, found game pak loading doberry had been messed with. Bit of a duff job on whoever tried to repair it before me - and it even looks like they spotted there was a short and tried to slice through it with a knife:

Pins A2 and A1 were definitely connected! Some flux and solder later and it looks more like this:

And now the Gameboy boots with a nice clean Nintendo logo. Except… it doesn't go past that point at all - and in fact the screen looks like it's doing some weird flash dance, goi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 04 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3095</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/04/up-your-nose/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T18:55:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A covid vaccine for your airways: The promising science of nasal spray vaccines. Rail monopolies destroyed the American supply chain: Heads they win, tails we lose. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A covid vaccine for your airways (permalink) The covid vaccine picture is awfully confusing. The current vaccines are doing a great job of preventing serious illness (at least, for people who are boosted), but they're not nearly so effective at preventing infection and transmission. What's more, the new variants are more contagious and less likely to cause severe infection, but they also appear to confer less immunity against re-infection: https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s how to watch the games with Firefox because we all need a winter distraction]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68430</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/how-to-watch-winter-games-multiple-videos-firefox/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T18:17:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If omicron canceled your winter plans, watching the Beijing games may be the next best thing. Can’t snowboard? See star athletes shred. Closed ski resort? Leave the poles to the pros. And yes, it feels like we just put out the flames on the torch — less than six months ago to be exact. But […]
The post Here’s how to watch the games with Firefox because we all need a winter distraction appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New York Times editorial director of games on creating her ideal corner of the internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68362</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/everdeen-mason-nytimes-director-of-games-internet-interview/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T17:44:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post The New York Times editorial director of games on creating her ideal corner of the internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sea Chase]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2577/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2577/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sea_chase.png" title="There are two rules on this ship: Never gaze back into the projection abyss, and never touch the red button labeled DYMAXION." alt="There are two rules on this ship: Never gaze back into the projection abyss, and never touch the red button labeled DYMAXION." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3090</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/03/liquidation-preference/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-03T20:23:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Money is power: A political economy parable (with a side of environmental racism). When crypto-exchanges go broke, you'll lose it all: The fatal flaw in the "neither fish nor fowl" gambit (there is such a thing as society). This day in history: 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Money is power (permalink) "Political economy" may sound like an obscure technical matter, but it's a really very simple (and incredibly important) idea: That the economy is inevitably political, and there is no way to depoliticize economic theory. That is, every aspect of economics – taxation, antitrust, contract and labor law, etc – is fundamentally political. There is no objective perch on which an economist can stand and decid…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update on Firefox Reality]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68415</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/update-on-firefox-reality/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-03T14:03:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla’s mission is to make sure the Internet remains open and accessible to all. Four years ago, we launched Firefox Reality, a browser for mixed reality, and our exploration in browsing in new and emerging realities. We’ve been at the forefront of developing new technologies, like WebVR and WebAR, and in some instances, Mozilla continues […]
The post Update on Firefox Reality appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 02 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3080</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/02/its-the-economy-stupid/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T18:25:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links To fight inflation, fight monopolies: Cartels raise prices using supply chain and "generous" benefits as cover for price-gouging. How noncompetes shackle workers to dead-end jobs: "You can't work for anyone who competes with Amazon for the next 18 months." Agricultural right to repair law is a no-brainer: Farmer-tinkerer solidarity. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading To fight inflation, fight monopolies (permalink) The majority of the public blames inflation on price-gouging. That's not surprising, because the CEOs of monopolistic companies keep boasting about their record profits even as they raise prices. If a company raises prices and margins, then we don't …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control Group]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2576/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2576/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/control_group.png" title="Placeble 228 x/6
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜" alt="Placeble 228 x/6
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exciting news: I’m on Rhizome!! (Artbase and Artist Profile)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5260</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/exciting-news-im-on-rhizome-artbase-and-artist-profile"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T20:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So here’s a dream come true for my work, and I’m dedicating an entire blog post to this very cool news… My work is on Rhizome again! Artist Profile: Nathalie Lawhead By Ryan Kuo https://rhizome.org/editorial/2022/feb/01/artist-profile-nathalie-lawhead/ Everything is going to be OK Rhizome Artbase https://artbase.rhizome.org/wiki/Q12199 “Everything is going to be OK” was recently included in the Rhizome Artbase. They put out a call for submissions for their executable poetry project. It seemed perfect. “Everything is going to be OK” very much fits that description because it features so much poetry. Then Ryan Kuo asked if I wanted to collaborate on an...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep your multiple online lives private with Multi-Account Containers Add-on on Mozilla VPN]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68376</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/mozilla-vpn/multi-account-containers-add-on-on-mozilla-vpn/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T17:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Mozilla, online privacy has always been one of our top priorities. Recently we announced Total Cookie Protection on Firefox Focus to combat cross-site tracking, and last year we introduced Firefox Relay, a privacy-first product that hides your real email address to help protect your identity. We are always looking for ways to offer privacy […]
The post Keep your multiple online lives private with Multi-Account Containers Add-on on Mozilla VPN appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: Feb 01 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3070</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/01/collaborators-not-fools/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T15:37:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Mafia hires good accountants: Honest cheaters enable the mob. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Mafia hires good accountants (permalink) High-profile leaks like the Pandora Papers and financial collapses like Carillion have shone a spotlight on the role that "the professions" play in enabling international finance crimes, which include both money-laundering and the underlying (ghastly, violent) crimes that produce the money to be laundered. For example, the Sackler family knowingly and deliberately created the opioid epidemic that has killed more than 800,000 Americans so far, and then used the best, most respectable, highest price bankruptcy lawyers in the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shaw Joins Firefox’s Trusted Recursive Resolver Program]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68365</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/shaw-firefox-trusted-recursive-resolver-program-doh/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shaw becomes first Canadian ISP to Commit to Data Retention and Transparency Requirements That Protect Customer Privacy Today, Mozilla, the maker of Firefox, and Shaw Communications Inc. have announced that Shaw is the first Internet Service Provider (ISP) in Canada to provide Firefox users with encrypted Domain Name System (DNS) services through Mozilla’s Trusted Recursive […]
The post Shaw Joins Firefox’s Trusted Recursive Resolver Program appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A toy DNS resolver]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/01/a-dns-resolver-in-80-lines-of-go/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/01/a-dns-resolver-in-80-lines-of-go/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T09:15:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I wrote a comic last week called “life of a DNS query” that explains how
DNS resolvers work.
In this post, I want to explain how DNS resolvers work in a different way –
with a short Go program that does the same thing described in the comic.
The main function (resolve) is actually just 20 lines, including comments.
I usually find it easier to understand things work when they come in the form
of programs that I can run and modify and poke at, so hopefully this program
will be helpful to some of you.
The program is here: https://github.com/jvns/tiny-resolver/blob/main/resolve.go
what’s a DNS resolver?
When your browser needs to make a DNS query, it asks a DNS resolvers. When
they start, DNS resolvers don’t know any DNS records (except the IP addresses
of the root nameservers). But the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of January Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42583</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/01/31/end-of-january-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T23:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events February 5 is the next meeting of the SF Bay IF Meetup. February 20 is the next meeting of the Seattle IF Meetup, and will be held via Discord, so people are welcome to attend remotely. It will feature a guest appearance from Daniel Ravipinto, one of the authors of the classic parser IF … Continue reading "End of January Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sending email notifications from GitHub organisations to different emails]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7114</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/02/01/sending-email-notifications-from-github-organisations-to-different-emails/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T23:37:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m part of a few organisations on GitHub and had one email address for notifications. This annoyed me as I didn’t want company notifications to my personal account as I couldn’t answer these. As it turns out, you can set up several email addresses in your GitHub account. In settings, go to Access > Emails […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 31 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3061</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/31/heel-turn/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T19:22:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Grappling with Big Wrestling: Vince McMahon has a monopoly on violence. Podcasting about the copyleft trolls who tried to shake me down: Pixsy and the depravity of speculative invoicing. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Grappling with Big Wrestling (permalink) If you're a Very Online person, it's easy to think that tech is a uniquely monopolized industry. How could you not – anyone over the age of 30 has had a front row seat for the transformation of the wild and wooly early web into "a group of five websites, each consisting of screenshots of text from the other four." https://twitter.com/tveastman/status/1069674780826071040 There's a chorus of captured economists…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for January]]></title>
        <id>log.html#jan2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#jan2022"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of January. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Left, re-wrote documentation, redesigned the UX for save-as/open-as.
Orca, re-wrote documentation, and added the operators manual on launch.
Thousand Rooms, released 3 new languages: Polish, Hungarian and Serbian. Now offering book as an ePUB.
Uxn, re-wrote entire documentation, and started a project devlog.
Nasu, improved zoom tool, it is now possible to move between tiles(Masto) while zoomed.
Yufo, released a small game for the Virtual Pet Jam.
100r, added new page: cast-iron cookware, and updated medical.
News
On January 28th Uxn turned 1 year old! We'd like to thank everyone who has contributed code, ideas, time and laughs to help this project grow into what it is now. It was a wonderful year for smol ordinators. See an image that Rekka made for uxn's birthday.
We finally released versions of the Uxn emulator for all major systems(Linux, OS X and Windows), with the option of a version bundled with a few starter roms. We simplified the guide too, to make it easier to install and use.
Our lion's mane mushroom grew another full head, we harvested it and made some mushroom pakoras.
In other news, Devine was interviewed on Anonradio, listen to it here. Also, Compudanzas released an Introduction to Uxn Programming book, with a foreword by Devine.
Pino book club
We're reading The Complete Cosmicomics by Italo Calvino, and The Dawn of Everything: A New History of Humanity by David Graeber.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What If? 2]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2575/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2575/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/what_if_2.png" title="CLARIFICATION: By 9/13, I mean September 13th, not the 9th day of Jancember, the cursed 13th month that exists between December and January in the transdimensional temporal plane." alt="CLARIFICATION: By 9/13, I mean September 13th, not the 9th day of Jancember, the cursed 13th month that exists between December and January in the transdimensional temporal plane." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3055</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/30/ring-minus-one/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-30T20:10:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The battle for Ring Zero: The esoteric argument I have been having with myself since 2002. This day in history: 2002, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The battle for Ring Zero (permalink) In Bruce Sterling's Locus review of my novel Walkaway, he describes the book as "advancing and demolishing potential political arguments that have never been made by anybody but [me]." That is a fair cop. I spend a lot of time worrying about esoteric risks that no one else seems to care about. https://locusmag.com/2017/06/bruce-sterling-reviews-cory-doctorow/ For example: for twenty years now, I have been worrying about the shifting political, technical and social frameworks that govern our fundamental relationsh…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An old photo of a very large BBS]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 30 years ago, I was given this picture.  I wanted to present it 
in a post all by itself to give it a chance to "sink in" before I went 
and used it in an analogy.  First, I'll just show the image and explain 
what you're looking at here.




I do remember the description from the back: this is a picture of *part 
of* something that was called the Software Creations BBS.  It was a 
multi-line bulletin board system where you could dial up and send 
messages to people, upload and download files, and (presumably) play 
online games ("doors") and anything else they cared to offer.

64 machines in a little space.  I have to assume 
they are at least 
286s (ATs, more or 
less), but it's impossible to tell from just this picture.  They could 
have been 386s or even 486s by that point, but …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One machine can go pretty far if you build things properly]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, so yesterday I 
posted
a picture of an old multi-line bulletin board system which had 
apparently taken over an entire bedroom with dozens of computers.  I 
mentioned that I intended to come back to the topic to throw in my own 
two cents, and so here we go.


Or, were you someone who found it horrific and wished there was a 
simpler way?  Did you wonder if it would be possible to pack all of that 
into one or maybe two boxes, instead?  Did you want a way to negate all 
of that complexity while still providing the same level of service?


Now, things are different.  I look at that and just sigh at the lost 
opportunities.  The actual amount of work being done on behalf of any of 
the users who are connected is tiny.  If we ignore the fact that the 
actual BBS software and related acc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>