<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html</id>
    <title>Ajour / Spitlo.com</title>
    <updated>2022-02-26T00:24:14.747Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.14.4</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 24 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3200</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/24/uber-for-arbitration/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-24T14:21:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Mass arbitration attack could bring Intuit to its knees: Justice for the millions ripped off by Turbotax's "Free File" fraud. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Mass arbitration attack could bring Intuit to its knees (permalink) Ever hear of "binding arbitration?" That's a clause in a contract that says that you aren't allowed to sue the company you're doing business with, even if they cheat, maim or kill you. It was invented to let giant companies of equal size and power agree in advance not to spend billions and decades in court to resolve contractual disputes. Then, Federalist Society judges led by Antonin Scalia set about clearing the way for arbitration to be cr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some things about getaddrinfo that surprised me]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/23/getaddrinfo-is-kind-of-weird/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/23/getaddrinfo-is-kind-of-weird/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-23T08:33:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Here are some things you may or may not have noticed about DNS:
when you resolve a DNS name in a Python program, it checks /etc/hosts, but when you use dig, it doesn’t.
switching Linux distributions can sometimes change how your DNS works, for example if you use Alpine Linux instead of Ubuntu it can cause problems.
Mac OS has DNS caching, but Linux doesn’t necessarily unless you use systemd-resolved or something
To understand all of these, we need to learn about a function called
getaddrinfo which is responsible for doing DNS lookups.
There are a bunch of surprising-to-me things about getaddrinfo, and once I
learned about them, it explained a bunch of the confusing DNS behaviour I’d
seen in the past.
where does getaddrinfo come from?
getaddrinfo is part of a library called libc whic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rounding]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2585/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2585/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/rounding.png" title="I've developed a novel propulsion system powered by loss of precision in unit conversion." alt="I've developed a novel propulsion system powered by loss of precision in unit conversion." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 22 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3191</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/22/national-champions/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-22T16:07:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting Part III of "The Internet Heist": In which the cartel gives itself a veto over your family life. China hamstrings its Big Tech: "National champions" are neither. This day in history: 2007, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting Part III of "The Internet Heist" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read the final part of "The Internet Heist," my Medium series on the copyright wars' early days, when the entertainment and tech giants tried to leverage the digital TV transition into a veto over every part of our lives. https://onezero.medium.com/the-internet-heist-part-iii-8561f6d5a4dc In Part I, I described the bizarre Broadcast Flag project, where Hollywood studios and Intel collude…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Results without all of the brackets]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/21/result/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-22T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, I
put forth
a bunch of API possibilities for the problem of needing to return a 
value but also indicating the lack of a value and being able to comment 
on why.  In it, the notion of a "wrapper" around a string was presented, 
such that it might look like "Result<string>", and those brackets 
started looking like a pain.  There was also the possibility of having 
something like "ResultString", but didn't that open the door to having a 
bunch of code duplication?


After this had existed for a while, the general happy feeling of having 
this stuff in place became infectious.  I wanted it to cover other 
things with it, too.  I wanted it to handle something a bit more 
complicated than a mere string, and so decided to try my hand at the 
template-wrangling metaprogramming cruft t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 21 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3185</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/21/contra-nihilismum/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:05:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A(nother) massive Swiss banking leak: Sunshine won't disinfect anything on its own. The people's disruption: Tech rights are workers' rights. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A(nother) massive Swiss banking leak (permalink) Look, there's been another massive banking leak, this one from Credit Suisse, showing complicity in laundering money for the world's greatest monsters: human traffickers, despots, criminals. They're calling it Suisse Secrets. https://www.theguardian.com/news/2022/feb/20/credit-suisse-secrets-leak-unmasks-criminals-fraudsters-corrupt-politicians They had to call it that, because Swiss Leaks was already taken, for the 2015 UBS leaks that rev…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Headline Words]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2584/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2584/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/headline_words.png" title="Roundly-condemned headlinese initiative shuttered indefinitely." alt="Roundly-condemned headlinese initiative shuttered indefinitely." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Returning values and errors]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/20/return/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-20T21:33:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you agree with the notion that you need to be able to tell the 
difference between the absence of a value and a value itself, then this 
has some impacts on the code you write.  If you want to keep 'em 
separated (so they can come out and play), then it gets you looking at 
your API designs in certain ways.


Imagine we're talking about a helper function that is intended to be run 
inside a program that's handling the access to a web page.  It's 
probably a CGI program, but it could also be buried inside some much 
bigger thing, too.  This is all about C++ styles, but you can probably 
see slices of other languages in here, too.


string UserIP() -- No more lifetime worries here, but oops, uh, well, 
what if we don't know what it is and need to provide an error?  If it's 
a CGI situatio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things that used to be hard and are now easy]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/20/things-that-used-to-be-hard-and-are-now-easy/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/20/things-that-used-to-be-hard-and-are-now-easy/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-20T09:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I was talking to some friends the other day about the types of
conference talks we enjoyed.
One category we came up with was “you know this thing that used to be super
hard? Turns out now it’s WAY EASIER and maybe you can do it now!“.
So I asked on Twitter about programming things that used to be hard and are now easy
Here are some of the answers I got. Not all of them are equally “easy”, but I
found reading the list really fun and it gave me some ideas for things to
learn. Maybe it’ll give you some ideas too.
SSL certificates, with Let’s Encrypt
Concurrency, with async/await (in several languages)
Centering in CSS, with flexbox/grid
Building fast programs, with Go
Image recognition, with transfer learning (someone pointed out that the joke in this XKCD doesn’t make sense anymore)
B…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 19 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3180</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/19/now-we-are-two/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-19T15:35:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Pluralistic is two: Still at it! This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Pluralistic is two (permalink) Today is the second anniversary of the founding of Pluralistic, my multiplatform, non-metrics-driven, solo blog, founded in some haste after my unplanned (but overdue and amicable) departure from Boing Boing. For two years, I've been putting out a new edition nearly every day (550 posts, or 75%). Each edition has one or more posts, and many of the editions have consisted of one or two long essays. In some ways, Pluralistic's long form essays are the dividends for the 20+ years I've been a daily blogger. All those short pieces I've written over the preceding decades are …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-February Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42614</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/02/19/mid-february-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-19T13:27:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mask demo! This month’s link assortment is a few days later than usual; that’s because I was focused in the first half of February on launching the demo for Mask of the Rose, the new game I’ve been working on at Failbetter. Mask of the Rose is set in the Fallen London universe, but decades … Continue reading "Mid-February Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 18 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3174</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/18/broken-records/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-18T15:17:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Tech platforms' playbook inevitably produces dumpster-fires: Anil Dash's amazing "broken tech/content culture cycle." This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Tech platforms' playbook inevitably produces dumpster-fires (permalink) Very rarely, I find an article that I want to share, but whose every line so so perfect that I can hardly bear to summarize it because I just want to repost the whole thing, peppered with "HELL YEAH"s. That's how I feel about Anil Dash's "That broken tech/content culture cycle." https://anildash.com/2022/02/09/the-stupid-tech-content-culture-cycle/ Dash lays out a playbook for firms that claim to be "tech companies" but rely on cultural production to g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chorded Keyboard]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2583/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2583/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/chorded_keyboard.png" title="And even though it all went wrong / I'll stand before the lord of song / with nothing on my tongue but 'I don't understand, I swear I backed up my keyboard config before messing with it'" alt="And even though it all went wrong / I'll stand before the lord of song / with nothing on my tongue but 'I don't understand, I swear I backed up my keyboard config before messing with it'" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My "daily drivers", and what happened to Slackware here]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/17/using/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T21:48:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In
yesterday's post,
I mentioned taking my old Mac Mini out of the OS X/macos ecosystem and 
bringing it into Debian, and then what kind of hilarity followed when I 
attempted to install a Javascript linter (and it tried to drag in 180+ 
node-related packages).


Readers are advised that this post will probably contain 
definitely contains a even higher than usual amount of 
navel-gazing as I dish out the details of my setup.  My usual 
disclaimer of "this works for me and probably won't work for you, so if 
you have different tastes, then great, go with that" definitely applies 
here.


First of all, the one that most people actually notice is the actual box 
which is serving rachelbythebay.com, which at the moment is a box called 
snowgoose.  I had installed it in early 2020 as CentOS 8 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3158</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/17/live-by-the-swordlive-by-the-sword/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T17:32:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The last days of Myspace: Facebook is following the steep decline playbook. The child labor story hidden by the Great Resignation: Bosses want to turn kids into scabs. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The last days of Myspace (permalink) I hated Facebook from the start and couldn't wait for it to die. That was a pretty reasonable thing to expect. After all, I'd watched social networks from Sixdegrees on crash and burn as the network effects that drove their growth also drove their precipitous collapse. A system enjoys "network effects" if it increases in value as it adds users. Social networks are all about these effects: you join Facebook because your friends are there,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A twisted maze of dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/16/deps/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T03:07:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh sure, everyone laughs about things having a lot of dependencies, but 
do they ever really think about the implications of having hundreds of 
teeny little libraries, all moving independently?  This is how it 
manifests in the real world.


My relative inexperience with Debian systems means I'm constantly being 
delighted to discover that such and such has already been packaged up 
and is just an apt command away.  Things that I would have done by hand 
in the years up to this point now have someone else worrying about them.


This is what happened next:


... huh.  The story basically ends there.  I'm going to handle this some 
other way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Americans deserve federal privacy protections and greater transparency into hidden harms online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68502</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/americans-deserve-federal-privacy-protections-and-greater-transparency-into-hidden-harms-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-16T21:45:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Privacy is fundamental and cannot be treated as optional. Companies and regulators need to work hand in hand to provide stronger privacy protections to people. Technical privacy protections by companies are complementary to privacy regulation and neither alone is sufficient.” Marshall Erwin Marshall Erwin, Mozilla’s Chief Security Officer, testified today before the Committee on House […]
The post Americans deserve federal privacy protections and greater transparency into hidden harms online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to secure your data in less than 10 minutes]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68476</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/privacy-security/how-to-secure-data-online/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-16T18:15:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data Privacy Day has come and gone. But here at Mozilla, helping educate people around online privacy is so important to us that we want to be your guide to protecting your data over the next four weeks. Save this page on Pocket, come back every Wednesday and find a couple of quick things you […]
The post How to secure your data in less than 10 minutes appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3155</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/16/unauthorized-paper/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-16T16:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The extremely shady "educational integrity" industry: From Proctorio to Honorlock. Oh great, there's DRM in printer PAPER now: Dymo was so preoccupied with whether or not they could, they didn't stop to think if they should. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The extremely shady "educational integrity" industry (permalink) The pandemic presented an opportunity to reconsider our seemingly immutable assumptions about life – for adults, anyway. We got the Great Resignation and "hybrid" work-from-home. Our kids got remote learning. Ugh. Don't get me wrong: remote learning has its advantages, especially for kids coping with physical and mental health issues, kids with pas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Trap]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2582/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2582/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/data_trap.png" title="It's important to make sure your analysis destroys as much information as it produces." alt="It's important to make sure your analysis destroys as much information as it produces." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 15 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3150</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/15/management-jesuits/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T17:18:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links McKinsey For Kids (no, really): Give us a child when they are seven and they are ours for life. Outing German spy agencies by mailing them Airtags: A threat-model parable. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading McKinsey For Kids (no, really) (permalink) McKinsey for Kids is a new website from the scandal-haunted consulting giants who proposed that Oxycontin-producers Purdue Pharma pay a bounty to pharma distributors based on the number of lethal overdoses in their territories. Its purpose is to teach kids to think like McKinsey Consultants. https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/mckinsey-for-kids/hungry-fish-baffled-farmers-and-what-happened-next "Chapter 1" of the p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox And Pixar Animation Studios team up to help you show your true colors]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68380</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/true-colors-with-firefox-pixar-animation-studios-turning-red/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“But maybe I like this new me.” The trailer for Disney and Pixar’s new film, “Turning Red,” streaming on Disney+ March 11, ends with Mei, its 13-year-old protagonist, considering a wild idea: acceptance. Maybe I like this new me. Yes, in her case the “new me” is becoming a giant red panda when she feels […]
The post Firefox And Pixar Animation Studios team up to help you show your true colors appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add 4740180 to the list of silly magic numbers]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/15/4740180/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-15T08:11:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh dear.  The software fungus where bits of code take the
literal characters "HTTP" as a number
has expanded.  Now it has a variant: 4740180.


Where does this one come from?  
Go and gRPC, apparently!


I found this while searching the web for "1213486160" to see how things 
have been going in the past few years.  Unfortunately, it's still biting 
people all over the place.  There are far too many posts asking people 
to upgrade their software, or restart things, or do any number of 
useless rubber-chicken-waving techniques which ultimately will 
accomplish nothing.

When you see a funny-looking number, figure out where it comes from.
That's the only way to have any chance of understanding what's actually 
going on.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feedback: environments, old BBSes, Honda's 2022 bug]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/14/feedback/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T23:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yep, it's time for another round of reader feedback.

"process infection" story:

https://lwn.net/Articles/883547/):


If you do privileged execution of specific operations via IPC you get 
the guarantee that whatever is done, is done from a well-defined, 
pristine execution environment, without leaking context implicitly. The 
IPC message is the *full* vulnerable surface, and that's as minimal as 
it can get. And that's great.




Oh wow, thank you for mentioning that, unnamed reader!  I definitely 
read that post on LWN at some point in the past couple of days when the 
pkexec thing started going around.  It must have really worked its way 
into my head, and then eventually stirred up the memory of everything 
getting "nicely infected" at $OLD_JOB.


Every time I talk about trying to par…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 13 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3143</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/14/externalities/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T18:49:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting Part II of "The Internet Heist": Big Content wants to plug your A-Hole! Comprehensive synthesis of the technological, ecological and political critique of blockchainism: It's all about the externalities. Eating invasive species: How to structure an invasivorism that doesn't hunger for more invaders. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting Part II of "The Internet Heist" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read the second part of "The Internet Heist," a series of three articles about the weirdest, most far-reaching, most bonkers battle of the copyright wars of the early 2000s. https://onezero.medium.com/the-internet-heist-part-ii-cb2add31a4fb…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pop Quiz: What are 5 questions to ask yourself before taking that online quiz?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68461</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/online-quizzes-data-collection-privacy-tips/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T16:56:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Who hasn’t taken a quiz online to figure out what TV character you are most like, what city should you live in or what 90s song most represents you? These quizzes seem innocent enough. You put in the name of your high school best friend, you select the kind of pet you had growing up […]
The post Pop Quiz: What are 5 questions to ask yourself before taking that online quiz? appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The multiple meanings of "nameserver" and "DNS resolver"]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/14/some-dns-terminology/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/14/some-dns-terminology/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T12:31:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m working on a zine about DNS right now, so I’ve been thinking about DNS
terminology a lot more than a normal person. Here’s something slightly
confusing I’ve noticed about DNS terminology!
Two of the most common DNS server terms (“nameserver” and “DNS resolver”)
have different meanings depending on the situation.
Now this isn’t a problem if you already understand how DNS works – I can
easily figure out what type of “nameserver” is being discussed based on
context.
But it can be a problem if you’re trying to learn how DNS works and you don’t
realize that those words might refer to different things depending on the
context – it’s confusing! So I’m going to explain the different possible
meanings and how to figure out which meaning is intended.
the 2 meanings of “nameserver”
There are 2 ty…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health Stats]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2581/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2581/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/health_stats.png" title="You will live on forever in our hearts, pushing a little extra blood toward our left hands now and then to give them a squeeze." alt="You will live on forever in our hearts, pushing a little extra blood toward our left hands now and then to give them a squeeze." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 11 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3134</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/11/bezzlers-gonna-bezzle/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-11T19:02:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Big Lie that keeps the Uber bezzle alive: A credulous press continues to report massive losses as profitability. This day in history: 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Big Lie that keeps the Uber bezzle alive (permalink) Uber is (still) a bezzle ("the magic interval when a confidence trickster knows he has the money he has appropriated but the victim does not yet understand that he has lost it"). And every bezzle – every bezzle – ends. Uber entered the market with an absurd proposition, which they papered over with an idiotic narrative…which the world ate up with a spoon. The absurd proposition: Uber could use apps to reinvent taxis, and turn a low-margin business into a high-margin busines…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rest and Fluids]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2580/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2580/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/rest_and_fluids.png" title="Remember not to take it easy. Put a hot washcloth on your forehead, remain standing, and breathe dry air while taking lots of histamines. You need to give your body a chance to get sick again." alt="Remember not to take it easy. Put a hot washcloth on your forehead, remain standing, and breathe dry air while taking lots of histamines. You need to give your body a chance to get sick again." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 10 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3130</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/10/monopoly-begets-monopoly/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T20:53:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Welcome to the Palmerverse: Ada Palmer's Renaissance-informed science fictional futurism. SEC vs private equity ripoffs: Personnel really are policy. Neuromancer today: Eileen Gunn on the enduring significance and wonder of William Gibson. Gators and Amazon tag-team small sellers: Amazon's bad conduct is good for (a certain kind of) business. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Welcome to the Palmerverse (permalink) Today in Wired, Gregory Barber profiles my friend, colleague and collaborator Ada Palmer, an extraordinary writer, librettist, historian, scholar, activist and performer: https://www.wired.com/story/ada-palmer-sci-fi-future-weird-hand-progress/ Palmer has just w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A nice story about Unix processes "infecting" each other]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/02/09/nice/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T19:24:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I once worked at a place that had an interesting little problem stemming 
from the way they managed machines and some of the fun side-effects 
processes can have on each other.  This is back in the pre-systemd days 
of running services, such that things tended to be started or restarted 
by someone or something that itself ran as root.  That is, if you 
started something, it might inherit one or more things from your 
environment.  Likewise, if you ran something with an unusual 
environment, it might bestow those "gifts" onto anything it happened to 
touch.


After locking themselves out of machines too many times, people 
generally learned that after you mess with a glibc upgrade, you restart 
the sshd listener on port 22.  Of course, they also had to learn to not 
whack EVERY sshd at the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Showing different titles depending if the tab is active or not]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7124</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/02/10/showing-different-titles-depending-if-the-tab-is-active-or-not/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-10T18:49:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just encountered a sneaky thing I had not seen, although it probably worked in 1999 already. A web site was showing a different title on the tab, depending on it being active or not. The whole trick is to use the blur and focus event handlers on the window to change the title. window.onblur […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 09 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3126</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/09/grievance-factory/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T19:17:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Litigation finance pits greed against greed: There was a late-stage captialism that swallowed a fly… Occupy the SEC on bank mergers: The Herfindahl-Hirschman Index considered harmful. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Litigation finance pits greed against greed (permalink) Early in the 19th century, political philosophers like Jeremy Bentham began to rail against champerty, whereby "unscrupulous nobles and royal officials would lend their names to bolster the credibility of doubtful and fraudulent claims in return for a share of the property recovered." https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Champerty_and_maintenance#History On its face, the practice of inviting investors to back …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tractor Beam]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2579/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2579/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/tractor_beam.png" title="Did you base the saucer shape on pop culture depictions of aliens, or was that stuff based on your ships? Does the rotational symmetry help with ... hey, where are you going?" alt="Did you base the saucer shape on pop culture depictions of aliens, or was that stuff based on your ships? Does the rotational symmetry help with ... hey, where are you going?" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3120</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/08/wall-street-landlords/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T17:26:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Pixels of You: A illustrated tale of love and photos. Wall Street's landlord business is turning every rental into a slum: And they're using public money to do it. UK Tories want a national database of porn-viewing habits: Oh fuck not this bullshit again. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Pixels of You (permalink) Pixels of You is a new young adult sf graphic novel, written by Ananth Hirsh and Yuko Ota and illustrated by Jenn Doyle, published today by Abrams. It's a sweet, smart tale of art, bitterness, enmity and camaraderie. https://www.abramsbooks.com/product/pixels-of-you_9781419749575/ Pixels' two protagonists are a pair of young women who have both won a covet…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy Preserving Attribution for Advertising]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68457</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/privacy-preserving-attribution-for-advertising/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-08T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advertising provides critical support for the Web. We’ve been looking to apply privacy preserving advertising technology to the attribution problem, so that advertisers can get answers to important questions without harming privacy. Attribution is how advertisers know if their advertising campaigns are working. Attribution generates metrics that allow advertisers to understand how their advertising campaigns […]
The post Privacy Preserving Attribution for Advertising appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Thomson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3115</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/07/broadcast-flag/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T16:41:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting part one of "The Internet Heist": My origin story, fighting the Broadcast Flag. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting part one of "The Internet Heist" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read the first part of "The Internet Heist," a three-part series I wrote for Medium on the "Broadcast Flag," which was invented 20 years ago, on my first day on the job at EFF. It's basically my origin-story. https://onezero.medium.com/the-internet-heist-part-i-3395769891b0 The Broadcast Flag was an incredibly gnarly, high-stakes digital technology issue. It combined no fewer than three esoteric fields – spectrum allocation, computer science, and copyright – and threa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recommended Reading Roundup #1]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5275</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/recommended-reading-roundup-1"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T00:15:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m going to try something new for this blog and that will be roundups of recommended reading. Here is the first! There’s a lot that I usually don’t get to share on my social media because that space is heavily game’s focused… so I thought of saving informative things I read, or quality resource, and then regularly sharing them on my blog. I’m also going to try to focus on sharing things relating to marginalized groups in Europe, as they relate to my own family’s history or (complicated) identity (Eastern Europe and the Balkans). I don’t get to talk about...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sword Pull]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2578/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2578/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sword_pull.png" title="Merlin really shouldn't leave his dirt bike lying around." alt="Merlin really shouldn't leave his dirt bike lying around." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 06 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3111</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/06/this-land-is-your-land/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-06T15:28:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Explaining UK Fair Dealing with Simpsons clips: An update to the classic "Fair(y) Use." Woody Guthrie, Songs and Art * Words and Wisdom: 332 pages of inspiration, joy and fascinating tales of a true American hero. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Explaining UK Fair Dealing with Simpsons clips (permalink) It's been 15 years since Bucknell U film prof Eric Faden made "A Fair(y) Tale," a short film that explains fair use by stringing together short, fair-use-qualifying clips from Disney movies. It remains an amazing accomplishment! https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BeKFAM892k4 Fair(y) Tale took 9 months to piece together as Faden painstakingly searched the corpus …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3104</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/05/time-for-some-game-theory/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-05T18:47:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How to design an anti-monopoly interop system: On the colossal bad faith of Subaru and Kia. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How to design an anti-monopoly interop system (permalink) A historical accident made Massachusetts a lab for studying how tech can serve monopolies, and the moves, countermoves and counter-countermoves show how businesses, tinkerers, governments and the public can liberate themselves from seemingly all-powerful monopolists. It all starts with Right to Repair. Companies love to monopolize the repair of their products. If the only place to get your broken stuff fixed is at its manufacturer's authorized depots, the manufacturer can move all kinds of v…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My hardware adventure with a Gameboy Pocket [blog]]]></title>
        <id>my-hardware-adventure-with-a-gameboy-pocket</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/02/05/my-hardware-adventure-with-a-gameboy-pocket"/>
        <updated>2022-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I bought this Gameboy Pocket off eBay in the hope that I could bring it back to life...

I'd seen this before and suspected that the game couldn't be loaded due to corruption during boot (on the GB side). I was wrong, but I definitely enjoyed the challenge!

Opening up the Gameboy up and took a peek, and yep, found game pak loading doberry had been messed with. Bit of a duff job on whoever tried to repair it before me - and it even looks like they spotted there was a short and tried to slice through it with a knife:

Pins A2 and A1 were definitely connected! Some flux and solder later and it looks more like this:

And now the Gameboy boots with a nice clean Nintendo logo. Except… it doesn't go past that point at all - and in fact the screen looks like it's doing some weird flash dance, goi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 04 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3095</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/04/up-your-nose/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T18:55:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links A covid vaccine for your airways: The promising science of nasal spray vaccines. Rail monopolies destroyed the American supply chain: Heads they win, tails we lose. This day in history: 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading A covid vaccine for your airways (permalink) The covid vaccine picture is awfully confusing. The current vaccines are doing a great job of preventing serious illness (at least, for people who are boosted), but they're not nearly so effective at preventing infection and transmission. What's more, the new variants are more contagious and less likely to cause severe infection, but they also appear to confer less immunity against re-infection: https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s how to watch the games with Firefox because we all need a winter distraction]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68430</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/how-to-watch-winter-games-multiple-videos-firefox/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T18:17:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If omicron canceled your winter plans, watching the Beijing games may be the next best thing. Can’t snowboard? See star athletes shred. Closed ski resort? Leave the poles to the pros. And yes, it feels like we just put out the flames on the torch — less than six months ago to be exact. But […]
The post Here’s how to watch the games with Firefox because we all need a winter distraction appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Bravo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New York Times editorial director of games on creating her ideal corner of the internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68362</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/everdeen-mason-nytimes-director-of-games-internet-interview/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T17:44:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Mozilla, we are the first to admit the internet isn’t perfect, but we are also quick to point out that the internet is pretty darn magical. The internet opens up doors and opportunities, allows for people to connect with others, and lets everyone find where they belong — their corners of the internet. […]
The post The New York Times editorial director of games on creating her ideal corner of the internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sea Chase]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2577/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2577/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sea_chase.png" title="There are two rules on this ship: Never gaze back into the projection abyss, and never touch the red button labeled DYMAXION." alt="There are two rules on this ship: Never gaze back into the projection abyss, and never touch the red button labeled DYMAXION." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3090</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/03/liquidation-preference/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-03T20:23:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Money is power: A political economy parable (with a side of environmental racism). When crypto-exchanges go broke, you'll lose it all: The fatal flaw in the "neither fish nor fowl" gambit (there is such a thing as society). This day in history: 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Money is power (permalink) "Political economy" may sound like an obscure technical matter, but it's a really very simple (and incredibly important) idea: That the economy is inevitably political, and there is no way to depoliticize economic theory. That is, every aspect of economics – taxation, antitrust, contract and labor law, etc – is fundamentally political. There is no objective perch on which an economist can stand and decid…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update on Firefox Reality]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68415</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/update-on-firefox-reality/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-03T14:03:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla’s mission is to make sure the Internet remains open and accessible to all. Four years ago, we launched Firefox Reality, a browser for mixed reality, and our exploration in browsing in new and emerging realities. We’ve been at the forefront of developing new technologies, like WebVR and WebAR, and in some instances, Mozilla continues […]
The post Update on Firefox Reality appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 02 Feb 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3080</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/02/its-the-economy-stupid/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T18:25:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links To fight inflation, fight monopolies: Cartels raise prices using supply chain and "generous" benefits as cover for price-gouging. How noncompetes shackle workers to dead-end jobs: "You can't work for anyone who competes with Amazon for the next 18 months." Agricultural right to repair law is a no-brainer: Farmer-tinkerer solidarity. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading To fight inflation, fight monopolies (permalink) The majority of the public blames inflation on price-gouging. That's not surprising, because the CEOs of monopolistic companies keep boasting about their record profits even as they raise prices. If a company raises prices and margins, then we don't …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control Group]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2576/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2576/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/control_group.png" title="Placeble 228 x/6
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜" alt="Placeble 228 x/6
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜
⬜⬜⬜⬜⬜" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exciting news: I’m on Rhizome!! (Artbase and Artist Profile)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5260</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/exciting-news-im-on-rhizome-artbase-and-artist-profile"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T20:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So here’s a dream come true for my work, and I’m dedicating an entire blog post to this very cool news… My work is on Rhizome again! Artist Profile: Nathalie Lawhead By Ryan Kuo https://rhizome.org/editorial/2022/feb/01/artist-profile-nathalie-lawhead/ Everything is going to be OK Rhizome Artbase https://artbase.rhizome.org/wiki/Q12199 “Everything is going to be OK” was recently included in the Rhizome Artbase. They put out a call for submissions for their executable poetry project. It seemed perfect. “Everything is going to be OK” very much fits that description because it features so much poetry. Then Ryan Kuo asked if I wanted to collaborate on an...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep your multiple online lives private with Multi-Account Containers Add-on on Mozilla VPN]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68376</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/mozilla-vpn/multi-account-containers-add-on-on-mozilla-vpn/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T17:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Mozilla, online privacy has always been one of our top priorities. Recently we announced Total Cookie Protection on Firefox Focus to combat cross-site tracking, and last year we introduced Firefox Relay, a privacy-first product that hides your real email address to help protect your identity. We are always looking for ways to offer privacy […]
The post Keep your multiple online lives private with Multi-Account Containers Add-on on Mozilla VPN appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: Feb 01 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3070</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/02/01/collaborators-not-fools/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T15:37:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Mafia hires good accountants: Honest cheaters enable the mob. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Mafia hires good accountants (permalink) High-profile leaks like the Pandora Papers and financial collapses like Carillion have shone a spotlight on the role that "the professions" play in enabling international finance crimes, which include both money-laundering and the underlying (ghastly, violent) crimes that produce the money to be laundered. For example, the Sackler family knowingly and deliberately created the opioid epidemic that has killed more than 800,000 Americans so far, and then used the best, most respectable, highest price bankruptcy lawyers in the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shaw Joins Firefox’s Trusted Recursive Resolver Program]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68365</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/shaw-firefox-trusted-recursive-resolver-program-doh/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shaw becomes first Canadian ISP to Commit to Data Retention and Transparency Requirements That Protect Customer Privacy Today, Mozilla, the maker of Firefox, and Shaw Communications Inc. have announced that Shaw is the first Internet Service Provider (ISP) in Canada to provide Firefox users with encrypted Domain Name System (DNS) services through Mozilla’s Trusted Recursive […]
The post Shaw Joins Firefox’s Trusted Recursive Resolver Program appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A toy DNS resolver]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/01/a-dns-resolver-in-80-lines-of-go/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/02/01/a-dns-resolver-in-80-lines-of-go/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-01T09:15:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I wrote a comic last week called “life of a DNS query” that explains how
DNS resolvers work.
In this post, I want to explain how DNS resolvers work in a different way –
with a short Go program that does the same thing described in the comic.
The main function (resolve) is actually just 20 lines, including comments.
I usually find it easier to understand things work when they come in the form
of programs that I can run and modify and poke at, so hopefully this program
will be helpful to some of you.
The program is here: https://github.com/jvns/tiny-resolver/blob/main/resolve.go
what’s a DNS resolver?
When your browser needs to make a DNS query, it asks a DNS resolvers. When
they start, DNS resolvers don’t know any DNS records (except the IP addresses
of the root nameservers). But the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of January Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42583</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/01/31/end-of-january-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T23:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events February 5 is the next meeting of the SF Bay IF Meetup. February 20 is the next meeting of the Seattle IF Meetup, and will be held via Discord, so people are welcome to attend remotely. It will feature a guest appearance from Daniel Ravipinto, one of the authors of the classic parser IF … Continue reading "End of January Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sending email notifications from GitHub organisations to different emails]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7114</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/02/01/sending-email-notifications-from-github-organisations-to-different-emails/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T23:37:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m part of a few organisations on GitHub and had one email address for notifications. This annoyed me as I didn’t want company notifications to my personal account as I couldn’t answer these. As it turns out, you can set up several email addresses in your GitHub account. In settings, go to Access > Emails […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 31 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3061</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/31/heel-turn/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T19:22:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Grappling with Big Wrestling: Vince McMahon has a monopoly on violence. Podcasting about the copyleft trolls who tried to shake me down: Pixsy and the depravity of speculative invoicing. This day in history: 2002, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Grappling with Big Wrestling (permalink) If you're a Very Online person, it's easy to think that tech is a uniquely monopolized industry. How could you not – anyone over the age of 30 has had a front row seat for the transformation of the wild and wooly early web into "a group of five websites, each consisting of screenshots of text from the other four." https://twitter.com/tveastman/status/1069674780826071040 There's a chorus of captured economists…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for January]]></title>
        <id>log.html#jan2022</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#jan2022"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of January. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Left, re-wrote documentation, redesigned the UX for save-as/open-as.
Orca, re-wrote documentation, and added the operators manual on launch.
Thousand Rooms, released 3 new languages: Polish, Hungarian and Serbian. Now offering book as an ePUB.
Uxn, re-wrote entire documentation, and started a project devlog.
Nasu, improved zoom tool, it is now possible to move between tiles(Masto) while zoomed.
Yufo, released a small game for the Virtual Pet Jam.
100r, added new page: cast-iron cookware, and updated medical.
News
On January 28th Uxn turned 1 year old! We'd like to thank everyone who has contributed code, ideas, time and laughs to help this project grow into what it is now. It was a wonderful year for smol ordinators. See an image that Rekka made for uxn's birthday.
We finally released versions of the Uxn emulator for all major systems(Linux, OS X and Windows), with the option of a version bundled with a few starter roms. We simplified the guide too, to make it easier to install and use.
Our lion's mane mushroom grew another full head, we harvested it and made some mushroom pakoras.
In other news, Devine was interviewed on Anonradio, listen to it here. Also, Compudanzas released an Introduction to Uxn Programming book, with a foreword by Devine.
Pino book club
We're reading The Complete Cosmicomics by Italo Calvino, and The Dawn of Everything: A New History of Humanity by David Graeber.
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What If? 2]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2575/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2575/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/what_if_2.png" title="CLARIFICATION: By 9/13, I mean September 13th, not the 9th day of Jancember, the cursed 13th month that exists between December and January in the transdimensional temporal plane." alt="CLARIFICATION: By 9/13, I mean September 13th, not the 9th day of Jancember, the cursed 13th month that exists between December and January in the transdimensional temporal plane." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3055</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/30/ring-minus-one/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-30T20:10:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The battle for Ring Zero: The esoteric argument I have been having with myself since 2002. This day in history: 2002, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The battle for Ring Zero (permalink) In Bruce Sterling's Locus review of my novel Walkaway, he describes the book as "advancing and demolishing potential political arguments that have never been made by anybody but [me]." That is a fair cop. I spend a lot of time worrying about esoteric risks that no one else seems to care about. https://locusmag.com/2017/06/bruce-sterling-reviews-cory-doctorow/ For example: for twenty years now, I have been worrying about the shifting political, technical and social frameworks that govern our fundamental relationsh…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 29 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3049</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/29/planned-obsolescence/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-29T17:40:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links No, payday lenders aren't nice guys: Won't someone think of the poor usurers? The Right to Repair: A stupendous new book on a very urgent subject. This day in history: 2002, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading No, payday lenders aren't nice guys (permalink) "It is difficult to get a man to understand something when his salary depends upon his not understanding it." That quote from Upton Sinclair reveals the ideological underpinnings of consequential errors by economists that lead to material, negative consequences for poor people. Here's one of those errors. A pair of economists, one associated with the the far-right Scalia Center at George Mason University, performed a deeply flawed analysis of payd…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reasons for servers to support IPv6]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/29/reasons-for-servers-to-support-ipv6/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/29/reasons-for-servers-to-support-ipv6/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-29T07:44:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been having a hard time understanding IPv6. On one hand, the basics initially seem pretty
straightforward (there aren’t enough IPv4 addresses for all the devices on the
internet, so people invented IPv6! There are enough IPv6 addresses for
everyone!)
But when I try to actually understand it, I run into a lot of questions. One
question is: twitter.com does not support IPv6. Presumably it can’t be causing
them THAT many issues to not support it. So why do websites support IPv6?
I asked people on Twitter why their servers support IPv6
and I got a lot of great answers, which I’ll summarize here. These all come
with the disclaimer that I have basically 0 experience with IPv6 so I can’t evaluate these reasons very well.
First though, I want to explain why it’s possible for twitter.com to no…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trim [blog]]]></title>
        <id>trim</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/01/29/trim"/>
        <updated>2022-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the start of this year, after over 2½ years of growing my hair, I cut it all off, right to the scalp and donated it to charity, specifically so Little Princess Trust, a charity who create wigs for little girls with cancer. Whilst Julie also raised over £650 which pays for the creation.
I did post the progress on Twitter, but I don't trust that site to be around in the next decade or two, so I'm posting it here too, since this site will be around as long as I am.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In California, an Important Victory for Net Neutrality]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68375</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/in-california-an-important-victory-for-net-neutrality/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T23:05:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, the Ninth Circuit court upheld California’s net neutrality law, affirming that California residents can continue to benefit from the fundamental safeguards of equal treatment and open access to the internet. This decision clears the way for states to enforce their own net neutrality laws, ensuring that consumers can freely access ideas and services without […]
The post In California, an Important Victory for Net Neutrality appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenn Taylor Hodges</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3044</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/28/american-exceptionalism/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T18:22:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links California's chance for universal health care: It would save taxpayers trillions. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading California's chance for universal health care (permalink) "American exceptionalism" usually refers to Americans letting themselves off the hook for the sins they condemn in others (mass incarceration, death penalty, voter suppression, book burning, etc). But there's another kind of implicit exceptionalism, practiced by elites in service to the status quo: the belief that Americans are exceptionally stupid Nowhere is this negative exceptionalism more obvious than in American health-care debates, where the cost of providing universal healthcare is …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating Data Privacy Day]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68371</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/celebrating-data-privacy-day/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T17:27:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explore options to have a less creepy and more carefree online life Happy International Data Privacy Day! While January 28 marks a day to raise awareness and promote best practices for privacy and data protection around the world, we at Mozilla do this work year-round so our users can celebrate today — and every day […]
The post Celebrating Data Privacy Day appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An old photo of a very large BBS]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/26/swcbbs/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 30 years ago, I was given this picture.  I wanted to present it 
in a post all by itself to give it a chance to "sink in" before I went 
and used it in an analogy.  First, I'll just show the image and explain 
what you're looking at here.




I do remember the description from the back: this is a picture of *part 
of* something that was called the Software Creations BBS.  It was a 
multi-line bulletin board system where you could dial up and send 
messages to people, upload and download files, and (presumably) play 
online games ("doors") and anything else they cared to offer.

64 machines in a little space.  I have to assume 
they are at least 
286s (ATs, more or 
less), but it's impossible to tell from just this picture.  They could 
have been 386s or even 486s by that point, but …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One machine can go pretty far if you build things properly]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/27/scale/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T05:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, so yesterday I 
posted
a picture of an old multi-line bulletin board system which had 
apparently taken over an entire bedroom with dozens of computers.  I 
mentioned that I intended to come back to the topic to throw in my own 
two cents, and so here we go.


Or, were you someone who found it horrific and wished there was a 
simpler way?  Did you wonder if it would be possible to pack all of that 
into one or maybe two boxes, instead?  Did you want a way to negate all 
of that complexity while still providing the same level of service?


Now, things are different.  I look at that and just sigh at the lost 
opportunities.  The actual amount of work being done on behalf of any of 
the users who are connected is tiny.  If we ignore the fact that the 
actual BBS software and related acc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revisiting BlueSuburbia in Unreal (an update on what I’ve been up to)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5249</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/revisiting-bluesuburbia-in-unreal-an-update-on-what-ive-been-up-to"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T00:25:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have been heavily invested in learning Unreal and Blender. I announced that I wanted to make a 3D game, so this is my trajectory for the foreseeable future. I’ve been keeping a development update thread on Twitter. It’s fun to track it! update: i finished modeling a bunch of trees (enough for variety) and finally got the procedural forest running.it's so cool and spooky!! i was right too. the god rays + trees are intense. the light effect is amazing too. i love this.can't wait to get some good fog into this… https://t.co/E6OeK0h3Wz pic.twitter.com/DjqcVh9vcv — Nathalie Lawhead (@alienmelon) January...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autoresponder]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2574/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2574/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/autoresponder.png" title="I ADMIRE HOW YOU SET BOUNDARIES AND I HOPE YOUR COLLEAGUES RESPECT THEM! PLEASE SPARE MY LIFE!" alt="I ADMIRE HOW YOU SET BOUNDARIES AND I HOPE YOUR COLLEAGUES RESPECT THEM! PLEASE SPARE MY LIFE!" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There oughta be a Live Q&amp;A about the WiFi Game Boy Cartridge.]]></title>
        <id>https://there.oughta.be/a/live-q-and-a/about-the-wifi-game-boy-cartridge</id>
        <link href="https://there.oughta.be/a/live-q-and-a/about-the-wifi-game-boy-cartridge"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There will be a Live Q&amp;A session about the Game Boy WiFi cartridge on Friday 9pm (CET). Ask anything! Click the image to see the video on youtube.com. I have never done this before and am quite curious on how it will turn out and how many will attend. See you on Friday!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>there.oughta.be/</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3038</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/27/extraordinary-popular-delusions/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T18:02:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links As stocks tumble, wealthy speculators bid up house prices: The long-run effect of Obama's choice to bail out lenders, not borrowers. Cops' imaginary fears send addicts to real jail: The deadly myth of the fentanyl contact high. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading As stocks tumble, wealthy speculators bid up house prices (permalink) The Obama administration's most consequential decision was to address the Great Financial Crisis by bailing out the finance sector, rather than borrowers. It was an unforced error, directed by Goldman-Sachs bankers elevated to the ranks of finance regulators, and we are still living with its consequences. The choice to enact quantitat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What The Heck, z-index??]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/stacking-contexts/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/stacking-contexts/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T09:49:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The z-index property can be a tricky little bugger. Sometimes, no matter how much you crank up the number, the element never rises to the top! In this article, we explore stacking contexts, and see how they can thwart our efforts to use z-index. We'll also learn how to use this mechanism to our advantage.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Variables for React Devs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/css-variables-for-react-devs/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/css-variables-for-react-devs/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-27T09:49:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Variables are *really* cool, and they're incredibly powerful when it comes to React! This tutorial shows how we can use them with React to create dynamic themes. We'll see how to get the most out of CSS-in-JS tools like styled-components, and how our mental frame around media queries has been wrong all along.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A launch.json setting for end-to-end web development]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7095</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/01/26/a-launch-json-setting-for-end-to-end-web-development/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-26T18:10:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I start a new project these days I create the following launch.json file and put in in a .vscode folder on the the root of my project. This turns Visual Studio Code into an environment that gives me everything I need to build a web product without ever leaving it. If you want to […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alien Mission]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2573/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2573/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/alien_mission.png" title="Fine, we can go search the Himalayas for the Yeti ONE more time, but keep a safe altitude over the Pacific and PLEASE watch where you're going. We can't afford another Amelia Earhart incident." alt="Fine, we can go search the Himalayas for the Yeti ONE more time, but keep a safe altitude over the Pacific and PLEASE watch where you're going. We can't afford another Amelia Earhart incident." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hosting my static sites with nginx]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/24/hosting-my-static-sites-with-nginx/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/24/hosting-my-static-sites-with-nginx/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T07:59:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Recently I’ve been thinking about putting my static sites on servers
that I run myself instead of using managed services like Netlify or GitHub
Pages.
Originally I thought that running my own servers would require a lot of
maintenance and be a huge pain, but I was chatting with Wesley about what kind
of maintainance their servers require, and
they convinced me that it might not be that bad.
So I decided to try out moving all my static sites to a $5/month server to see
what it was like.
Everything in here is pretty standard but I wanted to write down what I did
anyway because there are a surprising number of decisions and I like to see
what choices other people make.
the constraint: only static sites
To keep things simple, I decided that this server would only run nginx and
only serv…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alien Observers]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2572/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2572/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/alien_observers.png" title="ALERT: Human 910-25J-1Q38 has created a Youtube channel. Increase erratic jerkiness of flying by 30% until safely out of range." alt="ALERT: Human 910-25J-1Q38 has created a Youtube channel. Increase erratic jerkiness of flying by 30% until safely out of range." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Revenge of the Hot Water Bottle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2022/01/the-revenge-of-the-hot-water-bottle.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2022/01/the-revenge-of-the-hot-water-bottle.html"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T09:50:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine a personal heating system that works indoors as well as outdoors, can be taken anywhere, requires little energy, and is independent of any infrastructure. It exists – and is hundreds of years old. The hot water bottle could save a great deal of energy and money without sacrificing thermal comfort. Hot water bottles work both indoors and outdoors. Illustration: Marie Verdeil. A hot water bottle is a sealable container filled with hot water, often enclosed in a textile cover, which is directly placed against a part of the body for thermal comfort. The hot water bottle is still a common household item in some places – such as the UK and Japan – but it is largely forgotten or...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>LOW-TECH MAGAZINE</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hydraulic Analogy]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2571/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2571/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/hydraulic_analogy.png" title="Current (water) running through the water (wires) causes it to boil, increasing the pressure (voltage), but resisting (impeding) the flow of hydroelectricity (water currents). This is the basis for Ohm's law." alt="Current (water) running through the water (wires) causes it to boil, increasing the pressure (voltage), but resisting (impeding) the flow of hydroelectricity (water currents). This is the basis for Ohm's law." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ever wondered what a Wordle social media update sounds to screenreader users?]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7086</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/01/19/ever-wondered-what-a-wordle-social-media-update-sounds-to-screenreader-users/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-19T21:44:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not pretty. This isn’t a dig at Skoop, he was just first on my timeline with a result when I did some accessibility testing. Screenreaders read out the squares as “black large square”, “green square” and “yellow square”. As a saving grace, they cleverly do group them, so four yellow squares are announces as […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Captain Picard Tea Order]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2570/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2570/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/captain_picard_tea_order.png" title="We can ask the Earl for his order once he's fully extruded from the dispenser." alt="We can ask the Earl for his order once he's fully extruded from the dispenser." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast recording: Development tools in the expert’s eye with Chris Heilmann]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7082</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/01/18/podcast-recording-development-tools-in-the-experts-eye-with-chris-heilmann/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T13:10:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday I was a guest on the JavaScript Master Podcast by Dariusz Kalbarczyk and we talked a bit more than an hour about my job as a Developer Tools PM, what annoys me the most about the toolintg situation and how the community can help. You can listen to the podcast on anchor.fm or Spotify […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brutalita Sans - font and editor [link]]]></title>
        <id>2022-01-18-47fd232c</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/links/2022-01-18-47fd232c"/>
        <updated>2022-01-18T10:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A simple mono font, but also comes with it's own easy to use visual editor where you can work on an multi-layered 5x11 grid to customise the font to your liking - and download it as an .OTF file.
Source: brutalita.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hypothesis Generation]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2569/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2569/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/hypothesis_generation.png" title="Frazzled scientists are requesting that everyone please stop generating hypotheses for a little bit while they work through the backlog." alt="Frazzled scientists are requesting that everyone please stop generating hypotheses for a little bit while they work through the backlog." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-January Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42577</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2022/01/15/mid-january-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-15T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events Feb 5 is the next meeting of the SF Bay IF Meetup. If you wish to enter Spring Thing this year with a new work of interactive fiction, you have until March 1 to submit your intent to enter, and March 31 to complete your game. Releases chiaroscuro is a short, low-fantasy IF novella … Continue reading "Mid-January Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some ways DNS can break]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/15/some-ways-dns-can-break/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/15/some-ways-dns-can-break/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-15T12:25:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I first learned about it, DNS didn’t seem like it should be THAT
complicated. Like, there are DNS records, they’re stored on a server, what’s
the big deal?
But with DNS, reading about how it works in a textbook doesn’t prepare you for
the sheer volume of different ways DNS can break your system in practice. It’s
not just caching problems!
So I asked people on Twitter for
example of DNS problems they’ve run into, especially DNS problems that didn’t
initially appear to be DNS problems. (the popular “it’s always DNS” meme)
I’m not going to discuss how to solve or avoid any of these problems in this
post, but I’ve linked to webpages discussing the problem where I could find
them.
problem: slow network requests
Your network requests are a little bit slower than expected, and it’s actually
…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinthariscope]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2568/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2568/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/spinthariscope.png" title="Other high scorers are melt-in-your-hand aluminum-destroying gallium and tritium-powered glowsticks. Lawn darts are toward the other end." alt="Other high scorers are melt-in-your-hand aluminum-destroying gallium and tritium-powered glowsticks. Lawn darts are toward the other end." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Klara and the Sun [book]]]></title>
        <id>klara-and-the-sun</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2022/klara-and-the-sun"/>
        <updated>2022-01-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Klara and the Sun]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turning a GitHub page into a Progressive Web App]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7077</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/01/13/turning-a-github-page-into-a-progressive-web-app/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-13T10:06:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just released my dice simulator app and in doing so learned about a few things about turning a GitHub Page into a PWA. To make this easier for subsequent projects, I put together a bare-bones template to turn any GitHub page into a PWA. Nothing in there is sophisticated and all it does is […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There oughta be GTA5 for the Game Boy.]]></title>
        <id>https://there.oughta.be/gta5-for-the-game-boy</id>
        <link href="https://there.oughta.be/gta5-for-the-game-boy"/>
        <updated>2022-01-12T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I presented my WiFi Game Boy cartridge a few weeks ago, I only had very few simple text-based demos. This post and especially the accompanying video now deliver more. In fact, I might have gone a bit too far, as I managed to stream full resolution video and even play games via WiFi. But see for yourself: Click the image to see the video on youtube.com. So, as usual, you have two alternatives to start here: Watch the video or read the article. If you are just curious and want to see what I did, definitely check out the video. If you want to understand exactly how it works and if you want to reproduce it or find tricks for your own projects, go for the article and the linked code. In any case, if you have not seen the previous article and/or video on the cartridge itself, you should start there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>there.oughta.be/</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Language Development]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2567/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2567/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/language_development.png" title="The worst is the Terrible Twos, when they're always throwing things and shrieking, &quot;forsooth, to bed thou shalt not take me, cur!&quot;" alt="The worst is the Terrible Twos, when they're always throwing things and shrieking, &quot;forsooth, to bed thou shalt not take me, cur!&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Offline? No dice!]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7071</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/01/11/offline-no-dice/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T21:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago I was on vacation in a place that had terrible mobile connectivity and whilst it provided WiFi, nothing worked. I even brought my own cables and travel router, but to no avail. This was not only a good opportunity for some “digital detox”, but it also showed me once again that […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revisiting why hyperlinks are blue]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68304</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/why-are-hyperlinks-blue-revisited/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T20:46:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why we need to revisit the origin of blue hyperlink While musing over my recently published article, Why are hyperlinks blue, I was left feeling a bit blue myself. Yes, it could have been the fact that I was evacuated and Hurricane Ida was destroying my home, I’ll admit. Besides that, I was also bothered […]
The post Revisiting why hyperlinks are blue appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elise Blanchard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Year, New Privacy Protection for Firefox Focus on Android]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68204</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/new-privacy-protection-for-firefox-focus-on-android/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T14:16:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever signed up for a contest to win a big screen TV or a vacation to an exotic location? Or have you joined a big retailer loyalty program so you can save money? If you answered yes to either of these questions you may be exchanging your name, home address, email address, phone […]
The post New Year, New Privacy Protection for Firefox Focus on Android appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make Beautiful Gradients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/make-beautiful-gradients/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/make-beautiful-gradients/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever noticed that gradients tend to look a little gray and washed-out in the middle? This happens because of a mathematical quirk with RGB colors. Fortunately, we can work around this quirk, and create beautiful, lush, saturated gradients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to find a domain's authoritative nameservers]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/11/how-to-find-a-domain-s-authoritative-nameserver/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/11/how-to-find-a-domain-s-authoritative-nameserver/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T08:30:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s a very quick “how to” post on how to find your domain’s authoritative
nameserver.
I’m writing this because if you made a DNS update and it didn’t work, there are 2 options:
Your authoritative nameserver doesn’t have the correct record
Your authoritative nameserver does have the correct record, but an old record is cached and you need to wait for the cache to expire
To be able to tell which one is happening (do you need to make a change, or do
you just need to wait?), you need to be able to find your domain’s
authoritative nameserver and query it to see what records it has.
But when I looked up “how to find a domain’s authoritative nameserver” to see
what advice was out there, I found a lot of different methods being mentioned,
some of which can give you the wrong answer.
So let’s wa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Checklist: How to Start 2022 Right]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68219</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/uncategorized/digital-checklist-how-to-start-2022-right/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-10T18:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For most, the New Year marks a time to reflect, reset and re-prioritize. While learning a new language, creating a budget or starting up a new hobby have become staples of our New Years’ Resolutions, as our lives increasingly shift online, it’s important we also use this opportunity to reassess our digital habits. Whether you […]
The post Digital Checklist: How to Start 2022 Right appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 10 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3007</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/10/see-you-in-the-funny-papers/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-10T16:16:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Personnel are policy: The Dems may do something to materially improve voters' lives. Maybe. Podcasting "Science fiction is a Luddite Literature": My last pre-op podcast. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Personnel are policy (permalink) It's hard not to freak out, watching Biden get punked by Joe Manchin over Build Back Better. Manchin's transparent ruse – splitting the infrastructure bill from BBB – was obviously a prelude to a betrayal. Thanks to Dem leadership's foolish error, the party that holds the House, the Senate and the Oval Office will go into the mid-terms and the next presidential election having failed to deliver on the vast majority of their cam…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla partners with The Markup to launch Rally study into Facebook’s tracking and data collection practices]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68200</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/mozilla-themarkup-partner-rally-facebook-tracking-data-collection/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Browser maker Mozilla today announced a partnership with The Markup, the non-profit newsroom that investigates how technology is reshaping society, on a research project to provide insights into and data about a space that’s opaque to policymakers, researchers and users themselves. By joining Mozilla and The Markup’s “Facebook Pixel Hunt” in Firefox, people can help […]
The post Mozilla partners with The Markup to launch Rally study into Facebook’s tracking and data collection practices appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decorative Constants]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2566/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2566/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/decorative_constants.png" title="Arguably, the '1/2' in the drag equation is purely decorative, since drag coefficients are already unitless and could just as easily be half as big. Some derivations give more justification for the extra 1/2 than others, but one textbook just calls it 'a traditional tribute to Euler and Bernoulli.'" alt="Arguably, the '1/2' in the drag equation is purely decorative, since drag coefficients are already unitless and could just as easily be half as big. Some derivations give more justification for the extra 1/2 than others, but one textbook just calls it 'a traditional tribute to Euler and Bernoulli.'" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2998</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/07/the-klept/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-07T17:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Jackpot watch: How the klept operates in the UK. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Jackpot watch (permalink) In his 2014 novel The Peripheral, William Gibson plunges us into a far-future London, radically depopulated, quietly authoritarian, and under the iron thumb of "the Klept" – a fusion of the British chumocracy with post-Soviet Eurasian kleptoracy. https://memex.craphound.com/2014/10/28/the-peripheral-william-gibson-vs-william-gibson/ The origins of this society – its depopulation, its neo-aristocracy, its captivity to inscrutable AIs called "the Aunties" are lost to history. They all took place during a time called "The Jackpot," an interregnum where huge swat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Latency]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2565/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2565/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/latency.png" title="Each SCAPDFATIAT point increases the chance that the process will involve the phrase 'by the next business day.'" alt="Each SCAPDFATIAT point increases the chance that the process will involve the phrase 'by the next business day.'" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2991</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/05/hillrom/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-05T16:21:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Hospital beds are a monopoly: The casket to hospital bed monopoly pipeline. This day in history: 2007, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Hospital beds are a monopoly (permalink) The great James Boyle tells an important parable about the coining of the term "ecology." Before the term came into wide use, the "ecology movement" as we know it was just a bunch of fragmented, seemingly disconnected issues. https://thepublicdomain.org/thepublicdomain1.pdf Like, if you're worried about owls and I'm worried about the ozone layer, it's not immediately apparent that we're fighting the same fight. It's not intuitive to link the fate of charismatic nocturnal avians to the gaseous composition of the upper atmosp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why might you run your own DNS server?]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/05/why-might-you-run-your-own-dns-server-/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/05/why-might-you-run-your-own-dns-server-/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-05T06:42:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the things that makes DNS difficult to understand is that it’s
decentralized. There are thousands (maybe hundreds of thousands? I don’t know!) of authoritative nameservers, and at least
10 million resolvers.
And they’re running lots of different software! All these different servers
running software means that there’s a lot of inconsistency in how DNS works,
which can cause all kinds of frustrating problems.
But instead of talking about the problems, I’m interested in figuring out –
why is it a good thing that DNS is decentralized?
why is it good that DNS is decentralized?
One reason is scalability – the decentralized design of DNS makes it
easier to scale and more resilient to failures. I find it really amazing that
DNS is still scaling well even though it’s almost 40 years old. Th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sunshield]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2564/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2564/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sunshield.png" title="RIP the surface of Mars" alt="RIP the surface of Mars" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On GameJolt’s new policy: why stigmatizing “sex” in games is harmful to the medium and never works…]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5236</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/on-gamejolts-new-policy-why-stigmatizing-sex-in-games-is-harmful-to-the-medium-and-never-works"/>
        <updated>2022-01-04T22:53:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday GameJolt emailed a lot of people saying that their game was removed because the site’s new policy bans any game that “depicts, solicits, promotes, normalizes, or glorifies sexual acts, sexual solicitation, and sexual violence“. I got an email too for F2OGGY (Only one survives!). This seemed like an obvious error to me because this game has 0 depiction of anything sexual. The game Curtain also received this notice… Source: https://twitter.com/ldreamfeel/status/1478065400286007304 Curtain is a brilliant and critically acclaimed work of art that interrogates abuse. It’s far from a porn game. “CURTAIN is an interactive first-person narrative about Kaci & Ally,...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 04 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2985</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/04/general-ludd/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-04T17:07:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Science fiction is a Luddite literature: My latest column for Locus Magazine. Neal Stephenson's 'Termination Shock': Geoengineering and the end of the world. Stellar images of quack exercise machines: A memento mori for anyone flexing in lycra on a Peleton. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Science fiction is a Luddite literature (permalink) My latest column for Locus Magazine is "Science Fiction is a Luddite Literature," and it's my contribution to the burgeoning movement to rehabilitate the reputation of the Luddite uprisings, overturning the libel that Luddites were motivated by a fear of technology: https://locusmag.com/2022/01/cory-doctorow-science-fiction-is-a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2973</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/03/party-like-its-1926/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-03T16:28:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Happy Public Domain Day: The public domain continues to roar back after decades in a coma. 2021 Daddy-Daughter podcast: The latest in a lengthy series. This day in history: 2002, 2007 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Happy Public Domain Day (permalink) On January 1, 2019 something extraordinary happened. For the first time since 1998, the American public domain got bigger. What happened in 1998? Congress – led by Rep Sonny Bono – extended the copyright on all works by 20 years. Works that had already been in the public domain went back into copyright. Works that were in copyright got an extra 20 years. The public domain…froze. This was a wanton, destructive act. The vast majority of works that the Sonny Bono…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Throat and Nasal Passages]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2563/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2563/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/throat_and_nasal_passages.png" title="I always felt like what the 'you are now aware of your tongue' thing neeeded in order to be truly enjoyable was an element of mortal peril." alt="I always felt like what the 'you are now aware of your tongue' thing neeeded in order to be truly enjoyable was an element of mortal peril." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YYMMDDHHMM just overflowed a signed 32 bit int]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/01/baddate/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/01/baddate/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T19:36:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I guess I've turned into a collector of numbers that break things 
sometimes.  Here's another one I just heard about, and it's directly 
related to what just happened with the calendar.


The last value for last year is December 31, 2021 at 23:59, and in this 
format it becomes 2112312359.  That just fits into a signed 32 bit 
number (which tops out at 2147483647).


So, if you're using Microsoft Exchange and stopped getting your mail in 
the past couple of hours, this is why!

Really!  No joke!

Happy 2022, everyone.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Magical 3D Button]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/3d-button/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/3d-button/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every action we take on the web starts with a button click, and yet most buttons are ho-hum and uninspired. In this tutorial, we'll build an animated 3D button with HTML and CSS that sparks joy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magical Rainbow Gradients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/rainbow-button/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/rainbow-button/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've ever tried to animate a gradient, you've been met with a harsh reality—it isn't possible. At least, it wasn't! In this tutorial, we'll leverage bleeding-edge browser features to animate ANY CSS property, including background gradients, using CSS Houdini, CSS variables, and React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Folding the DOM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/folding-the-dom/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/folding-the-dom/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we'll explore a technique we can use to "fold" a DOM node, like folding a letter in real-life. On that journey, we'll learn a lot about 3D transforms and CSS animation techniques!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/the_future</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/the_future"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T02:01:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, it's 2022 and everything is turning out exactly as I predicted back when I was 7. Self-driving cars, space stations, the internet.  Nailed it.
Favorite TV show of 2021 was Only Murders in the Building.  
Favorite game of 2021 was Loop Heroes. 
Favorite book of 2021 was Einstein's Fridge.
Favorite rediscovered joy of 2021 was reading physical books.
Favorite movie of 2021 was Dune.
Favorite time waster of 2021 was watching physics videos on YouTube.
Least favorite movie of 2021 was anything with f**king superheroes.
Favorite pandemic of 2021 was Covid-19 (three years running).
See you in an exciting 2022 where everyone will be nice and respectful and personal agendas are put aside for the greater good and we all come together and save the planet. 
Either that or a horrific dystopian post-apocalyptic world where we hunt each other for food.
2022 could go either way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books I read in 2021 [blog]]]></title>
        <id>books-i-read-in-2021</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/01/01/books-i-read-in-2021"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As my year in reading goes, I've certainly read less books, but I've not spent less time reading. It's just some books take me longer than others. For example, I read Call of the Wild, an 80(ish) page book in 4 weeks and then I read a 400 page book in 4 days… so it's really swings and roundabouts.
I recorded 21 books on my Kindle this year, but actually one of them was read aloud to the kids (Which I do still count) but another one was all of 19 pages… which, I think really doesn't count (it was Home: Habitat, Range, Niche, Territory by Martha Wells). So… 20 books then.
This post is mostly data driven (from my own web site's data) to give me a sense of the quality of the books I've read, otherwise individual reviews are all linked in this post or available on my books page.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of December Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42242</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/12/31/end-of-december-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events Running for a week starting January 1 on itch is the Historically Accurate Game Jam. This isn’t specifically an IF competition, and games of all types are welcome, as long as they’re written in a week and address the chosen time period or event of the jam. If you’ve had a craving to contribute … Continue reading "End of December Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021: Year in review]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/31/2021--year-in-review/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/31/2021--year-in-review/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T09:27:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s the end of the year again! This was my second full year working for myself
on wizard zines.
Here are some thoughts about what I’m working towards, a bunch of things I made
this year, and a few ideas and questions about 2022.
made some progress on a “mission statement”
I think the two hardest things about working for myself are working alone and
having to decide what to do.
This year I spent some time trying to figure out what I’m doing with wizard
zines. This is hard for me because I work in a pretty intuitive way – I have
some feelings about what’s important, and even though following my feelings
usually turns out well, I can’t always explain what I’m trying to do.
Here are some thoughts about what I’m trying to do:
I’m only interested in explaining “old” established technologies (HT…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My 2021 [blog]]]></title>
        <id>my-2021</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2021/12/31/my-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On a frequency of once every 365 days, based on the theme of my previous me-me-me posts and a general stamp I like to leave myself to remind Future Remy what the hell went on, here is my 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for December]]></title>
        <id>log.html#dec2021</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#dec2021"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of December. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Grimgrains, published a tofu from soy flour recipe, and reduced the amount of ingredients appearing on the main page so it loads faster.
Left, created inline image support, and implemented a search feature(Birdsite) inspired by the Canon Cat(1987)'s LEAP™ key.
Cat Clock, released our very own cat clock.
Turye, released a font editor.
TGA parser, released a tool to make it easier to bring images into the Uxn ecosystem.
Wunderland Rabbits, released a new image.
News
It is snowing, and we are cocooning. Our little woodstove is working hard. This month, we finally decided to release a paperback version of Busy Doing Nothing.
In our last update log, we mentioned that we were trying to grow Lion's Mane mushroom, and we are happy to report that it was a success! It grew beautifully. Rek was so excited about the mushroom that they decided to draw some this month, this series focuses on varieties that grow on Vancouver Island.
In other news, we had an interview with the founder of Sourcehut, read it here. Also, our good friend Alderwick make us a very cool gift(YouTube).
Pino book club
We're reading Fantômes: Issue 1, with work by 18 talented artists, put together by Lizbeth. It is a eerie, and gorgeous zine, we strongly recommend the Mike Wolf version.
Pino's location: 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Formatting Meeting]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2562/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2562/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/formatting_meeting.png" title="Neither group uses iso 8601 because the big-endian enthusiasts were all at the meeting 20 years ago." alt="Neither group uses iso 8601 because the big-endian enthusiasts were all at the meeting 20 years ago." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iron Widow (Iron Widow, #1) [book]]]></title>
        <id>iron-widow-iron-widow-1</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/iron-widow-iron-widow-1"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Iron Widow (Iron Widow, #1)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiny indiegames and the joy of Very Small Things]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5229</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/tiny-indiegames-and-the-joy-of-very-small-things"/>
        <updated>2021-12-30T01:53:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[~ This post is my epic roundup of recommendations for 202x! ~ When we talk about games, especially the indie game space, most of the games we suggest are ones with lots of critical acclaim, playtime, and that demand plenty of involvement. Playing a game these days feels like as much of a financial investment as it becomes a life investment. I find myself drawn more and more to spelunking itch.io for tiny hidden gems… getting lost while diving into all the developer pages filled with all these odd little works. Browsing itch or GameJolt has become almost as rewarding...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moonfall]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2561/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2561/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/moonfall.png" title="Novel ideas and cool explosions are both good, but what I really want from a movie is novel ideas ABOUT cool explosions." alt="Novel ideas and cool explosions are both good, but what I really want from a movie is novel ideas ABOUT cool explosions." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Psalm for the Wild-Built (Monk & Robot, #1) [book]]]></title>
        <id>a-psalm-for-the-wild-built-monk-and-robot-1</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/a-psalm-for-the-wild-built-monk-and-robot-1"/>
        <updated>2021-12-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lovely but I found the language almost too distracting.
Only right at the end of the book did I consider that maybe I really wasn't the right audience for the story - as it seemed to smack of "millennium type problems". Using air quotes in my description because I'm fairly sure this is a patronising statement I'm making!
The Dex character feels discontent with their achievements and is struggling to find fulfilling meaning. Their work has meaning to others but they're left feeling empty. Obviously it's an impossible measure as life trondles forward and achievements change with time.
For me it was only really when Dex meets the Robot (whose name I've already forgotten) when the book became more engaging. It was like the Dex character could be challenged and some real depth was offered (for better or worse for Dex's personality).
But what I did struggle with was the language and the odd shoehorning of gender pronouns. Dex is neither "he" or "she", so Chamber's settles with using the "they" pronoun. This led to my own confusion regularly thinking the lines I was reading was referring to Dex and another character that was in the scene.
The sore-thumb moment is when Dex asks, interestingly, what pronoun the Robot uses, and the Robot responds with "it" and it refers to itself as an object. Dex replies with (something like) they are the same, and their pronoun is "they". This seemed like a potentially interesting exchange between the Robot and Dex about the subject of how one refers to oneself and how they identify, but it doesn't happen. It just has that exchange, and then the story returns to what they were doing and carries on. It felt jarring and like Chamber's wanted to discuss this topic, but instead shoe horned it in.
I do also suspect that my trouble with the language is a me-thing and probably with practice it won't cause me as much (or any) confusion, but for now, and this book, it definitely affected how I enjoyed the story.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lego Report 8]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/lego8</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/lego8"/>
        <updated>2021-12-27T18:54:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That didn't take long to fix and rebuild. I don't know what is taking the city of Rome so long.

Start to finish, it took just over a year. I blame Limited Run Games.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>