<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html</id>
    <title>Ajour / Spitlo.com</title>
    <updated>2021-10-15T00:18:14.839Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacked! Unravelling a data breach]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67517</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/hacked-unravelling-a-data-breach/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T21:30:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a story about paying a steep price for a pair of cheap socks. The first loose thread in June One Tuesday morning as I* was having my coffee and toast before kicking off the work day, I got a text from my credit card company alerting me to a suspected fraud charge. Of […]
The post Hacked! Unravelling a data breach appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at the outlying data points]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/13/temp/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T03:02:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the fun things I used to do at a prior job was to dig through the 
raw data points which were collected from the *many* servers we had.  I 
could just pick an interesting-sounding metric and then would just ask 
the system to show me the top 10 or bottom 10 out of a population of 
thousands or more.


To get my feet wet with the whole "investigations" thing that we'd do, I 
started looking into this one day and chose one of the many temp sensors 
which were being logged by the servers.  I forget exactly which one it 
was, for there were many.  The CPUs logged it, the chassis logged it, 
the power supply logged it, and so on.  There were so many choices.


I went looking for a reason.  What could possibly explain this?  First 
off, it didn't line up with any obvious pattern in the host names.  The 
hosts were named for whichever team owned them, followed by a sequence 
number that was bumped any time a new one was provisioned.  There was no 
signal to be found in that.


There was more, though.  You could also see a "rack position" in this 
data, and now it started getting interesting.  It seems that all of the 
really hot machines had a rack position of something low, like 04 or 05, 
and never anything higher than that.  In fact, when looking at a whole 
rack, it was always the lowest number of all of the positions that were 
being used.  Now this was worth chasing!


It's good that I asked, since they told me something surprising: 
position 04 or 05 or whatever was the *bottom* of the rack.  Yes, 
somehow, the lowest machine in the rack was the hottest!  They found 
this interesting, too, and wound up digging into it.  Given that I was 
far away in a distant office, this was the best way for us to proceed.


The problem was that the bottommost server would have nothing below it 
but just open space until it got to the floor.  That space would not 
move air efficiently, and it obviously mattered.


This rolled out and my hot spots disappeared.  Fantastic!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In support of Wren (the abuse she endured while working on Fight Knight)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5131</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/in-support-of-wren-the-abuse-she-endured-while-working-on-fight-knight"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T01:03:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am writing this post in support of Wren. Hello, I'm the "writer" of the Dangen Warning and the former writer of Fight Knight. I feel it's important for me to come forward about why I left the Fight Knight project. https://t.co/ccrZgh1IeA — Wren (@rivalerose) October 1, 2021 Wren is a wonderful human who endured physical abuse, psychological abuse, gaslighting, manipulation, and pretty much that entire spectrum that we’re way too used to hearing about when survivors share their stories. She endured this while working on the game Fight Knight, putting out what I’m sure was amazing work that we...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTTPS and your online security]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.mozilla.org/foxtail/2017/04/21/https-protect/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/https-protect/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T21:47:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have long advised Web users to look for HTTPS and the lock icon in the address bar of their favorite browser (Firefox!) before typing passwords or other private information into a website. These are solid tips, but it’s worth digging deeper into what HTTPS does and doesn’t do to protect your online security and […]
The post HTTPS and your online security appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M.J. Kelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 13 Oct 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2712</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/10/13/theres-an-app-for-that/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T16:26:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Charter uses bad credit threats to corral ex-subscribers: "Resubscribe or we'll keep trashing your credit report." Adobe uses copyfraud to preserve spyware: A free-as-in-surveillance-free Flash installer is gone thanks to a bogus copyright claim. India funded a starving kids' app, but not food: Solutionism at its worst. This day in history: 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Charter uses bad credit threats to corral ex-subscribers (permalink) I'm more of a Charter-Spectrum hostage than a customer: I need the internet to earn my living, and my town (Burbank) has signed an exclusive deal with Charter, so I send them $134.99/mo for some of the worst internet in California. It turns out that Chart…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Screencasting technical guide by Egghead [link]]]></title>
        <id>2021-10-13-b8820d28</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/links/2021-10-13-b8820d28"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T12:14:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Egghead screencasts themselves are excellent, but this is a treasure trove of tips for better screencasts.
Better screencasts often (to me) means simpler for your audience or student to follow along - which is only positive.
Source: howtoegghead.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flag Map Sabotage]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2528/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2528/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/flag_map_sabotage.png" title="Delaware hopes to explore the western edge of areas marked with the Belgian flag, once the tornadoes die down." alt="Delaware hopes to explore the western edge of areas marked with the Belgian flag, once the tornadoes die down." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An UPDATE without a WHERE, or something close to it]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/12/break/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/12/break/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T19:50:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I know I've already
commented
on a certain site's big outage
twice now,
but I have one more bit of rumor to share, and it apparently invalidates 
what I had heard previously.  That is, it may not have been a matter of 
"show X Y" vs. "clear X Y", but rather some kind of automation that went 
a bit too far.


Then, what if you didn't have to actually type something in to hit the 
button?  Maybe you forgot, or something else happened, and you didn't 
fill it in, so when you did that, it said "okay, cool then" and 
did all of them instead?


Go to tool, don't type in target, hit button, ALL targets affected.


It sounds like another kind of "footgun" (you know, something you can 
use to shoot yourself in the foot) from the world of databases: an 
UPDATE without a WHERE.



UPDATE my_table SET invalid = true WHERE asset_id = 1012;



Imagine what happens when you forget the WHERE.  It's the last thing on 
the line as shown, so you could send off the command early and it would 
totally work.  It would look like this:


And... guess what, without that WHERE, it just set that bit everywhere.  
Everything is marked invalid, and your business might suffer for it.


Final note on the "do all the things" thing: maybe the tool 
actually is supposed to let you do that.  In that case, maybe it would 
be good if it said something like "you are about to drain 123,456 
devices, so type in that exact number to proceed".  You know,
that
kind of thing.  It tends to add enough of a pause to prevent some 
disasters.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 12 Oct 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2703</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/10/12/no-criminals-no-crimes/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T18:22:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links This Thing Between Us, a neck-hair-stand-up cuycuy horror: Gus Moreno's debut novel. There are no corporate criminals in America: Because America doesn't have corporate crime prosecutions. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading This Thing Between Us, a neck-hair-stand-up cuycuy horror (permalink) Gus Moreno's debut novel, "This Thing Between Us," is a genuinely creepy supernatural horror novel, a book that made the hairs on the back of my neck stand up and prompted me to turn on the nightlight at bedtime. https://www.fsgoriginals.com/books/this-thing-between-us I almost didn't read it. It's billed as a book about a widower whose smart-speaker is haunted by his wife…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What if… you could use Visual Studio Code as the editor of in-browser Developer Tools?]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=6972</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/10/12/what-if-you-could-use-visual-studio-code-as-the-editor-of-in-browser-developer-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T15:21:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting with the next version of Microsoft Edge, we are running an experiment that allows you to use Visual Studio Code as the editor of the in-browser Developer Tools. Here’s a three minute video explaining why we think this is a good idea. Developer Tools have excellent visual tools that allow you to tweak and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 11 Oct 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2697</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/10/11/consider-the-ant/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T15:26:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Hope, Not Optimism": A theory of change based on truth, not fiction. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Hope, Not Optimism" (permalink) This week on my podcast, a reading of my latest Medium column, "Hope, not optimism," in which I describe a theory of change that distinguishes activism from novelism. https://doctorow.medium.com/hope-not-optimism-943e88291b Plotting a novel is a process of radical simplification: a character goes through a linear progression of challenges of increasing difficulty and consequence, until the stakes are raised to their utmost when the tale reaches its climax. That's nothing like the real world (perhaps that…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Nobel Prizes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2527/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2527/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/new_nobel_prizes.png" title="They've endowed a separate prize in Physiology or Medicine or Stopping Dr. Adams." alt="They've endowed a separate prize in Physiology or Medicine or Stopping Dr. Adams." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating all the wonderful zines from the Electric Zine Jam 2.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5122</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/celebrating-all-the-wonderful-zines-from-the-electric-zine-jam-2-0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-10T00:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During the month of September I ran another Electric Zine Jam (the two point oh edition!) in which people made a bunch of beautiful zines. This jam was to celebrate the new Electric Zine Maker update which introduced a number of templates, and the brand new UI update. I’m also over the moon that PAGE online wrote about it! “Zines und OpenSource passen wunderbar zueinander, findet Nathalie Lawhead und entwickelt seit 2018 den Electric Zine Maker. Nun ist ein großes Update für das Printshop-Tool erschienen.” – by Lena Simonis on PAGE, Zine Design: Micro-Heft gestalten mit dem Electric Zine Maker...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Birthday ScummVM]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/scummvm_20</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/scummvm_20"/>
        <updated>2021-10-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wrote Scumm and I don't think I could do what they did.
Respect.
Happy Birthday ScummVM]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Oct 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2692</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/10/08/unfollow-everything/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T17:55:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Facebook shouldn't be in charge of how you use Facebook: Unfollow Everything and the need for (good) tech regulation. This day in history: 2006, 2011, 2016 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Facebook shouldn't be in charge of how you use Facebook (permalink) The Facebook whistleblower's testimony was refreshing and frightening by turns, revealing the company's awful internal culture, where product design decisions that benefited its users were sidelined if they were bad for its shareholders. The big question now is, what do we do about it? The whistleblower, Frances Haugen rejected the idea that Facebook's power should be diminished; rather, she argued that it should be harnessed – put under the supervision of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favorite Puzzle]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/favorite_puzzle</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/favorite_puzzle"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chatting with a game designer friend the other day and we were bemoaning the state of adventure game puzzles and it got us talking.  So I was wondering what is your favorite puzzle in Thimbleweed Park, Maniac Mansion, Monkey Island or any other classic point-and-click game?
Do you like head scratchers?  What makes a puzzle good? What makes a puzzle hard? What makes a puzzle just busy work? Is that bad?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TSP vs TBSP]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2526/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2526/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/tsp_vs_tbsp.png" title="It's like one teraspoon / when all you need is a kilonife" alt="It's like one teraspoon / when all you need is a kilonife" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Oct 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2687</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/10/07/markets-in-everything/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T16:12:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links DoS a federal agency, then charge for access: Enq carries on a tradition of genuinely terrible startup ideas. "Inclusive Access" allows textbook monopolists to permanently consolidate their gains: Universities are auto-billing students for high-priced, self-destructing textbooks they can't loan or sell. Scottish Limited Partnerships are still laundering criminal millions: Offshore is actually onshore. This day in history: 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading DoS a federal agency, then charge for access (permalink) There's a hell of a zap that neoclassical economics puts on your head. After being brainwashed to think that markets "naturally emerge" wherever a shortage occurs, a certain kind of ev…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 06 Oct 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2681</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/10/06/merck-cenary/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T16:13:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links We paid to develop Merck's covid pill: And now they're charging us a 4,000% markup on it. This day in history: 2016, 2020. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading We paid to develop Merck's covid pill (permalink) Comparing the government to a household or a business isn't merely inapt (a government is a currency creator, while a household is a currency user – their budgeting constraints are totally unrelated) – it's also profoundly dishonest. Like, if you really are worried about government "living beyond its means," then you should freak out every time Congress writes a $715B no-strings-attached check to the Pentagon, or sends $258B to the ultra-rich as part of the CARES Act. https://www.propublica.org/article/the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Low-tech Solar Panel?]]></title>
        <id>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/typepad/krisdedecker/lowtechmagazineenglish/~3/s1xYIgkW3e8/how-to-build-a-low-tech-solar-panel.html</id>
        <link href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/typepad/krisdedecker/lowtechmagazineenglish/~3/s1xYIgkW3e8/how-to-build-a-low-tech-solar-panel.html"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[George Cove, a forgotten solar power pioneer, may have built a highly efficient photovoltaic panel 40 years before Bell Labs engineers invented silicon cells. If proven to work, his design could lead to less complex and more sustainable solar panels. Above: George Cove stands next to his third solar array. Source: "Generating electricity by the sun's rays", Popular Electricity, Volume 2, nr. 12, April 1910, pp.793. More efficient, less sustainable Ever since Bell Labs presented the first practical solar PV panel in the 1950s, technological development has focused on reducing costs and increasing the efficiency of solar cells. According to these standards, researchers have made a lot of progress. The efficiency of solar panels increased from less than 5% in...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>LOW-TECH MAGAZINE</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible Animations in React]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/prefers-reduced-motion/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/prefers-reduced-motion/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T05:42:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I really love animation, but not everybody does. In fact, it can make some people literally sick! In this tutorial, we'll see how to ensure that we respect user preferences, and create animations that can be disabled.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Air Travel Packing List]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2525/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2525/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/air_travel_packing_list.png" title="I know the etiquette is controversial, but I think it's rude when the person in front of me reclines their seat into the bell of my trumpet." alt="I know the etiquette is controversial, but I think it's rude when the person in front of me reclines their seat into the bell of my trumpet." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['date -d' vs. 'date -s', and 'show foo' vs. 'clear foo']]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/05/cmd/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/05/cmd/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T21:54:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's something fun I saw which created an outage once.  I've written 
about this
before,
but in light of yesterday's fun and games, I figured this one is worth 
another mention.


One way to do this on a Linux box with the usual GNU userspace stuff is 
to feed it to date, like this:


The problem is, there's another command very much like it that will even 
spit out the same output, only it has a nice little side-effect: it 
also sets the clock.  That command is date -s.


Another problem is that you might not have known that -s has that 
effect, and you have been using it because it gives you the output you 
want, and you don't realize what else it can do.


This then touched off a whole bunch of badness which I already talked 
about before.  It messed up other systems, and brought up questions of 
how to defend against it, and all of that other good stuff you'd expect 
to hear after a problem of that sort.

display everything, but instead it 
cleared everything.


show mpls lsp


clear mpls lsp


Hopefully the similarity to 'date -d' vs. 'date -s' is clear.

Small commands can have giant consequences.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mailbag: Macro to Micro Ideas]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42081</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/10/05/mailbag-macro-to-micro-ideas/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T17:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s question, gathered from Twitter a little while back, is this: How do you go from the macro to the micro, i.e. from a big, broad idea for a game to the concrete instantiation of it? A long time ago I wrote Idea to Implementation, a discussion of how to get from implementation to completed … Continue reading "Mailbag: Macro to Micro Ideas"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Oct 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2672</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/10/05/masha-rides-again/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T15:43:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Attack Surface paperback is out: And a once-in-a-lifetime deal on the Little Brother audiobooks. Dave Eggers' "The Every": A tragicomic look at Big Tech, following from "The Circle." Open Access Ninja: "The Brew of Law." This day in history: 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Attack Surface paperback is out (permalink) It's my book-birthday! Today marks publication of the Tor (US/Canada) paperback edition of ATTACK SURFACE, a standalone adult Little Brother book. https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250757517/attacksurface Little Brother and its sequel Homeland were young adult novels that told the tale of Marcus Yallow, a bright young activist in San Francisco who works with his peers to orga…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[News from Firefox Focus and Firefox on Mobile]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67466</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/news-from-firefox-focus-and-firefox-on-mobile/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of our promises this year was to deliver ways that can help you navigate the web easily and get you quickly where you need to go. We took a giant step in that direction earlier this year when we shared a new Firefox experience. We were on a mission to save you time and […]
The post News from Firefox Focus and Firefox on Mobile appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tools to explore BGP]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/10/05/tools-to-look-at-bgp-routes/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/10/05/tools-to-look-at-bgp-routes/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T08:53:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday there was a big Facebook outage caused by BGP. I’ve been vaguely
interested in learning more about BGP for a long time, so I was reading a
couple of articles.
I got frustrated because none of the articles showed me how I could actually
look up information related to BGP on my computer, so I wrote a tweet asking for tools.
I got a bunch of useful replies as always, so this blog post shows some tools
you can use to look up BGP information. There might be an above average number
of things wrong in this post because I don’t understand BGP that well.
I can’t publish BGP routes
One of the reasons I’ve never learned much about BGP is – as far as I know, I don’t have access to publish BGP routes on the internet.
With most networking protocols, you can pretty trivially get access to
imple…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In the news today: *munch munch munch*]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/04/callthecops/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/10/04/callthecops/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T18:39:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some people who know me and know what I used to do saw the news today 
(or just tried to go online for cat pictures and failed) have been 
reaching out for reactions.





As for the potential customer, well, you should know how to reach me.  
Bring your checkbook.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 04 Oct 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2663</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/10/04/avoidance-is-evasion/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T16:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Take It Back": My Medium column on copyright termination and rights reversion. Savage Love A-Z: A bestiary of good sex. The Pandora Papers: Tax avoidance is tax evasion. USPS pilots postal banking: Slashing taxes (on the poor). This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Take It Back" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read "Take It Back," my Medium essay, "Take it back: Copyright reversion, bargaining power, and authors’ rights," all about the obscure, but increasingly exciting realm of copyright termination at reversion. https://doctorow.medium.com/take-it-back-e3689628f4f0 What's copyright termination? Under US law, creators can file paper…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a VPN at home? Here are 5 reasons you might.]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67429</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/mozilla-vpn/do-you-need-a-vpn-at-home-here-are-5-reasons-you-might/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T15:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might have heard of VPNs — virtual private networks — at some point, and chalked them up to something only “super techy” people or hackers would ever use. At this point in the evolution of online life, however, VPNs have become more mainstream, and anyone may have good reasons to use one. VPNs are […]
The post Do you need a VPN at home? Here are 5 reasons you might. appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M.J. Kelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comet Visitor]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2524/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2524/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/comet_visitor.png" title="It's a myth that the Great Wall of China is the only human-made structure visible from space--there are LOTS of structures for us to feel self-conscious about!" alt="It's a myth that the Great Wall of China is the only human-made structure visible from space--there are LOTS of structures for us to feel self-conscious about!" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for September]]></title>
        <id>log.html#sep2021</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#sep2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of September. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Orca, added way for instances of Orca to talk to each other.
Calc, wrote a little graphical calculator to help with learning binary and hexadecimal.
Dexe, added option to copy the textual value of a selection.
Uxn, updated UxnDS emulator.
Wiktopher, added Chapter 16: The Big Dark.
100R, added new pages: Western Canada, alcohol stove, decorations and shore power cord repair. The site also has a new splash.
News
It is an early announcement, but end of June 2022 we will be giving a keynote presentation, alongside Khyam Allami, at NIME(New Interfaces for Musical Expression).
Rekka wrote an article on Saving Energy When Cooking Aboard for Noonsite.
Check out Eli's guide on installing Uxn on OS X, and Keijiro's version of Flappy Bird in UxnTal.
Our friends at Compudanzas have released part 6 of their Introduction to Uxn Programming tutorial. This new chapter basically shows you how to build Pong!
Pino book club
We started reading The Stories of Ray Bradbury by Ray Bradbury. Favorite shorts so far include There Will Come Soft Rains, The Coffin and There Was an Old Woman.
Pino's location: 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS prefers-color-scheme user query and order of preference]]></title>
        <id>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/prefers-color-scheme-browser-vs-os/</id>
        <link href="https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/prefers-color-scheme-browser-vs-os/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I spent some time in Reeder app this morning, catching up with RSS and the latest articles published by my favorite blogs.
I was reading Scott O’Hara’s article about using JavaScript to detect high contrast and dark modes, which includes a small, very useful script to do exactly what the title says. The output of that script at first looked like it was a “false positive”. But some further investigation led me to learn something new about the prefers-color-scheme CSS user query.

Scott’s article includes a Codepen to demonstrate the output of the script. The script will check and detect if you currently have high contrast mode or dark mode enabled, and will output the result of the check.
See the Pen 
  JavaScript to detect media queries by Scott (@scottohara)
  on CodePen.


Since JavaScri…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Blog on SaraSoueidan.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 02 Oct 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2658</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/10/02/debt-trap/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T17:50:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links How the IMF loan-sharks the global south: With surcharges, the cruelty is the point. This day in history: 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading How the IMF loan-sharks the global south (permalink) When you take out a loan or get a credit card, the headline figure is the "APR" – the annual percentage rate of interest. But anyone who's ever borrowed because they were poor and needed money has learned the hard way that APRs are pure fiction. To get the true APR (what economists politely call the "effective" APR) you have to factor in the fees, penalties and other gotchas that turn reasonable seeming interest rates into perennial, inescapable debt-traps. Take student debt. During the 2020 presi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All my zines are now available in print!]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/10/02/all-my-zines-are-now-available-in-print/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/10/02/all-my-zines-are-now-available-in-print/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T09:42:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! In June I announced that I was releasing 4 zines in print and promised “more zines
coming soon”. “Soon” has arrived! You can get any zine you want in print now!
I’m doing this now so that you can get zines in the mail in time for Christmas, or
any other end-of-year holiday you celebrate :)
you can preorder zines today!
First the basic facts!
you can preorder zines as of today
the preorder deadline is October 12
zines will ship around November 5
you’ll get them in time for Christmas
more logistical details in the Preorders FAQ
Here’s the link to get them:
Preorder print zines





Here are a few more notes about how the print zines work – they’re mostly the same as last time
why a preorder?
It makes it easier to decide how many zines to print! I don’t want to
accidentally underestima…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Miracle Whip, Finstas, #InternationalPodcastDay, and #FreeBritney all made the Top Shelf this week]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67511</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/best-tweets-miracle-whip-finstas-internationalpodcastday-freebritney-oct-1/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T22:12:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Mozilla, we believe part of making the internet we want is celebrating the best of the internet, and that can be as simple as sharing a tweet that made us pause in our feed. Twitter isn’t perfect, but there are individual tweets that come pretty close. Each week in Top Shelf, we will be […]
The post Miracle Whip, Finstas, #InternationalPodcastDay, and #FreeBritney all made the Top Shelf this week appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis of  Google’s Privacy Budget Proposal]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67487</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/google-privacy-budget-analysis/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fingerprinting is a major threat to user privacy on the Web. Fingerprinting uses existing properties of your browser like screen size, installed add-ons, etc. to create a unique or semi-unique identifier which it can use to track you around the Web. Even if individual values are not particularly unique, the combination of values can be […]
The post Analysis of  Google’s Privacy Budget Proposal appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Rescorla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superhero passwords may be your kryptonite wherever you go online]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67455</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/superhero-passwords-may-be-your-kryptonite-wherever-you-go-online/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T13:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A password is like a key to your house. In the online world, your password keeps your house of personal information safe, so a super strong password is like having a superhero in a fight of good vs. evil. In recognition of Cybersecurity Awareness month, we revisited our “Princesses make terrible passwords for Disney+ and […]
The post Superhero passwords may be your kryptonite wherever you go online appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenifer Boscacci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Endangered]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2523/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2523/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/endangered.png" title="The list includes polio, Guinea worm, and this one particular enterovirus strain that they've been tracking out of spite after it went around the lab a few years ago." alt="The list includes polio, Guinea worm, and this one particular enterovirus strain that they've been tracking out of spite after it went around the lab a few years ago." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2647</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/30/dont-believe-the-criti-hype/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T18:06:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Facebook thrives on criticism of "disinformation": They'd rather be evil than incompetent. This day in history: 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Facebook thrives on criticism of "disinformation" (permalink) The mainstream critique of Facebook is surprisingly compatible with Facebook's own narrative about its products. FB critics say that the company's machine learning and data-gathering slides disinformation past users' critical faculties, poisoning their minds. Meanwhile, Facebook itself tells advertisers that it can use data and machine learning to slide past users' critical faculties, convincing them to buy stuff. In other words, the mainline of Facebook critics start from the presumption that …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of September Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42219</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/09/30/end-of-september-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events Tomorrow, October 1, IF Comp games will be available to play and judge. Anyone can participate in judging — so if you want to be part of that, check out the website for instructions. The judging period runs through November 15. October 2 is the next meetup of the San Francisco Bay Area IF … Continue reading "End of September Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fun with glibc and the ctype.h functions]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/29/alnum/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/29/alnum/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T05:34:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I got really bored tonight and went down some rabbit holes and turned up 
something from about a year ago.  If you follow the latest Linux type 
stuff, you probably remember this, but if not, this might seem new to 
you.  It's just something dumb and amusing.


Go grab a Linux box with glibc on it.  Then compile and run this C code:


Then run it and watch what happens.  If you have multiple machines, try 
it on some of them and compare the results.  If the results are 
different, why do you suppose that is?


Neat, right?  It makes me want to go looking for places where people are 
calling these functions with ints that I can control to see if I can 
blow it up.

source
to see how the sausage is made by someone who did the work already.


...


This is awesome because it's that many more possibilities.  I had been 
grepping source for "isalnum" to try to find inputs I can control, but 
now I realize that FAR more functions give a way into this.  Have fun!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 29 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2638</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/29/jubilance/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T19:36:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Debts that can't be paid, won't be paid: The first David Graeber Foundation meetup, between Thomas Piketty and Michael Hudson. "Are you calling me a racist?": The libertarian case for racism. Wells Fargo can't stop criming: The nation's third-biggest bank is a criminal enterprise. This day in history: 2001, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Debts that can't be paid, won't be paid (permalink) It's been just over a year since the death of activist, writer and anthropologist Gavid Graeber – a brilliant speaker, writer and thinker who helped give us Occupy, "we are the 99%" and "Bullshit Jobs." On the anniversary of David's death, his widow Nika Dubrovsky convened the first "Art Project" discussi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Repairing our shore power cord]]></title>
        <id>shore_power_cord_repair.html</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/shore_power_cord_repair.html"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On a rainy summer day, we pulled into Silva bay on Gabriola Island and found a place at a dock to wait out a spell of bad weather. The power receptacle appeared fine, but once we were ready to leave we found the male connection of our shore power cord had melted. Two out of three prongs were stuck in the receptacle. We've never had issues with our cord before, and for now we assume that the marina shore connection was faulty. Either way, we had to repair the power cord.
We always prefer to repair than to replace, so when we returned to a place with a marine store, we got ourselves replacements connections, both male and female, to replace the two damaged ends.
We thought we'd document the process of fixing a shower power cord. Although, this is only specific to Marinco marine fittings.
In …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-Factor Security Key]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2522/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2522/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/two_factor_security_key.png" title="The bruises on my fingertips are my proof of work." alt="The bruises on my fingertips are my proof of work." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2631</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/28/timescale-dependent/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T16:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Democrats can pass the reconciliation today (sorta): A bet on the 'endowment effect.' This day in history: 2001, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Resourcecent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Democrats can pass the reconciliation today (sorta) (permalink) This week, millions are playing Congressional Kremlinology, guessing whether House/Senate Dems have the votes for the $3.5T reconciliation package, playing Fantasy Football Sophie's Choice to cut programs if corporate Dems whittle it down. https://prospect.org/infrastructure/building-back-america/infrastructure-summer-sophies-choice-of-the-reconciliation-bill/ But as Harold Meyerson writes for The American Prospect, there's a high-stakes, high-risk gambit that would let the willing, pr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The World of CSS Transforms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/transforms/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/transforms/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:03:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The “transform” property is such a powerful part of the CSS language! In this blog post, we'll take a deep look at this property and see some of the nifty things it can do.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Magical 3D Button]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/3d-button/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/3d-button/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:03:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every action we take on the web starts with a button click, and yet most buttons are ho-hum and uninspired. In this tutorial, we'll build an animated 3D button with HTML and CSS that sparks joy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Importance of Learning CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/the-importance-of-learning-css/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/the-importance-of-learning-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:03:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I know so many super-talented developers who share the same achilles heel: CSS. Instead of trying to “outrun” CSS, this article explores why leaning in and going deeper can be a tremendous boon for your development life and your career.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What the heck, z-index??]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/stacking-contexts/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/stacking-contexts/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:03:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The z-index property can be a tricky little bugger. Sometimes, no matter how much you crank up the number, the element never rises to the top! In this article, we explore stacking contexts, and see how they can thwart our efforts to use z-index. We'll also learn how to use this mechanism to our advantage.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full-Bleed Layout Using CSS Grid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/full-bleed/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/full-bleed/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:03:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Certain layouts are surprisingly dastardly. On the modern web, one of the most common layouts is also one of the trickiest. In this tutorial, I break down how to build the "full-bleed" layout using CSS Grid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 27 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2623</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/27/lethal-dysfunction/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T18:16:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Breaking In": Why you shouldn't take career advice from successful writers. Democrats, health care monopolies, and market failures: Market health care is a fatal disease. Shelter is a toxic asset: NIMBYism is a fatal disease. This day in history: 2001, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Breaking In" (permalink) This week on my podcast, a reading of "Breaking In," my latest column for Locus Magazine. It was inspired by the writers who are just starting out and looking for advice on how to advance their careers – and my realization that I have none to give. https://locusmag.com/2021/09/cory-doctorow-breaking-in/ After all, when I broke into science fiction, the web barely exist…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toothpaste]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2521/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2521/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/toothpaste.png" title="&quot;9 out of 10 dentists have banned me from their offices.&quot;" alt="&quot;9 out of 10 dentists have banned me from their offices.&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 26 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2618</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/26/mike-ford-rides-again/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T15:25:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Scholars of Night: John M Ford was a goddamned WIZARD. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Scholars of Night (permalink) John M Ford ("Mike" to his many friends) was one of science fiction's most accomplished writers, by which I mean, his accomplishments were so prodigious as to be slightly bewildering. If he hadn't been so mind-bogglingly quick-witted in person, it would be tempting to believe that his books were the product of several eccentric geniuses. Everything he did, he did brilliantly, and he did so very much. He was the author of several bestselling, award-winning RPG modules, and a Star Trek novel that was also a Gilbert and Sullivan musical, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generative art & tools (on the intersection of toys, tools, and games…)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5114</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/generative-art-tools-on-the-intersection-of-toys-tools-and-games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T00:42:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hoarded a lot of links to tools again, and am putting aside some time to share them here. Here’s another tool post! I just opened a blog category called “tools” in which you can read all my writing about open source, freeware, or small tools from small devs. At this point I feel like I’ve already said everything I can possibly say about the wonderful world of tools, coming out of this space… It’s an inspiring area that never fails to surprise! One thing that I’ve been thinking about lately is the intersection between tools and games. When you...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 24 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2611</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/24/comcom-acm/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:20:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Demonopolizing the internet with interoperability: My op-ed in the Communications of the ACM This day in history: 2001, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Demonopolizing the internet with interoperability (permalink) The Communications of the Association for Computing Machinery has just published my editorial, "Competitive Compatibility: Let's Fix the Internet, Not the Tech Giants," explaining how interoperability was once an engine for competition and user empowerment – and how that ended. https://cacm.acm.org/magazines/2021/10/255710-competitive-compatibility/fulltext As the title suggests, regulators are fed up with Big Tech's abuses, but they're not sure what to do about it. One approach is to "…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New tool: an nginx playground]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/09/24/new-tool--an-nginx-playground/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/09/24/new-tool--an-nginx-playground/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T08:25:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! On Wednesday I was talking to a friend about how it would be cool to
have an nginx playground website where you can just paste in an nginx config
and test it out. And then I realized it might actually be pretty easy to build,
so got excited and started coding and I built it. It’s at
https://nginx-playground.wizardzines.com.
Here’s a screenshot:

For the rest of the post I’m mostly going to talk about how I built the
project, because there were a few decisions that weren’t obvious to me.
how to use it
You need to enter both an nginx config and a curl or http command to make a
HTTP request to that nginx instance
And then you click “Run” in the top right, and it’ll output either:
the results of the command you executed (if nginx started successfully), or
the nginx error logs (if nginx …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symbols]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2520/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2520/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/symbols.png" title="&quot;röntgen&quot; and &quot;rem&quot; are 20th-century physics terms that mean &quot;no trespassing.&quot;" alt="&quot;röntgen&quot; and &quot;rem&quot; are 20th-century physics terms that mean &quot;no trespassing.&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 23 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2606</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/23/remedies-beyond-antitrust/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T16:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Halloween Moon: A YA novel from Nightvale creator Joseph Fink. The music monopolists: Thinking outside the antitrust box. This day in history: 2011, 2016 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Halloween Moon (permalink) In "The Halloween Moon," Welcome to Nightvale co-creator Joseph Fink brings his superb, unmatchable gift for balancing the weird and the real to a spooky middle-grades novel that echoes such classics as Neil Gaiman's Coraline. https://www.harpercollins.com/products/the-halloween-moon-joseph-fink If you're a stranger to Fink's work, the thing you need to know is that Nightvale and his other projects manage to walk the tightrope between weird, creepypasta-style humor and real pathos, in a glo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Content Model Is Not a Design System]]></title>
        <id>https://alistapart.com/article/a-content-model-is-not-a-design-system/</id>
        <link href="https://alistapart.com/article/a-content-model-is-not-a-design-system/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you remember when having a great website was enough? Now, people are getting answers from Siri, Google search snippets, and mobile apps, not just our websites. Forward-thinking organizations have adopted an omnichannel content strategy, whose mission is to reach audiences across multiple digital channels and platforms.
But how do you set up a content management system (CMS) to reach your audience now and in the future? I learned the hard way that creating a content model—a definition of content types, attributes, and relationships that let people and systems understand content—with my more familiar design-system thinking would capsize my customer’s omnichannel content strategy. You can avoid that outcome by creating content models that are semantic and that also connect related content.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>by</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A different take on the NUMA OOM killer story]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/22/membind/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/22/membind/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T05:10:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was digging through some notes on old outages tonight and found 
something potentially useful for other people.  It's something I
have mentioned before,
but it seems like maybe that post didn't have enough specifics to
make it really "land" when someone else does a web search.


On a Wednesday night not so long ago, someone opened a SEV (that is, a 
notification of something going wrong) and said the individual tasks for 
their service were "crash looping".  These things ran in an environment 
where they were supervised by the job runner, so if they died, they'd be 
restarted, but you never wanted to keep it in this kind of state.


It looked like this had started when some update had rolled out.  That 
is, prior to the update, their service was fine.  After they changed 
something, it s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 22 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2598</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/22/kropotkin-graeber/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T16:43:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Gig workers around the globe: One disease, many pathologies. Mutual Aid and David Graeber: A new, illustrated edition of Kropotkin's masterpiece, with an introduction from the great, much-missed hero of Occupy. Facebook algorithm boosts pro-Facebook news: Orwell was an optimist. This day in history: 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Gig workers around the globe (permalink) My 2010 YA science fiction novel For the Win imagines a global solidarity movement among precarious gig workers paid to "gold farm" inside massively multiplayer online games. https://craphound.com/category/ftw/ The kids who do this work realize they have more in common with each other than their bosses, and form a glo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Escher Circuits: Using Vision to Perform Computation]]></title>
        <id>https://esoteric.codes/blog/escher-circuits-using-vision-to-perform-computation</id>
        <link href="https://esoteric.codes/blog/escher-circuits-using-vision-to-perform-computation"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T07:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2008, Mark Changizi, a Sloan-Swartz Fellow in Theoretical Neuroscience at Caltech, noted that the eye can make sense of complex relationships that often mystify the brain. 


Our everyday visual perceptions rely upon unfathomably complex computations carried out by tens of billions of neurons across over half our cortex. In spite of this, it does not “feel” like work to see. Our cognitive powers are, in stark contrast, “slow and painful,” and we have great trouble with embarrassingly simple logic tasks. 

Might it be possible to harness our visual computational powers for other tasks, perhaps for tasks cognition finds difficult? 


In other words, could we trick the eye into performing computation? 

Changizi proposed the Escher Circuit, "a special kind of image that amounts to 'visual software' our 'visual hardware' computes" merely through perception.

Escher Circuits work by creating different states corresponding to how the eye resolves ambiguous images. Its core component, the wire, holds a state of 0 when we perceive it as if we are to the right of it; otherwise, it holds a state of 1.


wire


0


1


 
Read More]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>esoteric.codes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sloped Border]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2519/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2519/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sloped_border.png" title="&quot;The slope will be 74° at ground level.&quot; &quot;Okay, I think we can hack together a  ... wait, why did they specify ground level? It's 74° everywhere, right? ... Oh no, there's a whole section in the treaty labeled 'curvature.'&quot;" alt="&quot;The slope will be 74° at ground level.&quot; &quot;Okay, I think we can hack together a  ... wait, why did they specify ground level? It's 74° everywhere, right? ... Oh no, there's a whole section in the treaty labeled 'curvature.'&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Location history: How your location is tracked and how you can limit sharing it]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67369</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/mozilla-explains/location-history/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In real estate, the age old mantra is “location, location, location,” meaning that location drives value. That’s true even when it comes to data collection in the online world, too — your location history is valuable, authentic information. In all likelihood, you’re leaving a breadcrumb trail of location data every day, but there are a […]
The post Location history: How your location is tracked and how you can limit sharing it appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M.J. Kelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Interactive Guide to CSS Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/css-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/css-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T17:49:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This comprehensive guide shows how to use CSS transitions! A back-to-basics look at the fundamental building blocks we need to create microinteractions and other animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 21 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2590</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/21/monica-byrne/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T14:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Actual Star: Monica Byrne's millennium-spanning tour-de-force climate novel. Ignore career advice from established writers: We don't know anything about breaking in today. The Framework is the most exciting laptop I've ever used: Sustainable, upgradeable, repairable and powerful. This day in history: 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Actual Star (permalink) This month marks the publication of "The Actual Star," a new, wildly ambitious, wildly successful novel by Monica Byrne, spanning 3,000 years of history from the ancient Maya to a distant future. https://www.harpervoyagerbooks.com/book/9780063002913/the-actual-star/ The tale braids three moments: the collapse of the Mayan roy…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple's private relay service does not sit still]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/20/hop/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/20/hop/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T01:45:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have an older iPhone that used to be my daily driver.  It mostly just 
hangs around for testing random junk.  It's still getting updates, and 
so when Apple offered it iOS 15 today, I installed it.  This gave me a 
chance to turn on their beta "private relay" stuff which seems to be 
a TOR-like system.


What did surprise me is the lack of "stickiness" for these IP addresses.  
Every five seconds or so, it seems to hop to another address in the same 
(IPv6, remember) /64.  If you're not down with v6 conventions yet, this 
means the first four parts like "xxxx:xxxx:xxxx:xxxx" stay the same, but 
the last four change completely every time.


I actually don't have any v4-only (aka LEGACY) stuff to try it on, so I 
have no idea what happens on that side of the world.  It probably looks 
about the same, albeit within a much smaller range of possible source IP 
addresses.  It probably resembles a CGNAT type situation.

It'll be fun to see what this breaks, and who howls the loudest.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did you hear about Apple’s security vulnerability? Here’s how to find and remove spyware.]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67335</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/mozilla-explains/find-and-remove-spyware/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T16:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spyware has been in the news recently with stories like the Apple security vulnerability that allowed devices to be infected without the owner knowing it, and a former editor of The New York Observer being charged with a felony for unlawfully spying on his spouse with spyware. Spyware is a sub-category of malware that’s aimed […]
The post Did you hear about Apple’s security vulnerability? Here’s how to find and remove spyware. appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Claudius</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching by filling in knowledge gaps]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/09/20/teaching-by-filling-in-knowledge-gaps/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/09/20/teaching-by-filling-in-knowledge-gaps/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T09:28:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! This post (like patterns in confusing explanations)
is another one in the “julia attempts to articulate her teaching strategy”
series.
I’ll start out by talking about a “backwards” approach to learning
that I think a lot of you will recognize (do projects first without fully
understanding what you’re doing, fill in missing knowledge after), and then
talk about I try to teach in a way that works better with that mode of
learning.
how I’ve learned programming: backwards
There are a lot of “basic” concepts in programming, like memory management,
networking, operating systems, assembly, etc. You could imagine that you learn
programming by first starting with the basic concepts and then learning
abstractions on top of those concepts.
But, even though I have a very traditional CS backgrou…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lumpers and Splitters]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2518/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2518/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/lumpers_and_splitters.png" title="Anna Karenina is a happy family lumper and unhappy family splitter." alt="Anna Karenina is a happy family lumper and unhappy family splitter." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rover Replies]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2517/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2517/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/rover_replies.png" title="I'm so glad NASA let you take your phone to Mars!" alt="I'm so glad NASA let you take your phone to Mars!" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Me & Tinnitus: entry 4 [blog]]]></title>
        <id>me-and-tinnitus-entry-4</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2021/09/17/me-and-tinnitus-entry-4"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continuing my short diary of tinnitus treatment using the Lenire device (entry 1, 2, 3), I'm now at the 6 week mark.
The entire treatment period is 12 weeks, and at this point in time, I have a consultant appointment to ask how I'm getting on, and then to return the device for an adjustment and then it's sent back for me to continue the next 6 weeks.
So, how have I been getting on?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Great Resignation: New gig? Here are 7 tips to ensure success]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67274</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/the-great-resignation-new-job-tips/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T20:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If recent surveys and polls ring true, over 46% of the global workforce is considering leaving their employer this year. Despite COVID-19 causing initial turnover due to the related economic downturn, the current phenomenon coined “The Great Resignation” is attributed to the many job seekers choosing to leave their current employment voluntarily. Mass vaccinations and […]
The post The Great Resignation: New gig? Here are 7 tips to ensure success appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Vasquez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Learn Stuff Quickly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/blog/how-to-learn-stuff-quickly/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/blog/how-to-learn-stuff-quickly/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T19:58:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As software developers, we're always learning new things; it's practically the whole gig! If we can learn to quickly pick up new languages/frameworks/tools, we'll become so much more effective at our job. It's sort of a superpower.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding the basics of electricity by thinking of it as water [link]]]></title>
        <id>2021-09-16-e08f8eb6</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/links/2021-09-16-e08f8eb6"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T15:55:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been struggling to get my head around voltage and amps - specifically after I bought a device that wanted 5V and 2A supply, but I was only giving it 1.6A I found the machine would fail (and reboot). The lack of amperage meant it wasn't able to supply the entire board.
Just the image from this post was enough to make it click in my head 👍


VOLTAGE is like the pressure that pushes water through the hose. It is measured in volts (V).


CURRENT is like the diameter of the hose. The wider it is, the more water will flow through. It is measured in amps (I or A).


RESISTANCE is like sand in the hose that slows down the water flow. It is measured in ohms (R or Ω).


Source: www.freeingenergy.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging by starting a REPL at a breakpoint is fun]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/09/16/debugging-in-a-repl-is-fun/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/09/16/debugging-in-a-repl-is-fun/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T08:48:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I was talking to a Python programmer friend yesterday about debugging,
and I mentioned that I really like debugging using a REPL. He said he’d never
tried it and that it sounded fun, so I thought I’d write a quick post about it.
This debugging method doesn’t work in a lot of languages, but it does work in
Python and Ruby and kiiiiiind of in C (via gdb).
what’s a REPL?
REPL stands for “read eval print loop”. A REPL is a program that:
reads some input from you like print(f"2 + 2 = {2+2}") (read)
evaluates the input (eval)
print out the result (print)
and then goes back to step 1 (loop)
Here’s an example of me using the IPython REPL to run a print statement. (also
it demonstrates f-strings, my favourite Python 3 feature)
$ ipython3
Python 3.9.5 (default, May 24 2021, 12:50:35) 
Type 'c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Mirror Editing in Edge DevTools for VS Code]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=6959</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/09/16/css-mirror-editing-in-edge-devtools-for-vs-code/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T06:16:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summary: With the release of 1.3.1 of the Edge Tools for VS Code we introduce a better way to get changes you made in the Styles tool back into your source code. We’d love to know what you think of it and what we can do better. There’s a GitHub issue dedicated to feedback. Developer […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla VPN adds advanced privacy features: Custom DNS servers and Multi-hop]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67348</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/mozilla-vpn-adds-advanced-privacy-features-custom-dns-servers-and-multi-hop/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T22:43:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your online privacy remains our top priority, and we know that one of the first things to secure your privacy when you go online is to get on a Virtual Private Network (VPN), an encrypted connection that serves as a tunnel between your computer and VPN server. Today, we’re launching the latest release of our […]
The post Mozilla VPN adds advanced privacy features: Custom DNS servers and Multi-hop appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-September Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42212</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/09/15/mid-september-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events September 18-19, Emperatriz Ung is running a session for the Asian-American Writers’ Workshop called Prototyping Memory, A Game Design Approach To Nonfiction, about using Inform and IF techniques to reimagine setting, perspective, and structure. The Oxford/London IF Meetup is currently running a jam for pieces written for Seltani, Andrew Plotkin’s multiplayer hypertext platform. We’ll … Continue reading "Mid-September Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get where you’re going faster, with Firefox Suggest]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67315</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/firefox-news/firefox-suggest/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T16:16:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, people have to work too hard to find what they want online, sifting through and steering clear of content, clutter and click-bait not worthy of their time. Over time, navigation on the internet has become increasingly centralized and optimized for clicks and scrolling, not for getting people to where they want to go or […]
The post Get where you’re going faster, with Firefox Suggest appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Quest of Search]]></title>
        <id>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/in-quest-of-search/</id>
        <link href="https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/in-quest-of-search/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s been a recent discussion on Twitter about the idea of adding a new element in HTML that represents a search interface. A search form, basically.
The idea is to create a semantic HTML element for the ARIA search role, which represents a landmark region “that contains a collection of items and objects that, as a whole, combine to create a search facility.”
Opinions have been shared in the Twitter thread about whether adding a new HTML element is necessary. Many have argued that it was unnecessary because we can use the ARIA search role and repurpose a form element to create the same semantics. I disagree. And this article is the longer version of my personal opinion on the subject.
tl;dr
I do strongly encourage the addition of a new HTML element that represents—and can consequently o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Blog on SaraSoueidan.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hubble Tension]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2516/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2516/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/hubble_tension.png" title="Oh, wait, I might've had it set to kph instead of mph. But that would make the discrepancy even wider!" alt="Oh, wait, I might've had it set to kph instead of mph. But that would make the discrepancy even wider!" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing Beautiful Shadows in CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/designing-shadows/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/designing-shadows/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T14:31:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I look around the web, most of the shadows I see are fuzzy grey boxes. It doesn't have to be this way, though! CSS gives us the tools to create rich, lush, lifelike shadows. In this tutorial, I'll show you how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccine Research]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2515/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2515/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/vaccine_research.png" title="Honestly feel a little sheepish about the amount of time and effort I spent confirming &quot;yes, the vaccine helps protect people from getting sick and dying&quot; but I guess everyone needs a hobby." alt="Honestly feel a little sheepish about the amount of time and effort I spent confirming &quot;yes, the vaccine helps protect people from getting sick and dying&quot; but I guess everyone needs a hobby." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Variables for React Devs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/css-variables-for-react-devs/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/css-variables-for-react-devs/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T22:10:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Variables are *really* cool, and they're incredibly powerful when it comes to React! This tutorial shows how we can use them with React to create dynamic themes. We'll see how to get the most out of CSS-in-JS tools like styled-components, and how our mental frame around media queries has been wrong all along.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matrix 4, Blue’s Clues, #StarTrekDay and More — Everything That’s Old is New Again in This Week’s Top Shelf]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67302</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/best-tweets-matrix-blues-clues-september-10th/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T21:29:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Mozilla, we believe part of making the internet we want is celebrating the best of the internet, and that can be as simple as sharing a tweet that made us pause in our feed. Twitter isn’t perfect, but there are individual tweets that come pretty close. Each week in Top Shelf, we will be […]
The post Matrix 4, Blue’s Clues, #StarTrekDay and More — Everything That’s Old is New Again in This Week’s Top Shelf appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postcode & Geolocation API for the UK [link]]]></title>
        <id>2021-09-10-689ee834</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/links/2021-09-10-689ee834"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T13:26:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Free, Open Source and based solely on Open Data - simple API to boot.
Extremely useful for quick hacks, potentially useful for smaller projects (though limited to UK).
Source: postcodes.io]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quadratic algorithms are slow (and hashmaps are fast)]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/09/10/hashmaps-make-things-fast/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/09/10/hashmaps-make-things-fast/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T12:48:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I was talking to a friend yesterday who was studying for a programming
interview and trying to learn some algorithms basics.
The topic of quadratic-time vs linear-time algorithms came up, I thought this
would be fun to write about here because avoiding quadratic-time algorithms
isn’t just important in interviews – it’s sometimes good to know about in real
life too! I’ll explain what a “quadratic-time algorithm is” in a minute :)
here are the 3 things we’ll talk about:
quadratic time functions are WAY WAY WAY slower than linear time functions
sometimes you can make a quadratic algorithm into a linear algorithm by using a hashmap
this is because hashmaps lookups are very fast (instant!)
I’m going to try to keep the math jargon to a minimum and focus on real code
examples and how fast/…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lab Equipment]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2514/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2514/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/lab_equipment.png" title="I've been working on chocolate bar annealing techniques to try to produce the perfect laser s'more. Maybe don't mention that on the grant application though." alt="I've been working on chocolate bar annealing techniques to try to produce the perfect laser s'more. Maybe don't mention that on the grant application though." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feel good when you get online with Firefox]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67299</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/videos/feel-good-when-you-get-online-with-firefox/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T22:02:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The post Feel good when you get online with Firefox appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M.J. Kelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did internet friends fill the gaps left by social distance?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67252</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/internet-friends-during-pandemic-online/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T14:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[March 2020 brought to the world a scenario we only imagined possible in dystopian novels. Once bustling cities and towns were desolate. In contrast, the highways and byways of the internet were completely congested with people grasping for human connection, and internet friends became more important than ever.  Since then, there have been countless discussions […]
The post Did internet friends fill the gaps left by social distance? appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working with the ESP in Cspect [spectrum] [blog]]]></title>
        <id>working-with-the-esp-in-cspect</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2021/09/09/working-with-the-esp-in-cspect"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After developing the .http tool for the Spectrum Next in assembly, for my own workflow I did most of the testing against an emulator (before moving to hardware), however there's some quirks with Cspect and the wifi/esp/internet setup, and since I've been through the fire and come out the other side it makes sense to write it up.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Locking editor panes in Visual Studio Code prevents unwanted multi-tab experiences]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=6946</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/09/08/locking-editor-panes-in-visual-studio-code-helps-unwanted-multi-tab-experiences/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T19:19:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When using the Edge DevTools for VS Code extension inside the editor, one thing that I kept doing wrong was opening files accidentally next to the tools. By default, the tools show up as their own pane next to the main editor. This is an editor pane of VS Code, and thus supports many things, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saturn Hexagon]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2513/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2513/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/saturn_hexagon.png" title="Sorry, in SI units that's &quot;there's a big football in there.&quot;" alt="Sorry, in SI units that's &quot;there's a big football in there.&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My GDC 2021 Indie SoapBox Talk Transcript (five minutes about making desktop pets & virtual toys)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5108</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/my-gdc-2021-indie-soapbox-talk-transcript-five-minutes-about-making-desktop-pets-virtual-toys"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T22:33:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This last GDC I was invited to participate in the Indie Soapbox. It’s a wonderful set of talks that happens every GDC in which each speaker is given five minutes to talk about anything they want. I talked about desktop pets, desktop toys, and why that entire concept is such a valuable mode of expression. I actually plan on writing a much longer, and more in-depth post about this (it might end up being a longer talk too), as soon as I have time… It’s a topic that has really grown on me because I think it offers so much...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mailbag: Finding Inspiration in Non-Obvious Subject Matter]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42283</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/09/07/mailbag-finding-narrative-design-inspiration-in-non-obvious-subject-matter/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I used to publish questions that people have asked me either by email or on Twitter. That went on a hiatus for a while; to kick it off again, I asked Twitter folks what they’d be most interested in seeing me write about. Here was one of the questions: Where [do] you look for or … Continue reading "Mailbag: Finding Inspiration in Non-Obvious Subject Matter"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The No. 1 Ladies' Detective Agency [book]]]></title>
        <id>the-no-1-ladies-detective-agency</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/the-no-1-ladies-detective-agency"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The No. 1 Ladies' Detective Agency]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code runs on people]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/05/clever/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/05/clever/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-06T04:39:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wrote this a couple of years ago in another context, but it looks like 
it's still just as applicable today, so I decided to bring it out from 
behind the permission curtain.  This originally was only visible to 
coworkers who happened to look at my feed.  Now it isn't.


Code runs on people.  Please keep it simple.


You can throw all kinds of wicked, nasty, complicated, 
Klein-bottle-wannabe tricks into code and the computer will shrug and 
slog on through it.


Nobody will ever have more state about the code than the original author 
at the time of creation.  Everything after that pales in comparison.  If 
it takes an hour to figure out what's going on, well, that's an hour 
that wasn't spent doing something else more useful and interesting.


We get it, you're clever.  But the business doesn't need clever. It 
needs code that is only as complicated as absolutely necessary to get 
the job done.  Anything else is just wasted effort.


If a problem calls for clever, okay, then have at it.  But I bet it 
doesn't.  Most things really don't. Be honest with yourself, and with 
your future coworkers.  It makes for a healthier environment. 


I think this was originally written as an indirect response to some 
"clever-wielding" that had been witnessed on one of my tours of duty in 
some infrastructure team.  It's not clear that it had any positive 
effect, though.  These things are hard to measure after the fact, 
particularly once the "look how high I can pile up the clever" culture 
has infected a team thoroughly and it starts being rewarded.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revelation]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2512/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2512/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/revelation.png" title="And the heaven departed as a scroll when it is rolled together, but then more heaven kept appearing to replace it, as if the scroll was infinite." alt="And the heaven departed as a scroll when it is rolled together, but then more heaven kept appearing to replace it, as if the scroll was infinite." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home: Habitat, Range, Niche, Territory [book]]]></title>
        <id>home-habitat-range-niche-territory</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/home-habitat-range-niche-territory"/>
        <updated>2021-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Very brief but a good bridging story.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 04 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2575</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/04/hypervigilance/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T14:36:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Proctorio's awful reviews disappear down the memory hole: Ian Linkletter saved the receipts. This day in history: 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Proctorio's awful reviews disappear down the memory hole (permalink) Remember Proctorio? They're the "remote proctoring" company that boomed during the pandemic by promising that they could stop exam cheating through gross, discriminatory privacy invasions and snake-oil machine learning. In case you've lost the thread (it's been a minute), Proctorio is a tool that transforms students' personal computers into surveillance tools. For example, when you sit down, you have to use your webcam to give a remote party a tour of your room. If you live in crowded condit…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for August]]></title>
        <id>log.html#aug2021</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#aug2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of August. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Nasu, implemented a way to shift multiple tiles at once, and added a snarf buffer to copy/paste data between instances of Nasu.
Niju, completed, and released the project on itch.io.
Orca, implemented snarf buffer to easily bring patches in and out of it (uxn version).
Uxn, massive re-write of the Uxn VM, and CollapseOS now runs on Uxn.
Paradise, started on a Uxn-native version.
noodle, created a mascot, and added a tiny animation toolkit.
    
100r.co, added various hand drawn images to the knowledge base.
News
This month, our little engine was fixed (read about it here) we've been sailing around the Gulf Islands, working from anchor. We also found Iggy's successor, a used fiberglass dinghy that we've named Teapot. We've been rowing it from ship to shore, and it's so, so nice. We stopped by Saltspring Island and got to meet the sailors on BosunBird, a couple who have traveled around the world on a Vancouver27. Their blog was an invaluable resource for us on our travels through Japan. 
We've released a solid version of noodle, our drawing tool. Follow the tutorial on our website, or check out this amazing quick start guide by Polyducks. We also released niju, our little kana-learning game. Niju was a trial to see if we could design, write and assemble a project entirely within the Uxn computer.
Our friends at Compudanzas have released part 3, 4 and 5 of their Introduction to Uxn Programming tutorial.
Pino book club
Help. We still haven't finished The Swarm by Frank Schatzing. It is terrible, but we can't stop.
Pino's location: 48° 53.370'N, 123° 23.734'W
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doomscrolling, ads in texting, Theranos NOT Thanos, and more are the tweets on this week’s #TopShelf]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67233</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/best-tweets-sept-3-doomscrolling-theranos/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T21:14:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Mozilla, we believe part of making the internet we want is celebrating the best of the internet, and that can be as simple as sharing a tweet that made us pause in our feed. Twitter isn’t perfect, but there are individual tweets that come pretty close. Each week in Top Shelf, we will be […]
The post Doomscrolling, ads in texting, Theranos NOT Thanos, and more are the tweets on this week’s #TopShelf appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2571</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/03/kindgergarten-court/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T14:55:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Gun-maker demands Sandy Hook children's disciplinary records: Remington finds new depths of depravity to plumb. ALEC pushed voter suppression bills: And then lied about it. This day in history: 2006, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Gun-maker demands Sandy Hook children's disciplinary records (permalink) It's not clear to me whether running a company like Remington makes you into a fucking monster, or whether depraved assholes seek out companies like Remington to work for. In 2012, a gunman entered Sandy Hook Elementary School in Newton, CT, and murdered 20 children aged six and seven, and six staff members. Since 2014, the families of the dead have been suing gun-makers, a distributor, and a retailer f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recreate the Conditions]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2511/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2511/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/recreate_the_conditions.png" title="We've almost finished constructing the piña collider." alt="We've almost finished constructing the piña collider." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MIDI controller to PS/2 - part 1 [blog]]]></title>
        <id>midi-controller-to-ps2-part-1</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2021/09/02/midi-controller-to-ps2-part-1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little while back I saw a technical demo that used the shell of MIDI controller and inserted a PS/2 keyboard (effectively) under the keys to then control a program on the ZX Spectrum Next.
This prompted me to buy a MIDI controller but I didn't want to gut out the new hardware. So instead I found a way to map the USB MIDI to the PS/2 key presses, allowing me to use the piano keyboard on the retro hardware.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Followup on the dashboard story]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/01/dash/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/09/01/dash/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T22:31:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the weekend, I wrote a
post
about a big company project that dragged on for six months.  It elicited 
a bunch of responses in the usual places, but two or three of them were 
a little... off.  I figured I'd handle all of them at once right here.


I bet there was something that came up in the meeting where I said 
something like "you should be able to talk to our server right now but 
give it a try and let us know if you can't".  This meant that our RPC 
definitions were checked into source control like you'd expect, our 
service was already running in production (and NOT on someone's dev 
machine), and it had a well-defined service name.  This means anyone who 
knew how to talk the company's flavor of RPC could totally send it a 
request and get something back given just a little yak…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Sep 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2563</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/09/01/learned-helplessness/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T16:41:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Eviction is over (if we want it): The Big Bag of Money Method. This day in history: 2001, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Eviction is over (if we want it) (permalink) Now that the illegitimate, undemocratic Supremes have voided the CDC eviction ban, and now that the cowardly Dems who control House, Senate and Oval Office have declined to pass an eviction ban bill, millions of Americans teeter on the brink of homelessness. As we look at this looming crisis, which will increase the spread of covid, kill more Americans, and put a generations-long stamp of trauma on the people who lose their homes, we're asked to side with either renters or landlords. But that's a false dichotomy. Americans owe $12-14b to …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla VPN Completes Independent Security Audit by Cure53]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67228</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/mozilla-vpn-completes-independent-security-audit-by-cure53/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T16:10:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, Mozilla published an independent security audit of its Mozilla VPN, which provides encryption and device-level protection of your connection and information when you are on the Web, from Cure53, an unbiased cybersecurity firm based in Berlin with more than 15 years of running software testing and code auditing. Mozilla periodically works with third-party organizations […]
The post Mozilla VPN Completes Independent Security Audit by Cure53 appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modern Tools]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2510/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2510/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/modern_tools.png" title="I tried to train an AI to repair my Python environment but it kept giving up and deleting itself." alt="I tried to train an AI to repair my Python environment but it kept giving up and deleting itself." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Interactive Guide to Keyframe Animations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/keyframe-animations/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/keyframe-animations/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-31T21:41:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS keyframe animations are incredibly flexible and powerful, but they’re also a bit weird. In this deep-dive tutorial, we'll learn how CSS keyframes work from the ground up, and see how to use them to build high-quality animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 31 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2559</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/31/and-drown-it/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-31T17:14:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Inequality, not gerontocracy: Who killed interest rates? Monopoly power and political corruption: Starve the (corporate) beast, shrink it until it fits in a bathtub. This day in history: 2006, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Inequality, not gerontocracy (permalink) The received wisdom among economists is that the US's historical low interests rates are driven by high savings by aging boomers who are getting ready for, or in, retirement. The idea is boomers have salted away so much cash that banks don't bid for their savings, so interest rates fall. But at last week's Jackson Hole conference, a trio of economists presented a very different explanation for low interest, one that better fits the facts. In…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of August Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42010</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/08/31/end-of-august-link-assortment-5/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-31T10:28:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events The People’s Republic of IF, the Cambridge MA-based IF group, meets today, August 31, at 6:30 PM Eastern online. September 1 is the deadline to register as an author for IF Comp, and the games themselves will be due September 28. This year, unusually, there is a move so that authors participating in the … Continue reading "End of August Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A retrospective on the Electric Zine Maker, making tools, sharing the $ numbers, and more (after launching the really big update…)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5097</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/a-retrospective-on-the-electric-zine-maker-making-tools-sharing-the-numbers-and-more-after-launching-the-really-big-update"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T22:57:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over this weekend I finally launched the really big Electric Zine Maker update that I have been working on for the last few months. This is a notable update featuring a UI overhaul (it’s less intense now!), new templates, and a lot of fixes. I spent a lot of time making the UI friendlier. I couldn’t help myself so pop-up windows are cute pixel art. There’s animation to many elements, but I think it’s much more refined now. The main menu UI was always very “placeholder”, and many decisions in it had been for the sake of compromising for the...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generate an SEO-Friendly Sitemap for your Gatsby Site]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/gatsby/seo-friendly-sitemap/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/gatsby/seo-friendly-sitemap/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T20:41:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you maintain a blog, documentation, or any other sort of writing-based Gatsby site, you know how much work goes into content creation. Help users find your work by ensuring that it's properly indexed by Google!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 30 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2555</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/30/the-learning-app/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T16:52:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links India's 'toxic' ed-tech giant: How Byju's hard-sells desperate parents into taking out predatory loans for their kids' education. Podcasting "Utilities and Empires" and "FB's War on Switching Costs": A twofer from EFF's Deeplinks blog, on this week's podcast. This day in history: 2001, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading India's 'toxic' ed-tech giant (permalink) Byju's is a titan of the Indian ed-tech market, and its flagship program, The Learning App, has 40m users and 2.8m paid subscribers; its valuation is about to climb to $21b; it's been on a spending spree, buying up competitors in Asia and the USA. But as Akanksha Singh writes for Rest of World, the company's sales culture is rotten from…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monkey: the satirical Go package used unwittingly by Arduino and SalesForce]]></title>
        <id>https://esoteric.codes/blog/bouk-monkey-satirical-code-used-by-people-who-dont-get-the-joke</id>
        <link href="https://esoteric.codes/blog/bouk-monkey-satirical-code-used-by-people-who-dont-get-the-joke"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T10:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collisions between the personal and the commercial in open-source have become familiar, like when an irate independent developer pulled a widely-used package entirely in 2016 bringing down hundreds of projects. But we don't expect a commercial enterprise to suddenly discover a package they have long relied on forbids any use at all—and does so for a very good reason.

This was the realization for dapr, a “portable, serverless, event-driven runtime,” with 14k stars on GitHub, when an issue was opened last week about its dependency bouk/monkey. Monkey's license, in its entirety, reads:


I do not give anyone permissions to use this tool for any purpose. Don’t use it.

I’m not interested in changing this license. Please don’t ask.


It raises the question: do even corporate entities read the licenses of packages they use? While Dapr was called out, Arduino, SalesForce, and hundreds of other projects also reference Monkey.
Read More]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>esoteric.codes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Geometry Formulas]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2509/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2509/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/useful_geometry_formulas.png" title="Geometry textbooks always try to trick you by adding decorative stripes and dotted lines." alt="Geometry textbooks always try to trick you by adding decorative stripes and dotted lines." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Whole Truth (DI Adam Fawley, #5) [book]]]></title>
        <id>the-whole-truth-di-adam-fawley-5</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/the-whole-truth-di-adam-fawley-5"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unstoppable page turner.
I'm not known for reading books quickly - heck, the last book I read was 45 pages (or 80 pages, or 90 pages, or something low according to Kindle) and it took me a week to read.
This book is 400+ pages and I swallowed it in a matter of days. I cannot resist Hunter's writing style and it has me ending each chapter/section with "just one more…".
Great stuff. It also brings in some of the end of book 4 - All The Rage into a larger storyline.
The writing is certainly formulaic to some degree, but that's not particularly a bad thing and having familiarity with the characters, for me having read all the DI Adam Fawley series, means I can follow along at a much more interesting pace through the book.
I suspect this is classic "beach reading" if I were the type. I've enjoyed every one of Hunter's books I've read so far and I'll be pre-ordering the sixth installment: and easy choice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flowers for Eleven [blog]]]></title>
        <id>flowers-for-eleven</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2021/08/30/flowers-for-eleven"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I write this, it's the evening of the 30th of August. Previous years, indeed the last decade, this evening is terribly painful for me. This evening, 11 years ago Julie and I arrived at hospital, around this precise time, to find that during the late stages of labour, Tia's heartbeat had stopped.
Previous years, this evening specifically I try hard to hold the pain (and fear and anger) at arm's length.
This year has been different. As each year has always been different. No different bad or different good. Different… peaceful.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big company tale: six months for a list and a button]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/28/big/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/28/big/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-29T06:37:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the projects I did at a big company once upon a time was evolving 
organically, and we eventually realized we needed a "dashboard" of 
sorts.  That is, we wanted an internally-hosted page that would let 
anyone load it up and see what was going on with the service.  It was 
intended to be simple: ping our server, ask for the status, and then 
render the response into a simple list.  Later on, we knew we were going 
to want to add the ability to send a "panic" signal to our server from 
this page, so that anyone in the company could hit the "big red button" 
if things went haywire.


January 1: we put up a terrible hack: a shell script that runs a 
Python script that talks to the service to get the status and then 
dumps out raw HTML to a file in someone's public_html path.  


Janua…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2547</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/28/talking-hard-work-blues/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-28T18:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The "work ethic" is a dirty trick we play on ourselves: Rationalizing away the pointlessness and indignity of low-waged work. Facebook's war on switching costs: Network effects attract users, switching costs take them hostage. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2020. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The "work ethic" is a dirty trick we play on ourselves (permalink) In Nebraska – and elsewhere – the forced-labor camps that some prisoners are sent to have been rebranded. They're called "Work-Ethic Camps" now, and prisoners do 30-40h/week of hard labor for $1.21/day, interspersed with "intro to business" courses. As Jamiek McCallum writes in Aeon: "If there was a formula for obliterating the work ethic, giving pe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Circumappendiceal Somectomy]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2508/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2508/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/circumappendiceal_somectomy.png" title="Some personal news: After treating my first case a few years ago with antibiotics, I can report that I have now had appendicitis for the second and--unless something extremely unexpected happened with the surgery--final time." alt="Some personal news: After treating my first case a few years ago with antibiotics, I can report that I have now had appendicitis for the second and--unless something extremely unexpected happened with the surgery--final time." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 26 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2537</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/26/chained-to-the-mast/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T16:24:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Vaccinate workers at (almost) any price: Corporate America sabotaged paid vaccination leave. This day in history: 2001, 2011, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Vaccinate workers at (almost) any price (permalink) I admit it. I look at the overloaded hospitals, read the testimony of overworked health care workers, see the spiking case- and death-counts, and I find myself angry at people who won't get vaccinated. It's hard not to be angry, especially when you see people who reject the assurances about vaccine safety but conduct uncontrolled experiments on themselves using livestock medicine, based on conspiratorial social media threads. https://www.dailyposter.com/the-corporate-deterrent-to-more-vaccination…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design for Safety, An Excerpt]]></title>
        <id>https://alistapart.com/article/design-for-safety-excerpt/</id>
        <link href="https://alistapart.com/article/design-for-safety-excerpt/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T15:01:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Antiracist economist Kim Crayton says that “intention without strategy is chaos.” We’ve discussed how our biases, assumptions, and inattention toward marginalized and vulnerable groups lead to dangerous and unethical tech—but what, specifically, do we need to do to fix it? The intention to make our tech safer is not enough; we need a strategy.
This chapter will equip you with that plan of action. It covers how to integrate safety principles into your design work in order to create tech that’s safe, how to convince your stakeholders that this work is necessary, and how to respond to the critique that what we actually need is more diversity. (Spoiler: we do, but diversity alone is not the antidote to fixing unethical, unsafe tech.)
The process for inclusive safety
When you are designing for …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>by</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why are hyperlinks blue?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=66868</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/deep-dives/why-are-hyperlinks-blue/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The internet has ingrained itself into every aspect of our lives, but there’s one aspect of the digital world that I bet you take for granted. Did you ever notice that many links, specifically hyperlinks, are blue? When a co-worker casually asked me why links are blue, I was stumped. As a user experience designer […]
The post Why are hyperlinks blue? appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elise Blanchard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Call of the Wild [book]]]></title>
        <id>the-call-of-the-wild</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/the-call-of-the-wild"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Far more brutal than I expected.I'd known that Call of the Wild (and White Fang) were firm favourites of friends, and I knew they were books held in high regard - and I kind of assumed it was good for dog lovers.I had originally thought of reading this aloud to my daughter (absolutely a dog lover) but I'm glad I didn't.This story quickly gets to Buck being beaten, and beaten and then beaten some more. I guess the story is about finding strength when pushed to your limits, but I'm no English scholar so I could have totally missed the point!Buck is certainly heroic (or perhaps stoic) in the face of insurmountable hardship, and perhaps this is representative of the times that London lived in?What amazed me was, apparently, the Kindle version of the book is 45 pages - and it took me a week to read - either my page numbers are wrong or I stumbled through this book!!!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to enable text-to-speech in Pocket]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67138</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/videos/how-to-enable-text-to-speech-in-pocket/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-25T22:18:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Listen, you can have your articles in Pocket read out loud. This is perfect for those times when you’re doing chores around the house or driving during your commute, when your eyes and hands are busy. Step 1: Open your Pocket list in your mobile device and choose an article. Step 2: Tap the […]
The post How to enable text-to-speech in Pocket appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 25 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2531</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/25/taxes-are-for-the-little-stores/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-25T17:28:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Big Box stores' other shoe drops: Lowe's is a parasite that is killing its host. Belarusian dictator pwned by "cyber-partisans": When a secretive autocrat has no more secrets. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Big Box stores' other shoe drops (permalink) Since the start of this century, small and mid-sized towns have courted big box stores, using tax revenues to fund expensive road, sewer and electric expansions to lure large corporate chains to town. These companies promised jobs and tax revenues, and, technically speaking, they delivered both, but only if you do some very funny math. National chains pay little or no federal income tax, and often secure state tax a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stories Behind the Podcasts: Pocket’s New Partnership With Slate]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67150</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/pocket/pocket-slate-podcast-partnership-announcement/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-25T15:17:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pocket has long been the go-to place to discover, save, and spend time with the most thought-provoking and entertaining content from around the web. Now, Pocket – a Mozilla product – has teamed up with Slate’s world-class podcast hosts to provide deep dives into the episodes their listeners can’t stop thinking about. Through curated Pocket […]
The post Stories Behind the Podcasts: Pocket’s New Partnership With Slate appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[USV-C]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2507/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2507/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/usv_c.png" title="Ultra-Serial Violet C light is unpolarized, so you don't have to flip the polarizing filter over when you get the orientation wrong the first time." alt="Ultra-Serial Violet C light is unpolarized, so you don't have to flip the polarizing filter over when you get the orientation wrong the first time." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get started with Pocket]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=67127</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/videos/get-started-with-pocket/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-24T22:39:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Save what inspires you. Pocket is your save button for the internet. When a story catches your eye anywhere online, save it to Pocket and it’ll go straight to your list, ready for you to dig into when you’re free. Step 1: Create a Pocket account. Step 2: Install the Pocket app across your iOS […]
The post Get started with Pocket appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using console.log() on any website? Logpoints let you do that!]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=6938</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/08/24/using-console-log-on-any-website-logpoints-let-you-do-that/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-24T22:34:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you want to know the value of a certain expression in any JavaScript on the web, you can use logpoints for that. It is like injecting a console.log() anywhere you want. Here’s a quick demo: Here’s how the demo works: Open https://codepo8.github.io/dog-browser/ in the browser Open Developer Tools, go to the Sources tool Locate […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s what I learned from reading dozens of essays about the internet]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=66930</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/pocket/mozilla-cmo-lindsey-shepard-thoughts-pocket-college-essay-contest/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-24T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This past graduation season, Mozilla’s Pocket teamed up with Her Campus for The Future Connection, a writing contest for college students to reflect on what it’s like to come of age in a “hyper-online and always-connected world.” While this isn’t a new concept for them — this generation, including our essay contest winner, Esther Omole, were born […]
The post Here’s what I learned from reading dozens of essays about the internet appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 24 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2522</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/24/illegitimate-greatness/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-24T15:13:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Are privacy and antitrust on a collision course?: Harmful dominance, democratic privacy controls, interop and illegitimate greatness. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Are privacy and antitrust on a collision course? (permalink) In "The New Antitrust/Data Privacy Law Interface," Temple Law's Erika M Douglas presents a fascinating look at the tensions between privacy and competition. https://www.yalelawjournal.org/forum/the-new-antitrustdata-privacy-law-interface It's only fitting that Douglas published her paper in the Yale Law Journal, as that's the same journal that kickstarted the modern antitrust revolution when it published Lina Khan's "Amazon's Antitrust…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Human shielding and how things impact a person]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/23/shield/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/23/shield/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T19:52:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In reading some of the news today, I got to thinking about my own 
experiences at big companies, and then started wondering how much I had 
written about a certain topic.  I went looking through the now-decade of 
posts here, and somehow, I've never talked about "padding".  I mean, 
sure, the word itself comes up, but that's when talking about padding 
out meeting times, jamming a C-64 into a suitcase, or sticking spaces 
or zeroes in front of some number.


For me, it goes something like this: if things are generally okay in my 
life, then I start the day with some amount of padding.  If something 
happens, that impacts the padding.  If there's enough padding, it ends 
up being a mild inconvenience at worst.  For instance, this time last 
week when I had my
flat tire
at 75 mph, I was in a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 23 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2516</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/23/dont-wanna-spoil-the-surprise/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T16:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Disneyland at a stroll": Winding up my series on "amusement parks, crowd control, and load-balancing" (for now). The Unraveling: Ben Rosenbaum's stunning debut novel. What kind of emergency is our emergency?: Kim Stanley Robinson on the structure of feeling of this perilous moment. The secrets of hospital bills: What do you call a "market" where no one chooses the services or knows the prices? This day in history: None Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Disneyland at a stroll" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read parts four and five of my Medium series on "amusement parks, crowd control, and load-balancing" – "Expectations management" and "Disneyland at a stroll." https://craphou…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflection: Embracing My Undulating Image]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=66826</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/pocket/college-esssay-contest-winner-mozilla-pocket-hercampus/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T14:06:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This past May, Pocket and HerCampus teamed up to announce an essay contest asking college students to reflect on what it’s like to come of age in a hyper-online world for a $5,000 cash prize and the opportunity to be published and promoted on Pocket. There were over 800 entries, and we are excited to […]
The post Reflection: Embracing My Undulating Image appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick tip: creating round “talking heads” videos in Screenflow]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=6932</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/08/23/quick-tip-creating-round-talking-heads-videos-in-screenflow/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T08:56:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adding your face in a small circle to videos has become fashionable lately and some extensions do that automatically for you. Good old Screenflow, which I’ve used for years now, has no masking option though. But you still can achieve round videos using a setting and learning that screenflow’s sliders are weird. By default, Screenflow […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Projecting]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2506/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2506/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/projecting.png" title="This is something we all need to work on, but especially you all." alt="This is something we all need to work on, but especially you all." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seltani Jam]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42268</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/08/22/seltani-jam/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-22T20:15:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At a recentish Oxford/London IF Meetup, some participants expressed an interest in writing for, and playing with, Seltani. If you’re not familiar with it, Seltani is Andrew Plotkin’s multiplayer choice-based narrative platform. It lets players explore a shared environment, view each others’ actions, and change the world in ways that will affect others — in some … Continue reading "Seltani Jam"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 21 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2506</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/21/podcasting-as-a-visual-medium/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-21T16:21:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Bubble: Fantastic graphic novel adaptation of the brilliant comedy/sf podcast. This day in history: 2001, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Bubble (permalink) Bubble is a wildly improbable artifact – a graphic novel adaptation of a comedy/drama podcast that manages to turn podcasting into a visual medium. https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250245564 Written by Jordan Morris and Sarah Morgan with art by Tony Cliff and colors by Natalie Riess, this Firstcecond book manages to recapture the comedy, the snark, the trenchant commentary and the drama of the original Maximim Fun podcast series. https://maximumfun.org/podcasts/bubble/ Bubble is a comedy/sf story about a distant outpost on a hostile p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cybersecurity, Facebook data, OnlyFans update and more are on this week’s Top Shelf]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=66855</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/best-tweets-august-16-cybersecurity-facebook-data-onlyfans/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-20T22:22:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Mozilla, we believe part of making the internet we want is celebrating the best of the internet, and that can be as simple as sharing a tweet that made us pause in our feed. Twitter isn’t perfect, but there are individual tweets that come pretty close. Each week in Top Shelf, we will be […]
The post Cybersecurity, Facebook data, OnlyFans update and more are on this week’s Top Shelf appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your devices and your employer]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/20/phones/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/20/phones/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-20T21:16:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I 
wrote
the other day about how I went out and bought a second cell 
phone just because I wanted it to take the burden of all of the crap my 
new employer was about to throw at me.  I didn't get into the reasoning 
behind this, or some of my experiences, and figured it's probably worth 
some explanation.


This was far enough back in time to where we all still had desk 
phones, and assigned numbers that would ring in straight from the 
outside world, if you can believe it.  Mine never got any use, but it 
was definitely there for the first couple of years.


In those times, things were relatively simple.  The most mixing of work 
and personal stuff you could do was using your work laptop for other 
stuff.  I did this, and I know now that it was stupid, but I will now 
explain how it came …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it really is just a bad battery]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/19/batt/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/19/batt/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-20T02:17:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a secondary phone which doesn't get a whole lot of use.  I bought 
it a couple of years ago before starting a full time employee gig with 
the pink mustache factory.  I did this because my friends who were 
already there advised me that the company did not supply phones but did 
expect you to load a crapload of apps on to do your job.


It also meant that I could put it away at the end of the day and all 
work-related stuff would stay out of sight and out of mind until the 
next morning.


So, overall, I was surprised when it started being really belligerent 
about battery statuses.  I would find it at the end of the day somewhere 
down below 30% charge despite doing nothing but carrying it around in my 
purse all day.  Then, it would stay there at some low value for a very 
long ti…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[News Story Reaction]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2505/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2505/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/news_story_reaction.png" title="Unless the next line is, &quot;After we broke up, she blamed the painting and spent years planning her revenge, so my sorrow is mixed with relief that the dogs at least denied her that triumph.&quot;" alt="Unless the next line is, &quot;After we broke up, she blamed the painting and spent years planning her revenge, so my sorrow is mixed with relief that the dogs at least denied her that triumph.&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 19 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2499</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/19/failure-cascades/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-19T17:06:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Machine learning's crumbling foundations: Doing 'data science' with bad data. Hench: The madcap rage of life under vigilante rule. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Machine learning's crumbling foundations (permalink) Technological debt is insidious, a kind of socio-infrastructural subprime crisis that's unfolding around us in slow motion. Our digital infrastructure is built atop layers and layers and layers of code that's insecure due to a combination of bad practices and bad frameworks. Even people who write secure code import insecure libraries, or plug it into insecure authorization systems or databases. Like asbestos in the walls, this cruft has been fragmentin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patterns in confusing explanations]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/confusing-explanations/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/confusing-explanations/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-19T02:13:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Recently I’ve been thinking about why I explain things the way I do. The
usual way I write is:
Try to learn a topic
Read a bunch of explanations that I find confusing
Eventually understand the topic
Write an explanation that makes sense to me, to help others
So why do I find all these explanations so confusing? I decided to try and find
out! I came up with a list of 12 patterns that make explanations hard for me to
understand. For each pattern I’ll also explain what I like to do instead to
avoid the issue.
these patterns are very normal
This list isn’t meant to make you feel bad about your writing. I’ve probably
done all of these things! I’m certainly going to do them again! I even did at
least one of them while writing this post!
But knowing that I’m likely to accidently do these t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A big hole in a big road ate one of my tires]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/18/infra/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/18/infra/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T23:42:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A while back, I bought and installed a dash camera on my car.  I figured 
after initially seeing tons of crazy Russian insurance scams thwarted by 
it, and then a bunch of crazy videos from the rest of the world, it was 
my turn.  Then, over the weekend, it finally paid off by capturing video 
of something awful that happened to me.


My assumption is that the Phoenix-Vegas traffic makes things really 
crappy, hence the added enforcement and whatnot.  I figured, okay, I'll 
set the cruise control exactly at the 75 mph limit and just leave it 
there until I'm well past this area.  At least it's going to be 
well-maintained, well-lit, and all of that, right?  Safety corridor?
Surely that means they also maintain it better, since they enforce much 
more strenuously?


It was just a single sou…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 18 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2495</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/18/lets-make-a-deal/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T17:41:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Sacklers threaten us all with a good time: "Give us total impunity or we won't accede to the total impunity deal" is a hell of an ultimatum. This day in history: 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Sacklers threaten us all with a good time (permalink) The Sacklers are a multigenerational family of drug dealers, descended from the pioneer of the benzo epidemic, whose family drug business, Purdue Pharma, jumpstarted the opioid epidemic with its drug Oxycontin. The epidemic's US body count is past 800,000. The Sacklers are worth billions – the family's net worth exceeds that of other criminal dynasties like the Rockefellers. They are facing a blizzard of litigation thanks to their ac…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding in Indigenous African Languages]]></title>
        <id>https://esoteric.codes/blog/african-programming-languages</id>
        <link href="https://esoteric.codes/blog/african-programming-languages"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T09:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A phonebook.yl program in Yorlang

The language Yorlang began like many code projects, with a group of programmers contemplating a what-if.


One evening after work, i was scrolling through the messages in a group chat that i'm in and i read a message by someone talking about how cool it will be to have a programming language in yoruba that can process the command "sope 'hello world' ". So, i thought it was cool and i decided to create a very small language.


With that modest intention in mind, Karounwi Anoulowapo (based in Nigeria) created Yorlang, a JS-like language using keywords drawn from Yoruba. As colleagues requested more features, he kept expanding it until it became a full-fledged language. Other Yoruba-speaking programmers contributed, along with some non-speakers who were excited about a programming language created by and for West Africans.


One of the major contributors to the projects is a guy from the Igbo tribe. He documented the architecture of the code, contributed helper functions to the language, and also made small sample programs using yorlang.
Read More]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>esoteric.codes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fissile Raspberry Isotopes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2504/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2504/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/fissile_raspberry_isotopes.png" title="Grandma's shelf-stable blackberry pie meson recipe was a huge seller until her farm was shut down by a joint FDA/NRC investigation." alt="Grandma's shelf-stable blackberry pie meson recipe was a huge seller until her farm was shut down by a joint FDA/NRC investigation." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asking nicely for root command execution (and getting it)]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/17/pop/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/08/17/pop/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T21:27:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There was a SEV review meeting once upon a time, and in it, we had 
reviewed some incident where something bad happened involving something 
that ran as root.  I don't remember the finer points of that one any 
more, but the resident VP who ran the show wondered aloud how much 
"root exposure" we had in our infra in general.  That got my attention.


After the meeting ended without using the whole 90 minutes, the room was 
still reserved for another 15-20 minutes or so, and a couple of people 
hung out to look at the list.  One noticed that this one service 
running everywhere had these options for "pre" and "post" commands.  
This was a service which was normally used for performance measurement 
stuff and involved running an external command.  You'd say "okay, 
analyze this thing for me"…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Indiepocalypse x kuš! (The secret collaboration I was working on is out now!!)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5093</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/indiepocalypse-x-kus-the-secret-collaboration-i-was-working-on-is-out-now"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T20:26:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s a small but meaningful announcement! Download link >> https://pizzapranks.itch.io/indiepocalypse-x-kus Over the last few months I was secretly working on a collaboration project for the “Indiepocalypse x kuš” mashup. The project teamed up a group of random indie devs (provided by Indiepocalypse) with random comic artists (provided by kuš). The results are stellar! Even thecatamites worked on a game for it. I’m honored to be part of this! The person I was teamed up with is Gvidas Pakarklis, who is an amazing illustrator and artist. You can see more of his work on Instagram. His work is very symbolic and...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2489</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/17/king-bullet/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T16:02:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Sandman Slim's final adventure: King Bullet brings in Richard Kadrey's masterpiece for a hell of a landing. Big Oil caught lying about methane: 84 times worse than CO2. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Sandman Slim's final adventure (permalink) It's been more than a decade since Richard Kadrey blew the roof off supernatural horror with his hardboiled SANDMAN SLIM, the tale of an LA magician whose coven sends him to hell, who returns to wreak bloody revenge. https://memex.craphound.com/2009/07/24/kadreys-sandman-slim-a-hard-boiled-revenge-novel-from-hell/ As impressive as that breakout was, Kadrey has only gone from strength to strength, publishing ten more vo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Removing "shows" from Spotify [blog]]]></title>
        <id>removing-shows-from-spotify</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2021/08/17/removing-shows-from-spotify"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For some reason Spotify has increasingly been pushing shows and podcasts as a thing I might want to listen to. I don't. I'm happily paying for Spotify so I don't have to listen to ads, so instead I seem to get them in the podcast form.
I asked Spotify's support how to turn this off, and they said:

We're afraid that it's not currently possible to remove these recommendations. Rest assured, we'll let the right folks know this is something you'd like to see soon.

So yeah… I won't be holding my breath.
This to me, falls within the right to repair (which I really don't understand or agree with the push back) - so I fixed it myself.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 Aug 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2480</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/08/16/die-miete-ist-zu-hoch/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T17:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Housing, money laundry, speculation and precarity: Henry George was an optimist. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Housing, money laundry, speculation and precarity (permalink) Something amazing is happening in Berlin. Next month, Berliners will vote in a referendum to force Germany's largest publicly traded landlords to sell 240,000 homes to the state, whereupon those homes will become publicly owned housing. https://www.ft.com/content/4a5fb5ed-00cf-4a70-8653-820f0c1ff757 Berlin is a rarity: a semi-autonomous city whose history is overshadowed by a half-century of heavy public spending (in the west) as part of a program to prove that capitalism was a system o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>