<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html</id>
    <title>Ajour / Spitlo.com</title>
    <updated>2022-01-15T00:20:39.384Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.12.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://spitlo.github.io/ajour/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinthariscope]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2568/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2568/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/spinthariscope.png" title="Other high scorers are melt-in-your-hand aluminum-destroying gallium and tritium-powered glowsticks. Lawn darts are toward the other end." alt="Other high scorers are melt-in-your-hand aluminum-destroying gallium and tritium-powered glowsticks. Lawn darts are toward the other end." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turning a GitHub page into a Progressive Web App]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7077</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/01/13/turning-a-github-page-into-a-progressive-web-app/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-13T10:06:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just released my dice simulator app and in doing so learned about a few things about turning a GitHub Page into a PWA. To make this easier for subsequent projects, I put together a bare-bones template to turn any GitHub page into a PWA. Nothing in there is sophisticated and all it does is […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There oughta be GTA5 for the Game Boy.]]></title>
        <id>https://there.oughta.be/gta5-for-the-game-boy</id>
        <link href="https://there.oughta.be/gta5-for-the-game-boy"/>
        <updated>2022-01-12T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I presented my WiFi Game Boy cartridge a few weeks ago, I only had very few simple text-based demos. This post and especially the accompanying video now deliver more. In fact, I might have gone a bit too far, as I managed to stream full resolution video and even play games via WiFi. But see for yourself: Click the image to see the video on youtube.com. So, as usual, you have two alternatives to start here: Watch the video or read the article. If you are just curious and want to see what I did, definitely check out the video. If you want to understand exactly how it works and if you want to reproduce it or find tricks for your own projects, go for the article and the linked code. In any case, if you have not seen the previous article and/or video on the cartridge itself, you should start there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>there.oughta.be/</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Language Development]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2567/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2567/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/language_development.png" title="The worst is the Terrible Twos, when they're always throwing things and shrieking, &quot;forsooth, to bed thou shalt not take me, cur!&quot;" alt="The worst is the Terrible Twos, when they're always throwing things and shrieking, &quot;forsooth, to bed thou shalt not take me, cur!&quot;" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Offline? No dice!]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7071</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2022/01/11/offline-no-dice/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T21:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago I was on vacation in a place that had terrible mobile connectivity and whilst it provided WiFi, nothing worked. I even brought my own cables and travel router, but to no avail. This was not only a good opportunity for some “digital detox”, but it also showed me once again that […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revisiting why hyperlinks are blue]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68304</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/internet-culture/why-are-hyperlinks-blue-revisited/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T20:46:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why we need to revisit the origin of blue hyperlink While musing over my recently published article, Why are hyperlinks blue, I was left feeling a bit blue myself. Yes, it could have been the fact that I was evacuated and Hurricane Ida was destroying my home, I’ll admit. Besides that, I was also bothered […]
The post Revisiting why hyperlinks are blue appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elise Blanchard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Year, New Privacy Protection for Firefox Focus on Android]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68204</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/new-privacy-protection-for-firefox-focus-on-android/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T14:16:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever signed up for a contest to win a big screen TV or a vacation to an exotic location? Or have you joined a big retailer loyalty program so you can save money? If you answered yes to either of these questions you may be exchanging your name, home address, email address, phone […]
The post New Year, New Privacy Protection for Firefox Focus on Android appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make Beautiful Gradients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/make-beautiful-gradients/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/make-beautiful-gradients/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever noticed that gradients tend to look a little gray and washed-out in the middle? This happens because of a mathematical quirk with RGB colors. Fortunately, we can work around this quirk, and create beautiful, lush, saturated gradients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to find a domain's authoritative nameservers]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/11/how-to-find-a-domain-s-authoritative-nameserver/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/11/how-to-find-a-domain-s-authoritative-nameserver/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T08:30:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s a very quick “how to” post on how to find your domain’s authoritative
nameserver.
I’m writing this because if you made a DNS update and it didn’t work, there are 2 options:
Your authoritative nameserver doesn’t have the correct record
Your authoritative nameserver does have the correct record, but an old record is cached and you need to wait for the cache to expire
To be able to tell which one is happening (do you need to make a change, or do
you just need to wait?), you need to be able to find your domain’s
authoritative nameserver and query it to see what records it has.
But when I looked up “how to find a domain’s authoritative nameserver” to see
what advice was out there, I found a lot of different methods being mentioned,
some of which can give you the wrong answer.
So let’s wa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Checklist: How to Start 2022 Right]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68219</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/uncategorized/digital-checklist-how-to-start-2022-right/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-10T18:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For most, the New Year marks a time to reflect, reset and re-prioritize. While learning a new language, creating a budget or starting up a new hobby have become staples of our New Years’ Resolutions, as our lives increasingly shift online, it’s important we also use this opportunity to reassess our digital habits. Whether you […]
The post Digital Checklist: How to Start 2022 Right appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 10 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=3007</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/10/see-you-in-the-funny-papers/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-10T16:16:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Personnel are policy: The Dems may do something to materially improve voters' lives. Maybe. Podcasting "Science fiction is a Luddite Literature": My last pre-op podcast. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Personnel are policy (permalink) It's hard not to freak out, watching Biden get punked by Joe Manchin over Build Back Better. Manchin's transparent ruse – splitting the infrastructure bill from BBB – was obviously a prelude to a betrayal. Thanks to Dem leadership's foolish error, the party that holds the House, the Senate and the Oval Office will go into the mid-terms and the next presidential election having failed to deliver on the vast majority of their cam…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla partners with The Markup to launch Rally study into Facebook’s tracking and data collection practices]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68200</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/mozilla-themarkup-partner-rally-facebook-tracking-data-collection/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Browser maker Mozilla today announced a partnership with The Markup, the non-profit newsroom that investigates how technology is reshaping society, on a research project to provide insights into and data about a space that’s opaque to policymakers, researchers and users themselves. By joining Mozilla and The Markup’s “Facebook Pixel Hunt” in Firefox, people can help […]
The post Mozilla partners with The Markup to launch Rally study into Facebook’s tracking and data collection practices appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decorative Constants]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2566/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2566/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/decorative_constants.png" title="Arguably, the '1/2' in the drag equation is purely decorative, since drag coefficients are already unitless and could just as easily be half as big. Some derivations give more justification for the extra 1/2 than others, but one textbook just calls it 'a traditional tribute to Euler and Bernoulli.'" alt="Arguably, the '1/2' in the drag equation is purely decorative, since drag coefficients are already unitless and could just as easily be half as big. Some derivations give more justification for the extra 1/2 than others, but one textbook just calls it 'a traditional tribute to Euler and Bernoulli.'" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2998</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/07/the-klept/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-07T17:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Jackpot watch: How the klept operates in the UK. This day in history: 2007, 2012, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Jackpot watch (permalink) In his 2014 novel The Peripheral, William Gibson plunges us into a far-future London, radically depopulated, quietly authoritarian, and under the iron thumb of "the Klept" – a fusion of the British chumocracy with post-Soviet Eurasian kleptoracy. https://memex.craphound.com/2014/10/28/the-peripheral-william-gibson-vs-william-gibson/ The origins of this society – its depopulation, its neo-aristocracy, its captivity to inscrutable AIs called "the Aunties" are lost to history. They all took place during a time called "The Jackpot," an interregnum where huge swat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Latency]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2565/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2565/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/latency.png" title="Each SCAPDFATIAT point increases the chance that the process will involve the phrase 'by the next business day.'" alt="Each SCAPDFATIAT point increases the chance that the process will involve the phrase 'by the next business day.'" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2991</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/05/hillrom/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-05T16:21:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Hospital beds are a monopoly: The casket to hospital bed monopoly pipeline. This day in history: 2007, 2017, 2021 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Hospital beds are a monopoly (permalink) The great James Boyle tells an important parable about the coining of the term "ecology." Before the term came into wide use, the "ecology movement" as we know it was just a bunch of fragmented, seemingly disconnected issues. https://thepublicdomain.org/thepublicdomain1.pdf Like, if you're worried about owls and I'm worried about the ozone layer, it's not immediately apparent that we're fighting the same fight. It's not intuitive to link the fate of charismatic nocturnal avians to the gaseous composition of the upper atmosp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why might you run your own DNS server?]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/05/why-might-you-run-your-own-dns-server-/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2022/01/05/why-might-you-run-your-own-dns-server-/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-05T06:42:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the things that makes DNS difficult to understand is that it’s
decentralized. There are thousands (maybe hundreds of thousands? I don’t know!) of authoritative nameservers, and at least
10 million resolvers.
And they’re running lots of different software! All these different servers
running software means that there’s a lot of inconsistency in how DNS works,
which can cause all kinds of frustrating problems.
But instead of talking about the problems, I’m interested in figuring out –
why is it a good thing that DNS is decentralized?
why is it good that DNS is decentralized?
One reason is scalability – the decentralized design of DNS makes it
easier to scale and more resilient to failures. I find it really amazing that
DNS is still scaling well even though it’s almost 40 years old. Th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sunshield]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2564/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2564/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sunshield.png" title="RIP the surface of Mars" alt="RIP the surface of Mars" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On GameJolt’s new policy: why stigmatizing “sex” in games is harmful to the medium and never works…]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5236</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/on-gamejolts-new-policy-why-stigmatizing-sex-in-games-is-harmful-to-the-medium-and-never-works"/>
        <updated>2022-01-04T22:53:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday GameJolt emailed a lot of people saying that their game was removed because the site’s new policy bans any game that “depicts, solicits, promotes, normalizes, or glorifies sexual acts, sexual solicitation, and sexual violence“. I got an email too for F2OGGY (Only one survives!). This seemed like an obvious error to me because this game has 0 depiction of anything sexual. The game Curtain also received this notice… Source: https://twitter.com/ldreamfeel/status/1478065400286007304 Curtain is a brilliant and critically acclaimed work of art that interrogates abuse. It’s far from a porn game. “CURTAIN is an interactive first-person narrative about Kaci & Ally,...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 04 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2985</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/04/general-ludd/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-04T17:07:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Science fiction is a Luddite literature: My latest column for Locus Magazine. Neal Stephenson's 'Termination Shock': Geoengineering and the end of the world. Stellar images of quack exercise machines: A memento mori for anyone flexing in lycra on a Peleton. This day in history: 2002, 2007, 2012, 2017 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Science fiction is a Luddite literature (permalink) My latest column for Locus Magazine is "Science Fiction is a Luddite Literature," and it's my contribution to the burgeoning movement to rehabilitate the reputation of the Luddite uprisings, overturning the libel that Luddites were motivated by a fear of technology: https://locusmag.com/2022/01/cory-doctorow-science-fiction-is-a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 03 Jan 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2973</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2022/01/03/party-like-its-1926/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-03T16:28:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Happy Public Domain Day: The public domain continues to roar back after decades in a coma. 2021 Daddy-Daughter podcast: The latest in a lengthy series. This day in history: 2002, 2007 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Happy Public Domain Day (permalink) On January 1, 2019 something extraordinary happened. For the first time since 1998, the American public domain got bigger. What happened in 1998? Congress – led by Rep Sonny Bono – extended the copyright on all works by 20 years. Works that had already been in the public domain went back into copyright. Works that were in copyright got an extra 20 years. The public domain…froze. This was a wanton, destructive act. The vast majority of works that the Sonny Bono…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Throat and Nasal Passages]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2563/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2563/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/throat_and_nasal_passages.png" title="I always felt like what the 'you are now aware of your tongue' thing neeeded in order to be truly enjoyable was an element of mortal peril." alt="I always felt like what the 'you are now aware of your tongue' thing neeeded in order to be truly enjoyable was an element of mortal peril." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YYMMDDHHMM just overflowed a signed 32 bit int]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/01/baddate/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2022/01/01/baddate/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T19:36:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I guess I've turned into a collector of numbers that break things 
sometimes.  Here's another one I just heard about, and it's directly 
related to what just happened with the calendar.


The last value for last year is December 31, 2021 at 23:59, and in this 
format it becomes 2112312359.  That just fits into a signed 32 bit 
number (which tops out at 2147483647).


So, if you're using Microsoft Exchange and stopped getting your mail in 
the past couple of hours, this is why!

Really!  No joke!

Happy 2022, everyone.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Magical 3D Button]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/3d-button/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/animation/3d-button/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every action we take on the web starts with a button click, and yet most buttons are ho-hum and uninspired. In this tutorial, we'll build an animated 3D button with HTML and CSS that sparks joy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magical Rainbow Gradients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/rainbow-button/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/rainbow-button/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've ever tried to animate a gradient, you've been met with a harsh reality—it isn't possible. At least, it wasn't! In this tutorial, we'll leverage bleeding-edge browser features to animate ANY CSS property, including background gradients, using CSS Houdini, CSS variables, and React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Folding the DOM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/folding-the-dom/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/react/folding-the-dom/"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we'll explore a technique we can use to "fold" a DOM node, like folding a letter in real-life. On that journey, we'll learn a lot about 3D transforms and CSS animation techniques!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/the_future</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/the_future"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T02:01:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, it's 2022 and everything is turning out exactly as I predicted back when I was 7. Self-driving cars, space stations, the internet.  Nailed it.
Favorite TV show of 2021 was Only Murders in the Building.  
Favorite game of 2021 was Loop Heroes. 
Favorite book of 2021 was Einstein's Fridge.
Favorite rediscovered joy of 2021 was reading physical books.
Favorite movie of 2021 was Dune.
Favorite time waster of 2021 was watching physics videos on YouTube.
Least favorite movie of 2021 was anything with f**king superheroes.
Favorite pandemic of 2021 was Covid-19 (three years running).
See you in an exciting 2022 where everyone will be nice and respectful and personal agendas are put aside for the greater good and we all come together and save the planet. 
Either that or a horrific dystopian post-apocalyptic world where we hunt each other for food.
2022 could go either way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books I read in 2021 [blog]]]></title>
        <id>books-i-read-in-2021</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2022/01/01/books-i-read-in-2021"/>
        <updated>2022-01-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As my year in reading goes, I've certainly read less books, but I've not spent less time reading. It's just some books take me longer than others. For example, I read Call of the Wild, an 80(ish) page book in 4 weeks and then I read a 400 page book in 4 days… so it's really swings and roundabouts.
I recorded 21 books on my Kindle this year, but actually one of them was read aloud to the kids (Which I do still count) but another one was all of 19 pages… which, I think really doesn't count (it was Home: Habitat, Range, Niche, Territory by Martha Wells). So… 20 books then.
This post is mostly data driven (from my own web site's data) to give me a sense of the quality of the books I've read, otherwise individual reviews are all linked in this post or available on my books page.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of December Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42242</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/12/31/end-of-december-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events Running for a week starting January 1 on itch is the Historically Accurate Game Jam. This isn’t specifically an IF competition, and games of all types are welcome, as long as they’re written in a week and address the chosen time period or event of the jam. If you’ve had a craving to contribute … Continue reading "End of December Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021: Year in review]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/31/2021--year-in-review/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/31/2021--year-in-review/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T09:27:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s the end of the year again! This was my second full year working for myself
on wizard zines.
Here are some thoughts about what I’m working towards, a bunch of things I made
this year, and a few ideas and questions about 2022.
made some progress on a “mission statement”
I think the two hardest things about working for myself are working alone and
having to decide what to do.
This year I spent some time trying to figure out what I’m doing with wizard
zines. This is hard for me because I work in a pretty intuitive way – I have
some feelings about what’s important, and even though following my feelings
usually turns out well, I can’t always explain what I’m trying to do.
Here are some thoughts about what I’m trying to do:
I’m only interested in explaining “old” established technologies (HT…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My 2021 [blog]]]></title>
        <id>my-2021</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2021/12/31/my-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On a frequency of once every 365 days, based on the theme of my previous me-me-me posts and a general stamp I like to leave myself to remind Future Remy what the hell went on, here is my 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for December]]></title>
        <id>log.html#dec2021</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#dec2021"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of December. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Grimgrains, published a tofu from soy flour recipe, and reduced the amount of ingredients appearing on the main page so it loads faster.
Left, created inline image support, and implemented a search feature(Birdsite) inspired by the Canon Cat(1987)'s LEAP™ key.
Cat Clock, released our very own cat clock.
Turye, released a font editor.
TGA parser, released a tool to make it easier to bring images into the Uxn ecosystem.
Wunderland Rabbits, released a new image.
News
It is snowing, and we are cocooning. Our little woodstove is working hard. This month, we finally decided to release a paperback version of Busy Doing Nothing.
In our last update log, we mentioned that we were trying to grow Lion's Mane mushroom, and we are happy to report that it was a success! It grew beautifully. Rek was so excited about the mushroom that they decided to draw some this month, this series focuses on varieties that grow on Vancouver Island.
In other news, we had an interview with the founder of Sourcehut, read it here. Also, our good friend Alderwick make us a very cool gift(YouTube).
Pino book club
We're reading Fantômes: Issue 1, with work by 18 talented artists, put together by Lizbeth. It is a eerie, and gorgeous zine, we strongly recommend the Mike Wolf version.
Pino's location: 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Formatting Meeting]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2562/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2562/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/formatting_meeting.png" title="Neither group uses iso 8601 because the big-endian enthusiasts were all at the meeting 20 years ago." alt="Neither group uses iso 8601 because the big-endian enthusiasts were all at the meeting 20 years ago." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iron Widow (Iron Widow, #1) [book]]]></title>
        <id>iron-widow-iron-widow-1</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/iron-widow-iron-widow-1"/>
        <updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Iron Widow (Iron Widow, #1)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiny indiegames and the joy of Very Small Things]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5229</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/tiny-indiegames-and-the-joy-of-very-small-things"/>
        <updated>2021-12-30T01:53:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[~ This post is my epic roundup of recommendations for 202x! ~ When we talk about games, especially the indie game space, most of the games we suggest are ones with lots of critical acclaim, playtime, and that demand plenty of involvement. Playing a game these days feels like as much of a financial investment as it becomes a life investment. I find myself drawn more and more to spelunking itch.io for tiny hidden gems… getting lost while diving into all the developer pages filled with all these odd little works. Browsing itch or GameJolt has become almost as rewarding...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moonfall]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2561/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2561/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/moonfall.png" title="Novel ideas and cool explosions are both good, but what I really want from a movie is novel ideas ABOUT cool explosions." alt="Novel ideas and cool explosions are both good, but what I really want from a movie is novel ideas ABOUT cool explosions." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Psalm for the Wild-Built (Monk & Robot, #1) [book]]]></title>
        <id>a-psalm-for-the-wild-built-monk-and-robot-1</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/a-psalm-for-the-wild-built-monk-and-robot-1"/>
        <updated>2021-12-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lovely but I found the language almost too distracting.
Only right at the end of the book did I consider that maybe I really wasn't the right audience for the story - as it seemed to smack of "millennium type problems". Using air quotes in my description because I'm fairly sure this is a patronising statement I'm making!
The Dex character feels discontent with their achievements and is struggling to find fulfilling meaning. Their work has meaning to others but they're left feeling empty. Obviously it's an impossible measure as life trondles forward and achievements change with time.
For me it was only really when Dex meets the Robot (whose name I've already forgotten) when the book became more engaging. It was like the Dex character could be challenged and some real depth was offered (for better or worse for Dex's personality).
But what I did struggle with was the language and the odd shoehorning of gender pronouns. Dex is neither "he" or "she", so Chamber's settles with using the "they" pronoun. This led to my own confusion regularly thinking the lines I was reading was referring to Dex and another character that was in the scene.
The sore-thumb moment is when Dex asks, interestingly, what pronoun the Robot uses, and the Robot responds with "it" and it refers to itself as an object. Dex replies with (something like) they are the same, and their pronoun is "they". This seemed like a potentially interesting exchange between the Robot and Dex about the subject of how one refers to oneself and how they identify, but it doesn't happen. It just has that exchange, and then the story returns to what they were doing and carries on. It felt jarring and like Chamber's wanted to discuss this topic, but instead shoe horned it in.
I do also suspect that my trouble with the language is a me-thing and probably with practice it won't cause me as much (or any) confusion, but for now, and this book, it definitely affected how I enjoyed the story.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lego Report 8]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/lego8</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/lego8"/>
        <updated>2021-12-27T18:54:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That didn't take long to fix and rebuild. I don't know what is taking the city of Rome so long.

Start to finish, it took just over a year. I blame Limited Run Games.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lego Report 7]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/lego7</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/lego7"/>
        <updated>2021-12-27T02:09:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Placing the last piece.

And then disaster stuck while moving it.

Most of the debris is still assembled large chucks, so it shouldn't take long to fix.  I'm sure this happened to the real coliseum.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confounding Variables]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2560/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2560/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/confounding_variables.png" title="You can find a perfect correlation if you just control for the residual." alt="You can find a perfect correlation if you just control for the residual." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fix the unit test and open a giant hole everywhere]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/12/24/mkdir/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/12/24/mkdir/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-25T19:49:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Several years back, I was doing my thing in a corporate environment, 
working on a project with some friends.  By virtue of being in a very 
large company, we had quite the assortment of libraries which could be 
brought in to do stuff.  Given that we had a "would be nice" item on our 
feature list that involved doing something with the filesystem, I went 
looking for a matching feature, and it turned into a security dumpster 
fire.  Here's what happened.


When you're in that situation, you can't just mkdir() the final path.  
It won't work.  You have to start from the top and work your way down.  
The ones which already exist will probably fail with -EEXIST, so 
sometimes it makes more sense to look at what's there, work your way 
down, and then start the mkdir calls when you find that p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Twelve Days of Crunch Time Again]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/12_days_of_crunch_time_yet_again</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/12_days_of_crunch_time_yet_again"/>
        <updated>2021-12-25T17:56:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Holiday repost!
Clayton and I did this back in Dec of 2004.  Interesting how much hasn't changed. I'd have more "male" spouses now, something about loot crates and IAP, kissing up to steamers, and maybe change the last verse to be more "indie", but its shockingly accurate years later.
The Twelve Days of Crunch Time
A poem by Gilbert and Kauzlaric
On the twelfth day of crunch time,
My project gave to me...

Twelve cents in royalties,

Eleven kiss-ass previews,

Ten nerdy testers,

Nine patent lawsuits,

Eight unplanned for features,

Seven frames a second,

Six angry spouses,

Five focus groups!

Four unstable hacks,

Three days without sleep,

Two surly artists,

and a crappy publishing deal.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[December 25th Launch]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2559/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2559/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/december_25th_launch.png" title="Update: Santa has been destroyed by the range safety officer." alt="Update: Santa has been destroyed by the range safety officer." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hercule Poirot's Christmas [book]]]></title>
        <id>hercule-poirots-christmas</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/hercule-poirots-christmas"/>
        <updated>2021-12-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I totally failed to guess the killer!
Poirot was staple TV viewing when I was a teenage so the image of the character is burned well into my consciousness (thank you David Suchet) - so reading an Agatha Christie book tends to come with very easy imagination and even accents for characters.
The story is well built, told in a way that makes me think I should have been able to deduce the killer myself (and something I've always wondered about murder mystery stories) and does a good job of flipping my expectations on its head!
Solid stuff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lego Report 6]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/lego6</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/lego6"/>
        <updated>2021-12-22T22:03:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We should be done in time for the upcoming gladiator '22 season.  Tickets are still available. I hear Ferocianus Maximus is going to do well this year.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rapid Test Results]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2558/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2558/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/rapid_test_results.png" title="A solid red area with two white lines means that you have been infected with the anti-coronavirus, COVID+19, which will cure anyone you have close contact with." alt="A solid red area with two white lines means that you have been infected with the anti-coronavirus, COVID+19, which will cure anyone you have close contact with." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Dead Redemption 2 as a commentary on The Game Industry (my love–hate relationship with it)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/?p=5209</id>
        <link href="http://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/red-dead-redemption-2-as-a-commentary-on-the-game-industry-my-love-hate-relationship-with-it"/>
        <updated>2021-12-21T03:59:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been wanting to do another post talking about indie games, analyzing game design, and showcasing good examples from the indie space but… I’m struggling a lot with being afraid of unintentionally platforming an abuser. I know saying that out loud sounds irrational, maybe. It’s been hard finding love for a space that I feel like happily decided people like me are a justifiable loss if it means making snarky Twitter Takes about what they’re going through… or just benefiting from indifference. I don’t know anymore… I don’t want to rant. I want to talk about game design. It’s hard...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>alienmelon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The web starts on page four]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7063</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/12/20/the-web-starts-on-page-four/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-20T18:06:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After 25 years of working for, on and with the web, I am looking at the current state of it and I don’t like it. There is still a lot of beautiful, creative and amazing work out there, but on the whole, we lost an amazing opportunity. In its place we have a consumption machine […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Immunity]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2557/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2557/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/immunity.png" title="This plan may sound appealing to people who know a little about the immune system, but the drawbacks are clear to people who know a lot about the immune system and also to people who don't know anything about it." alt="This plan may sound appealing to people who know a little about the immune system, but the drawbacks are clear to people who know a lot about the immune system and also to people who don't know anything about it." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Log libraries and the tendency to open holes in things]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/12/18/log/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/12/18/log/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-19T01:05:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Logging stuff is in the news this week.  Specifically, people with Java 
and log4j somewhere in their lives are having a miserable time.  I 
figured I'd re-tell a story about terrible things done by way of a bunch 
of feature-rich libraries and dubious interconnections.  I've mentioned 
this in passing before, but this time I've tried to be much more 
specific about how it works.


Part 1: the flags.



DEFINE_bool(enable_foo, false, "Enable the foo feature");
 
...
 
void my_func() {
  if (FLAGS_enable_foo) {
    do_something();
  }
}




DECLARE_bool(enable_foo);
 
...
 
void other_func() {
  // Turns out we need foo enabled to do our stuff.
  FLAGS_enable_foo = true;
  // ...
}




int main(int argc, char** argv) {
  InitCompany(argc, argv);  // populates FLAGS_ of all kinds
  // ...
}
…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turing Complete]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2556/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2556/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/turing_complete.png" title="Thanks to the ForcedEntry exploit, your company's entire tech stack can now be hosted out of a PDF you texted to someone." alt="Thanks to the ForcedEntry exploit, your company's entire tech stack can now be hosted out of a PDF you texted to someone." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pocket & Texas Monthly Take You Inside The World of the Dallas Cowboys Cheerleaders With New Partnership]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68166</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/pocket/pocket-texas-monthly-take-you-inside-the-world-of-the-dallas-cowboys-cheerleaders-with-new-partnership/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-16T23:15:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your favorite go-to resource to discover, save, and spend time with interesting reads, has gone to Texas. This December, Pocket has teamed up with Texas Monthly, bringing Pocket users weekly deep dives on every episode of America’s Girls, Texas Monthly’s fascinating new podcast about how the Dallas Cowboys Cheerleaders became international icons.  From the scandals […]
The post Pocket & Texas Monthly Take You Inside The World of the Dallas Cowboys Cheerleaders With New Partnership appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Vasquez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There oughta be a WiFi Game Boy cartridge.]]></title>
        <id>https://there.oughta.be/a/wifi-game-boy-cartridge</id>
        <link href="https://there.oughta.be/a/wifi-game-boy-cartridge"/>
        <updated>2021-12-15T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It took a while, but I finally managed to create my own Game Boy cartridge. With WiFi! At this point, it can only demo a simple telnet-style communication and access Wikipedia articles, but I am confident that I will showcase more in the future. For now, the interesting and surprisingly tricky part is how the thing works at all. Click the image to see the video on youtube.com. If you just want to see the cartridge in action or want to get into all the details, I highly recommend to watch the video first as it goes through the difficulties and their respective solutions. In contrast, this article here is less visual in its explanations and mostly documents the device in detail, so unless you are already familiar with the parallel memory interface of the Game Boy, you might want to start with the overview from the video.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>there.oughta.be/</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid-December Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42239</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/12/15/mid-december-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-15T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events January 1 is currently scheduled as the next meetup of the SF Bay Interactive Fiction Meetup, but given that that is New Year’s Day, it’s possible that that will change. Running for a week starting January 1 on itch is the Historically Accurate Game Jam. This isn’t specifically an IF competition, and games of … Continue reading "Mid-December Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New tool: Mess with DNS!]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/15/mess-with-dns/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/15/mess-with-dns/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-15T09:41:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I’ve been thinking about how to explain DNS a bunch in the last year.
I like to learn in a very hands-on way. And so when I write a zine, I often
close the zine by saying something like “… and the best way to learn more
about this is to play around and experiment!“.
So I built a site where you can do experiments with DNS called Mess With DNS. It has examples of experiments you can try, and
you’ve very encouraged to come up with your own experiments.
In this post I’ll talk about why I made this, how it works, and give you
probably more details than you want to know about how I built it (design, testing,
security, writing an authoritative nameserver, live streaming updates, etc)
a screencast
Here’s a GIF screencast of what it looks like to use it:

it’s a real DNS server
First: Mess W…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notifications]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2555/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2555/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/notifications.png" title="It's 10:34 PM for this user. They really need to get going, they have a thing early tomorrow. Are you sure you want to notify?" alt="It's 10:34 PM for this user. They really need to get going, they have a thing early tomorrow. Are you sure you want to notify?" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I (re)learnt to read [blog]]]></title>
        <id>how-i-relearnt-to-read</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2021/12/14/how-i-relearnt-to-read"/>
        <updated>2021-12-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During the month of November this year, I read Wise Man's Fear - the longest book I've ever read, in my life at 1,000 pages.
Younger Remy would have never believed that I could read a book this length. It was simple something that was impossible. For me, my Kindle changed reading for me and opened the door to the world of literature.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gift Exchange]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2554/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2554/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/gift_exchange.png" title="In addition to having all their budgets in a spreadsheet with consistent formatting, they just love expressing preferences on a well-calibrated numerical scale." alt="In addition to having all their budgets in a spreadsheet with consistent formatting, they just love expressing preferences on a well-calibrated numerical scale." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lego Report 5]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/lego5</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/lego5"/>
        <updated>2021-12-12T21:35:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After 7000 signatures, some progress.  I am getting help.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Away with the Penguins [book]]]></title>
        <id>away-with-the-penguins</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/away-with-the-penguins"/>
        <updated>2021-12-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Took a while to warm to the characters, but worth it in the end.The story follows an exceptionally grumpy old lady, very much a stereotypical old person who doesn't trust anyone and exists almost just for themselves.We also meet her grandson who is equally useless in his own ways. These two characters together made it rather difficult to want to keep reading their story, but I'm glad I did persevere.Although the story is a little cliche, around four fifths the way through the book, it does a pretty good job to win me over to the main characters and I want to see them happy by the end of the story.Probably a little bit too long, but worth it for the payoff at the end.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Incident Report]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2553/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2553/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/incident_report.png" title="Increasing-precision timestamps are the Jaws theme of incident reports." alt="Increasing-precision timestamps are the Jaws theme of incident reports." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My best holiday shopping tip? Mozilla]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68152</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/my-best-holiday-shopping-tip-mozilla/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-09T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Mozilla can’t make your impossible-to-shop-for dad any easier to shop for, we can help make the process of holiday shopping more enjoyable. 
The post My best holiday shopping tip? Mozilla appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 09 Dec 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2969</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/12/09/practical-visionary/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-09T21:15:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Electrify: Saul Griffith's visionary, practical program for a US clean energy transition. This day in history: 2011, 2016 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Electrify (permalink) In Electrify, the MacArthur prizewinning engineer Saul Griffith offers a detailed, optimistic and urgent roadmap for a climate-respecting energy transition that we can actually accomplish in 10-15 years. There are a lot of popular science books out there, but the world really needs more popular engineering books – books that set out the technical parameters of our problems and the various proposed solutions, sorting the likely from the plausible to the foolish, and laying out a practical range of plans to accomplish the best of them. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking Out of the Box]]></title>
        <id>https://alistapart.com/article/breaking-out-of-the-box/</id>
        <link href="https://alistapart.com/article/breaking-out-of-the-box/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-09T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS is about styling boxes. In fact, the whole web is made of boxes, from the browser viewport to elements on a page. But every once in a while a new feature comes along that makes us rethink our design approach.
Round displays, for example, make it fun to play with circular clip areas. Mobile screen notches and virtual keyboards offer challenges to best organize content that stays clear of them. And dual screen or foldable devices make us rethink how to best use available space in a number of different device postures.
Sketches of a round display, a common rectangular mobile display, and a device with a foldable display.



These recent evolutions of the web platform made it both more challenging and more interesting to design products. They’re great opportunities for us to break out of o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>by</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Year in Review: How we’re curating the web with you and our top Pocket features]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68141</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/year-in-review-how-were-curating-the-web-with-you-and-our-top-pocket-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-09T14:06:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All this year, we’ve been experimenting with features to help you discover articles and voices that are relevant to your interests, and better organize your lists so you can easily find the stories that fit your mood or your time available. We saw lots of users engaging with positive and meaningful content, which demonstrated to […]
The post Year in Review: How we’re curating the web with you and our top Pocket features appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenifer Boscacci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kristen Trubey, Mozilla’s New Chief People Officer]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68139</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/leadership/kristen-trubey-mozillas-new-chief-people-officer/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-09T00:38:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am pleased to share that Kristen Trubey has joined Mozilla as our Chief People Officer. Kristen initially came to Mozilla in August in an interim capacity but she quickly settled in and made an immediate impact. Her expertise, experience and focus to create connections between company culture, employee experience, and business results proved to […]
The post Kristen Trubey, Mozilla’s New Chief People Officer appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mitchell Baker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 08 Dec 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2962</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/12/08/required-ish-reading/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-08T16:15:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links All the books I reviewed in 2021: Plus one I published! Broken Promises: The Writers Guild of America West makes the case for media un-consolidation. How elite hobbies let billionaires pay no tax: More from Propublica's IRS Leaks. This day in history: 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading All the books I reviewed in 2021 (permalink) This is more-or-less my last blogging day of 2021 (I may sneak a post or two in before the New Year, but I might not), so it's time for my annual roundup of my book reviews from the year gone by. I've sorted this year's books by genre (sf/f, other novels, graphic novels, YA, nonfic) and summarized the reviews with links to the full review. Here's last year's installme…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Last Molecule]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2552/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2552/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/the_last_molecule.png" title="Biology is really struggling; they're barely at 93% and they keep finding more ants." alt="Biology is really struggling; they're barely at 93% and they keep finding more ants." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 07 Dec 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2955</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/12/07/solar-panel-for-a-sex-machine/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-07T16:37:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Podcasting "Give Me Slack": On the parenting challenges of an era without second chances. A lexicon of euphemisms for "corporate crime": Compliance, risk, white collar crime… IP lawyers weaponize trade secrecy to stall vaccine waivers: But Karan Menon has their number. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Podcasting "Give Me Slack" (permalink) This week on my podcast, I read "Give Me Slack," my latest column for Medium, about the second (and third, and fourth) chances I got growing up, and how scary it is that my kid – and yours – won't get those chances. https://doctorow.medium.com/give-me-slack-b4e88a007dbf From the fourth through the eighth grade, I attended a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DNS doesn't "propagate"]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/06/dns-doesn-t-propagate/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/06/dns-doesn-t-propagate/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-06T09:44:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Yesterday I tweeted this:

I feel like the term "DNS propagation" is misleading, like you're not actually waiting for DNS records to "propagate", you're waiting for cached records to expire
— 🔎Julia Evans🔍 (@b0rk) December 5, 2021
 
and I want to talk about it a little more. This came up because I was showing a
friend a demo of how DNS caching works last week, and he realized that what was
happening in the demo didn’t line up with his mental model of how DNS worked.
He immediately brought this up and adjusted his mental model (“oh, DNS records are
pulled, not pushed!“). But this it got me thinking – why did my very
smart and experienced friend have an inaccurate mental model for how DNS works
in the first place?
First – I’m very tired of posts that complain about how people are “w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debunking]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2551/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2551/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/debunking.png" title="Mark Zuckerberg has only neutral feelings toward Peppa Pig, who he understands is a fictional character, and he blames the coronavirus pandemic on other factors." alt="Mark Zuckerberg has only neutral feelings toward Peppa Pig, who he understands is a fictional character, and he blames the coronavirus pandemic on other factors." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 05 Dec 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2947</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/12/05/universalism/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-05T16:31:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links When you hear "one size fits all," think "universal": The origins and expansion of a right-wing shibboleth. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading When you hear "one size fits all," think "universal" (permalink) Once, the phrase "one size fits all" was a futuristic boast offered by manufacturers availing themselves of new, high-tech materials that stretched and flexed without tearing or deforming. Today, it's a curse-word used to damn universal programs. What happened? As is so often the case with big linguistic shifts, the culprit is capitalist realism, the ideology that there is no alternative to unfettered profit-seeking, which relies heavily on linguistic games…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use dig]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/04/how-to-use-dig/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/12/04/how-to-use-dig/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-04T08:44:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! I talked to a couple of friends recently who mentioned they wished they knew
how to use dig to make DNS queries, so here’s a quick blog post about it.
When I first started using dig I found it a bit intimidating – there are so
many options! I’m going to leave out most of dig’s options in this post and just
talk about the ones I actually use.
Also I learned recently that you can set up a .digrc configuration file to make its output
easier to read and it makes it SO MUCH nicer to use.
I also drew a zine page about dig a few years ago, but I wanted to write this post to include a bit more information.
2 types of dig arguments: query and formatting
There are 2 main types of arguments you can pass to dig:
arguments that tell dig what DNS query to make
arguments that tell dig how to forma…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My list of magic numbers for your turkey day enjoyment]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2020/11/26/magic/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2020/11/26/magic/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-03T06:19:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, world!  A couple of days ago, I noticed someone remarking on a 
line from an older post of mine that had been making the rounds.  In it, 
I say something about adding a number to "my list of magic numbers".  
That person wanted to see that list.


And so, I have put together this list of everything I can think of at 
the moment, along with a whole bunch of commentary that should be able 
to send you on dozens of romps through Wikipedia.  Hopefully this will 
both satisfy the request for "the list" and provide a lot of amusement 
on a day which normally is lacking in content.


Be safe out there, and enjoy.


"HTTP" is 0x48545450 (1213486160) or 0x50545448 (1347703880).  If it 
shows up in your error logs, you're probably calling out to a poor web 
server instead of someone who actua…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One way a builder culture can fail]]></title>
        <id>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/12/02/build/</id>
        <link href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2021/12/02/build/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-03T03:33:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've told some stories about what happens when you end up at a company 
that builds nothing and instead rents everything from some vendor.  
Given that, it's only fair that I describe something bad that can 
happen at a company which is known for building stuff.


The trouble is that sometimes these companies will hire someone who's 
known for doing X... and *only* X.  They're a builder, all right, as 
long as you want them to build X.  Perhaps they have been building X at 
some other company, and now your company has hired them to come and do 
that same job over here instead.


There's also the possibility that the prestige of having this person 
working at the company is what they're actually cultivating, and 
management wants to make this person happy by letting them work on their 
pet project, even if the pet project itself is not doing anything 
positive.

actually belongs in 
production.  In one outcome, it's brilliantly executed and things grow.  
But, this is about the downsides, and in that scenario, it's a stinking 
pile of garbage and needs to be thrown out, but it gets forced in, 
anyway.


If this project is being pushed for political reasons, then it should 
not come as a surprise that when it finally does ship to production,
it causes outages and generally fails to deliver on its promises.  It's 
actually worse than just leaving things the way they had been before any 
of this stuff showed up.


Just imagine what companies would look like if their hiring processes 
filtered out this kind of charlatan instead of looking for whether they 
could do some dumb coding card trick in a 45 minute interview block.
I think they'd look very different, and a whole bunch of people would 
have to find another industry to prey upon.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Writing - rachelbythebay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Webb]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2550/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2550/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/webb.png" title="Each one contains a chocolate shaped like a famous spacecraft and, for the later numbers, a pamphlet on managing anxiety." alt="Each one contains a chocolate shaped like a famous spacecraft and, for the later numbers, a pamphlet on managing anxiety." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Printed Website: Volume III & The Comments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2021/12/printed-website-third-volume.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2021/12/printed-website-third-volume.html"/>
        <updated>2021-12-02T22:17:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Low-tech Magazine Volume III The newest Low-tech Magazine book collects 18 articles published between 2018 and 2021. At 368 pages it’s a thin book compared to earlier volumes. When we started the book series, the challenge was to unlock an archive of almost 12 years. It made sense to pack this content into as few volumes as possible. However, looking ahead, we will publish more often, once every one to three years, depending on the number of articles written. From now on, the articles will be arranged chronologically, from oldest to newest, and no longer the other way around. This volume contains 184 images in black and white. Low-tech Magazine: The Comments We also launched a book which collects almost...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>LOW-TECH MAGAZINE</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 02 Dec 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2937</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/12/02/empirical-facewash/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-02T17:15:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Massive Predpol leak confirms that it drives racist policing: As with McKinsey consultants, buying Predpol is a way to buy outside validation for the indefensible. This day in history: 2001, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Massive Predpol leak confirms that it drives racist policing (permalink) When you or I seek out evidence to back up our existing beliefs and ignore the evidence that shows we're wrong, it's called "confirmation bias." It's a well-understood phenomenon that none of us are immune to, and thoughtful people put a lot of effort into countering it in themselves. But confirmation bias isn't always an unconscious process. Consultancies like McKinsey have grown to multibillion-dollar ti…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 01 Dec 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2932</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/12/01/satyajit-das/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-01T18:42:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Fintech is a scam, a listicle in eight parts: $91.5b/year, doubling every year. Teaching thread management with puzzle games: Rocky's Boots, 2021 edition. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020. Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Fintech is a scam, a listicle in eight parts (permalink) The world's economy ground to a halt during the pandemic as millions died, production slowed or stopped altogether, and the resulting supply chain disruptions made many essential products and services impossible to deliver. And yet, the world's billionaires added $5.5b to their net worth during that time. https://ips-dc.org/global-billionaires-see-5-5-trillion-pandemic-wealth-surge/ Thank "financialization," the subor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pocket’s state-by-state guide to the most popular articles in 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68030</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/pocket/pocket-top-stories-by-state-best-of-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-01T14:43:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While we can’t predict what the history books will say about 2021, we can analyze what defined this year for us. We do just that in Pocket’s Best of 2021 — the most-saved, -read and -shared articles by Pocket readers, spanning culture, science, tech and more. 
The post Pocket’s state-by-state guide to the most popular articles in 2021 appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating Pocket’s Best of 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68032</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/pocket/pocket-best-of-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-01T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We aren’t the only ones putting out Top 10 content lists or Year in Reviews, but we’d argue these lists are different from the rest — a cut above. Pocket readers are a discerning bunch: they gravitate to fascinating long reads that deeply immerse readers in a story or subject; explainers that demystify complex or […]
The post Celebrating Pocket’s Best of 2021 appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of changes for November]]></title>
        <id>log.html#nov2021</id>
        <link href="https://100r.co/site/log.html#nov2021"/>
        <updated>2021-12-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of November. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.
Summary Of Changes
Donsol, designed a donsol turnip.
Uxn, wrote a file browser rom(Mastodon), improved on uxn utilities (clock, calculator(both YouTube)).
Nasu, added nametable to preview items on the spritesheet, and added option to flip a sprite horizontally or vertically in the blend view.
100r, added an information section on {drownspire}, the studio we had prior to hundredrabbits.
Oquonie, started tests to port the game to Uxntal(Birdsite).
Left, fixed bugs and improved speed.
News
This month, there was an intro to Uxn Programming(YouTube) workshop by Compudanzas, an event by Babycastles Academy. Give it a watch!
November was a very rainy month in Victoria, a perfect time for experiments in the galley. We are growing Lion's Mane mushrooms currently (a first for us), and we are continuing to lacto-ferment vegetables like kohlrabi, turnips, daikon, cauliflower and red onion. To learn how to do it, see our guide to lactofermentation.
Pino book club
We're reading The Summer Book by Tove Jansson (it's such a lovely book).
Pino's location: 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W
Continue Reading]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rekka Bellum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edge Cake]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2549/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2549/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/edge_cake.png" title="Every time IERS adds or removes a leap second, they send me a birthday cake out of superstition." alt="Every time IERS adds or removes a leap second, they send me a birthday cake out of superstition." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of November Link Assortment]]></title>
        <id>http://emshort.blog/?p=42237</id>
        <link href="https://emshort.blog/2021/11/30/end-of-november-link-assortment-6/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-30T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events December 4 is the next meetup of the San Francisco Bay Area IF Group. December 12 is the next meetup of the Seattle/Tacoma IF Group, meeting online via Discord. The Ectocomp competition for spooky and Halloween-y games is now over, but the entries can still be played. Or, if you’re looking for something to … Continue reading "End of November Link Assortment"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Short</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 29 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2923</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/29/ordinance-of-labourers/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-29T16:43:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The once and future mass-resignation and what it means for working people: On David Dayen's "The Great Escape." This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The once and future mass-resignation and what it means for working people (permalink) Once upon a time, a terrible disease swept the lands, prompting a great wave of resignations as low-waged workers walked off the job, rejecting offers of pay raises that would have been unthinkably lavish just a few years earlier. Their bosses went nuts. The former employers of these workers slammed them as lazy and greedy, and called upon their fellow bougies to take up "unskilled" labor and scab those proles back into the workplace. Whe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awful People]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2548/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2548/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/awful_people.png" title="Hm, this burger place has a couple of good reviews, but LakeSlayer7 says he got food poisoning there and everyone should try this other place down by the lake instead." alt="Hm, this burger place has a couple of good reviews, but LakeSlayer7 says he got food poisoning there and everyone should try this other place down by the lake instead." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wise Man's Fear (The Kingkiller Chronicle, #2) [book]]]></title>
        <id>the-wise-mans-fear-the-kingkiller-chronicle-2</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/books/2021/the-wise-mans-fear-the-kingkiller-chronicle-2"/>
        <updated>2021-11-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A wonderful journey into Rothfuss' world.
As part two of a three part series covering three days (one book per day), the tone and story continues brilliantly onwards from book one (which I read mid-2019).
The characters, their quirks and more importantly to me, the beautiful prose of the book came right back to life.
The book clocks in at a 1,000 pages, and though by my standard that's a (very) long book, quite often I found myself happy that I was still inside the tale and that I still had a long way to go before it would end (and I knew that the current decade wait for book three could well draw longer so I wasn't so eager to finish the book!).
For me, the enjoyment was in the storytelling and being whisked away into the world completely. I honestly did find the amount of sex in the book kind of over the top. I can buy that Kvothe is a legend character and one part of that is perhaps he has a reputation with women, but I'm not wholely sure I needed the many-month-long shagathon story when Kvothe is away with the faeries…
Still, even with this, I found myself wanting to stay in the world for as long as I could.
The very ending, like the last few pages of The Name of the Wind did surprise me a left me a little confused, but I like to think that one day The Doors of Stone will answer some of those questions…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 28 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2919</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/28/somos-cuba/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-28T15:55:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The Cuban vaccines: Omicron, vaccine apartheid, WTO TRIPS waivers and the false hope of viruses "gentling" themselves. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The Cuban vaccines (permalink) Are you low-key freaking out about omicron? Yeah, me too. Can't we catch a break? Maybe. Step one to preventing new, scarier mutant strains is to reduce the number of infected people, which require a mix of ventilation, masking, distancing, and, of course, vaccinations. These days, the "vaccine controversy" is primarily about vaccine-hesitancy and vaccine denial – that is, about people who can get the vaccine but choose not to. But if you cast your mind way, way, way back to last sprin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 26 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2906</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/26/ico-ico/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-26T19:07:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links UK ICO: surveillance advertising is dead: A true consent framework would do the trick. This day in history: 2011, 2016 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading UK ICO: surveillance advertising is dead (permalink) Here's the theory behind Europe's GDPR: if an online service wants to collect, store and/or process your personal information, it has to obtain your real, informed consent for each of those activities. In theory, this should have exterminated surveillance-based "behavioral" ads. In practice, nothing of the sort has happened…yet. Let's look at the theory first. The ad-tech industry has long maintained that it obtains consent for all its data-processing. This is an obvious pretense. This "consent" consists of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Yak Shaving and <md-block>, a new HTML element for Markdown]]></title>
        <id>https://lea.verou.me/?p=3392</id>
        <link href="https://lea.verou.me/2021/11/on-yak-shaving-and-md-block-an-html-element-for-markdown/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-26T16:08:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week has been Yak Shaving Galore. It went a bit like this: I’ve been working on a web component that I need for the project I’m working on. More on that later, but let’s call it <x-foo> for now. Of course that needs to be developed as a separate reusable library and released as […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lea Verou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Siren]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2547/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2547/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/siren.png" title="Directions from CITY OF TROY to ITHACA / Total time: 10y 54d 14h 25m / Warning: Route crosses an international border / route includes capture by the goddess Calypso / route includes a ferry" alt="Directions from CITY OF TROY to ITHACA / Total time: 10y 54d 14h 25m / Warning: Route crosses an international border / route includes capture by the goddess Calypso / route includes a ferry" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 25 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2902</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/25/strikesgiving/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-25T18:30:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Unions are finally fighting two-tier contracts: How the actual fuck did they fail to see through this bullshit decades ago? McKinsey taught Big Pharma how to price-gouge: Leaked slides document the lies, sleaze and profiteering. This day in history: 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Unions are finally fighting two-tier contracts (permalink) Now that Striketober has given way to Strikesgiving, let's pause for a moment and be grateful that labor made 2021 the year that unions wised up to the self-immolating scam that is the two-tier contract. As Alexandra Bradbury writes for Labor Notes, this year's most prominent labor actions fought against two-tier contracts, from the Teamsters to John Deere to Ka…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 24 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2896</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/24/no-puedo-pagar-no-pagara/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-24T19:31:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Spaniards fight Wall Street landlords: When margins and misery are correlated. The Tesla-financial complex: When your financial instruments are better than your cars. This day in history: 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Spaniards fight Wall Street landlords (permalink) One of the original sins of the modern economy was sidelining unions and social programs as a path to upward mobility and installing property speculation in their place. Converting the distribution of shelter (a human right and necessity) into a speculative asset had far-reaching consequences, and an eventual violent rupture was baked in from the start. A path to prosperity runs through the appreciation of your family home (n…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fiction vs Nonfiction]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2546/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2546/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/fiction_vs_nonfiction.png" title="The real challenge is how to file Boba Fett's biography of Doris Kearns Goodwin." alt="The real challenge is how to file Boba Fett's biography of Doris Kearns Goodwin." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 23 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2890</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/23/jump-in-the-line/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-23T16:26:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links The definitive answers to Disney's pernicious queueing debates: Defunctland simulated a themepark and produced the first public data on queue-management strategies. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading The definitive answers to Disney's pernicious queueing debates (permalink) Last summer, I wrote a six-part series on the history, future and present-day of queue- and crowd-management strategies at Disney themeparks, summarizing my endless reading, rumination, and direct experience on the question. https://doctorow.medium.com/disneyland-at-a-stroll-part-vi-62934f35aac1 Who gets to do what and when at a themepark may sound like a trivial question, but I think it's a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Custom CSS Reset]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/custom-css-reset/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/custom-css-reset/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-23T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a set of baseline CSS styles that come with me from project to project. In the past, I'd use a typical CSS reset, but times have changed, and I believe I have a better set of global styles!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 21 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2878</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/22/amr-vs-babies/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-22T16:55:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Private ambulances want a ban on firefighters rescuing babies: American Medical Response says Prescott Valley's firefighters shouldn't be allowed to operate an ambulance. Podcasting "Jam To-Day": How to free Big Tech's hostages on day one. This day in history: 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Private ambulances want a ban on firefighters rescuing babies (permalink) Prescott Valley, AZ is home to 150,000 people and a single private ambulance operator with the exclusive regional franchise: Lifeline Ambulance, a division of American Medical Response (AMR) – a predatory monopolist that has snapped up many smaller ambulance companies and locked in lucrative exclusivity deals with many US ci…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bayes' Theorem]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2545/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2545/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/bayes_theorem.png" title="P((B|A)|(A|B)) represents the probability that you'll mix up the order of the terms when using Bayesian notation." alt="P((B|A)|(A|B)) represents the probability that you'll mix up the order of the terms when using Bayesian notation." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I write and why I won't [blog]]]></title>
        <id>why-i-write-and-when-i-dont</id>
        <link href="https://remysharp.com/2021/11/21/why-i-write-and-when-i-dont"/>
        <updated>2021-11-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been publishing on my blog since 2006 - something I'm personally proud of. My blog is the personal little space I've carved for myself on the web. Whilst I'm here in the real world, my blog will exist in the digital world, and every single post URL will work (404s are for the weak! 😏).
Back in 2015 I set myself an goal to publish at least two posts a month, for the most part I've managed. I've always been a fan of "easy goals" - something that's achievable without it causing stress - so doing some writing twice a month definitely hit that sweet spot.
This particular blog has been active since 2006, but I had also toyed with more diary-like sites during the early-2000s but the URLs are so obscure not only has the web forgotten, but they're wiped clean from my own memory.
When I starte…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>remy sharp's b:log</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 20 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2871</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/20/quiet-part-out-loud/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-20T16:15:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Inflation or price-gouging?: Big business loves inflation talk. This day in history: 2006, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Inflation or price-gouging? (permalink) You can't turn around these days without bumping into scary inflation talk, and with good reason: asset bubbles, supply chain shocks and energy geopolitics are on their way to wiping out most or all of the wage gains eked out by low-waged workers during the pandemic's labor shortage. The underlying message of this scare-talk is that we've been too generous with "essential workers," by allowing them to inch a little closer to a living wage, and now it's time to roll that back, for their own good. What's the point of making $0.50/h more if it c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 19 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2868</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/19/hoffa-jr-defeated/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-19T20:09:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Teamsters transformed: Militant labor is strong labor. This day in history: 2001, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Teamsters transformed (permalink) It's one (true) thing to say that American union membership is down – that's a quantifiable, objective proposition. It's another to say that American unions are weak – and contrariwise, that unions are getting stronger. That's a lot more abstract and harder to pin down. If you'd like an unrolled version of this thread to read or share, here's a link to it on pluralistic.net, my surveillance-free, ad-free, tracker-free blog: https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/19/hoffa-jr-defeated/#teamsters-for-a-democratic-union But here's a nice, concrete version of wha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[7000 Signatures later...]]></title>
        <id>https://grumpygamer.com/lrg_signing</id>
        <link href="https://grumpygamer.com/lrg_signing"/>
        <updated>2021-11-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month I finally got done signing over 7000 cards for the Limited Run Games physical release of Monkey Island.
They asked if I would hand sign cards to go in the boxes.  Sure, how many can that be?  500?  800?
Nope.
They had over 7000 preorders and I signed every one of those cards.  If you bought one of the LRG Monkey Island boxes you won't get a Certificate of Authenticity with a crappy machine printed signature. 
I signed them all. 
I even left a few special messages on the backs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grumpy Gamer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heart-Stopping Texts]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2544/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2544/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/heart_stopping_texts.png" title="Was this your car? [looping 'image loading' animation]" alt="Was this your car? [looping 'image loading' animation]" />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s not send developers to the accessibility tree tool]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=7045</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/11/18/lets-not-send-developers-to-the-accessibility-tree-tool/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-18T17:14:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing for accessibility is an incredibly important part of your development process. Products that don’t block out users because of easy to avoid issues have more success. And the longer you wait with fixing accessibility problems, the harder it gets. That’s why it is annoying when it is hard to find out about accessibility problems. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 18 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2864</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/18/bipartisan-consensus/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-18T15:03:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links This is your Congress on drugs: Corruption kills. Harvard is full of rich, white low-achievers: 43% of white Harvard students didn't get in on merit. This day in history: 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading This is your Congress on drugs (permalink) Back in 2014, a pair of political scientists published a study of 1,779 US "policy issues" over 20 years, concluding that elected officials make policy to benefit the richest ten percent of the country to the exclusion of the needs of everyone else. https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/perspectives-on-politics/article/testing-theories-of-american-politics-elites-interest-groups-and-average-citizens/62327F513959D0A304D4893B382B992B Thi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 17 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2856</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/17/do-well-do-good-do-nothing/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-17T20:31:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links Aspiration's comprehensively deceptive greenwashing: It's "do well" OR "do good." Live Nation is to blame for the Astroworld deaths: Monopoly kills fandom, literally. This day in history: 2006, 2011, 2016 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading Aspiration's comprehensively deceptive greenwashing (permalink) It's impossible to miss Aspiration's star-studded marketing blitz, in which a succession of A-listers promise you that you can save the planet by switching credit-cards ("Do good. Do well."). They're emblematic of the promise of green capitalism, the idea that climate emergency is about a slight misconfiguration of the profit motive and the finance sector. If that's true, it's great news for our species, our civ…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging a weird 'file not found' error]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/11/17/debugging-a-weird--file-not-found--error/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2021/11/17/debugging-a-weird--file-not-found--error/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-17T12:34:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday I ran into a weird error where I ran a program and got the error
“file not found” even though the program I was running existed. It’s something
I’ve run into before, but every time I’m very surprised and confused by it
(what do you MEAN file not found, the file is RIGHT THERE???!!??)
So let’s talk about what happened and why!
the error
Let’s start by showing the error message I got. I had a Go program called
serve.go, and I was trying to bundle it into a Docker container with this
Dockerfile:
FROM golang:1.17 AS go

ADD ./serve.go /app/serve.go
WORKDIR /app
RUN go build serve.go

FROM alpine:3.14

COPY --from=go /app/serve /app/serve
COPY ./static /app/static
WORKDIR /app/static
CMD ["/app/serve"]

This Dockerfile
Builds the Go program
Copies the binary into an Alpine container
P…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Never Told Anyone]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2543/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2543/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/never_told_anyone.png" title="Even if you said you were an employee of the website, if you asked for my password, I'd tell you." alt="Even if you said you were an employee of the website, if you asked for my password, I'd tell you." />]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pluralistic: 16 Nov 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://pluralistic.net/?p=2848</id>
        <link href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/11/16/cop-tech/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-16T17:33:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's links What Police Get When They Get Your Phone: A new season of EFF's podcast, on cop-tech and what to do about it. This day in history: 2006, 2011, 2016, 2020 Colophon: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading What Police Get When They Get Your Phone (permalink) It's not surprising that the debate over digital rights is dominated by technologists – after all, spotting risks (and promises) of technology requires a technical understanding. Likewise, it's not surprising that technologists are accused of solutionism – they've got a hammer, and they're gonna look for nails. The problem with this critique is that not every tech intervention is solutionism. I mean, sure, social problems are caused by social relations, but tech can change…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cory Doctorow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Firefox Relay Premium, allowing more aliases to protect your identity from spammers]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.mozilla.org/?p=68007</id>
        <link href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/firefox-relay-and-premium-service/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-16T14:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, Firefox Relay, a privacy-first and free product that hides your real email address to help protect your identity, is available with a new paid Premium service offering. The release comes just in time for the holiday season to help spare your inbox from being inundated with emails from e-commerce sites, especially those sites where […]
The post Introducing Firefox Relay Premium, allowing more aliases to protect your identity from spammers appeared first on The Mozilla Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mozilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing “Shadow Palette Generator”]]></title>
        <id>https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/introducing-shadow-palette-generator/</id>
        <link href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/css/introducing-shadow-palette-generator/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-16T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In order to create lush, realistic shadows in CSS, we need to use multiple layers and colors. How do we come up with all of the parameters, though? I've built a tool that'll help.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh W. Comeau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>